Alright, this is CS50. Welcome to week 8, last week. We learned how to create, read, update, and delete databases using SQL. But this week, we're going to do it.
好的，欢迎回到 CS50，上周我们学习了如何使用 SQL 创建、读取、更新和删除数据库，而本周，我们要做的是。
SETH LADD. Adam, everyone. Happy Halloween.
SETH LADD。Adam，大家好。 万圣节快乐。
All right, so this is CS50, and this is week eight already.
好的，欢迎回到 CS50，现在已经是第八周了。
My thanks to Adam on today, this happy Halloween.
感谢 Adam 在这个快乐的万圣节来到这里。
In the coming moments, we're going to learn all about how the internet itself works, which, of course, is a technology that we all use every day, probably using in some form right now.
接下来的时间里，我们将学习互联网本身是如何运作的，当然，互联网是我们每天都在使用的一项技术，而且很有可能你现在就在以某种形式使用它。
But we'll see that if you start to understand some of the underlying building blocks that power the internet itself, we can actually start to build interesting things on top of it.
但我们会看到，如果开始了解一些驱动互联网本身的底层构建模块，我们就可以在其基础上构建有趣的东西了。
And a lot of the apps, the websites that you all use every day should become all the more familiar, things that you yourselves can create.
你会更加熟悉你每天使用的许多应用程序和网站，以及你自己可以创建的东西。
And honestly, when things go wrong, you'll have all the more of a mental model for how things work or are not, in fact, working so that you can ultimately Diagnose all the more issues yourselves.
而且坦白地说，当出现问题时，你会对事情是如何运作或实际上是如何不运作的有更清晰的认识，这样你最终就能自己诊断出更多的问题。
So if we take a look at the internet in the early days, it pretty much was just this.
所以如果我们看一下早期的互联网，它几乎就是这样。
This happens to be, of course, the geography of the United States.
当然，这正好是美国的地理位置。
And just some of the first points on the internet were these here.
互联网上最早的几个点就在这里。
This was so-called ARPANET back in 1969.
这就是 1969 年的所谓 ARPANET。
And indeed, the internet had its origins here in the United States with just a few computers interconnected somehow.
事实上，互联网起源于美国，最初只有几台计算机以某种方式连接在一起。
Initially, that, of course, began to grow over time, such that we eventually had the West Coast connected to the East Coast.
当然，随着时间的推移，它开始发展，最终西海岸和东海岸连接了起来。
And nowadays, what you can think of, these dots on the screens it's representing, are these things called routers.
如今，你可以把屏幕上的这些点想象成路由器。
Sort of computers, or really servers, that somehow have wires, or maybe wireless connections between them, that allow data to flow from point A to B to C. And then this, of course, has been now magnified across the entire globe, and even above ground as well, so that we can connect all the more readily to systems anywhere.
它们有点像计算机，或者说是服务器，它们之间通过电缆或无线连接，允许数据从 A 点流向 B 点再到 C 点。
当然，现在这种连接已经扩展到全球各地，甚至包括地面以上，所以我们可以更容易地连接到任何地方的系统。
Now, in order to route the data from one router to another, we need to somehow make routing decisions.
现在，为了将数据从一个路由器路由到另一个路由器，我们需要以某种方式做出路由决策。
And this is the kind of thing that the internet service providers, the ISPs of the world, just handle for us.
而这就是互联网服务提供商，也就是全球 ISP 为我们做的事情。
You and I plug our Macs, our PCs, into the network here at Harvard, or equivalently at Yale, or we somehow get online via Wi-Fi or cellular technology.
你我将 Mac 或 PC 接入哈佛的网络，或者在耶鲁也一样，或者通过 Wi-Fi 或蜂窝网络上网。
And then some of these larger entities, these bigger companies or countries, handle most of the data getting from point A to point B.
一些更大的实体，比如大公司或国家，会处理大部分从 A 点到 B 点的数据传输。
And if you think about what these routers represent, they're indeed just servers somehow interconnected, not unlike this grid of tiles here, for instance, back in the Zoom days.
如果你想想这些路由器代表什么，它们实际上就是以某种方式互连的服务器，就像我们在 Zoom 时代看到的这网格瓷砖一样。
And in fact, here we have, I claim, a grid of routers implemented here by the course's teaching fellows and course assistants and TAs.
事实上，我认为这里有一个由课程助教和 TA 们实现的路由器网络。
And if the goal at hand, for instance, is for Phyllis to route some piece of information, maybe it's an email, maybe it's a request for a web page in the bottom right-hand corner, all the way up to, say, Brian here in the top left-hand corner,
例如，如果目标是让 Phyllis 将一些信息（可能是一封电子邮件，也可能是对网页的请求）从右下角一路路由到左上角的 Brian，
Suffice it to say, each of these tiles represents a router, a server that can move the data back, forth, left, and right.
只需说，每个瓷砖代表一个路由器，一个可以前后左右移动数据的服务器。
That packet of information, so to speak, from Phyllis to Brian could take any number of different possible routes, up, down, left, right, to go from the one corner to another.
从 Phyllis 到 Brian 的信息包，可以说，可以采取任意数量的不同路径，上下左右，从一个角落到另一个角落。
So let me go ahead and hit Play on this video here, wherein the teaching fellows play this same role.
接下来，我将播放这段视频，助教们在其中扮演着同样的角色。
All right, so in this particular case, the data was routed pretty straightforwardly up and then to the left.
在这个例子中，数据非常直接地向上然后向左路由。
But suppose that one or more of the staff were a bit busy.
但假设一个或多个工作人员有点忙。
Maybe one of the routers is congested.
可能其中一个路由器拥塞了。
That is to say, just got way more envelopes at a moment in time than it can handle.
也就是说，在某个时刻收到的信封数量超出了它的处理能力。
Thankfully, the design of the internet is such that there's often multiple ways that data can get from point A to point B.
值得庆幸的是，互联网的设计使得数据通常可以通过多种方式从 A 点到达 B 点。
Maybe going through point C or point D instead.
也许会经过 C 点或 D 点。
And so there's a resilience there, even as some of these servers themselves might go down.
因此，即使其中一些服务器宕机，网络也具有一定的弹性。
So allow me to propose that we use the same grid of routers now to route the data in a slightly different way this time.
现在，让我们使用相同的路由器网络，以稍微不同的方式路由数据。
So success.
成功了！
You'll see perhaps later just how many takes it took us to actually get that routing right.
你可能稍后会看到我们实际完成了多少次才正确路由。
But it does, in fact, manifest that you can travel different paths in order to get the data from point A to point B. So as we talk about routers, as you think of the internet, I mean, think of those humans as just representing these routers, points A to B and everywhere in between.
但这确实表明，你可以通过不同的路径将数据从 A 点传输到 B 点。
当我们谈论路由器时，当你想到互联网时，请把这些人想象成代表着路由器，从 A 点到 B 点以及两者之间的所有点。
Now, how did the teaching staff know to route that packet up and then down or left and right in order to get to the destination?
那么，工作人员如何知道向上、向下、向左或向右路由数据包才能到达目的地呢？
Well, all of them were programmed, so to speak, to understand protocols.
可以说，所有工作人员都被编程为理解协议。
It's called TCP and IP, otherwise known together typically as TCP slash IP.
它被称为 TCP 和 IP，通常一起称为 TCP/IP。
And you've probably seen these acronyms at some point in the real world, on the internet, on some kind of documentation, a text, even if you haven't really thought hard about it.
你可能在现实世界中的某个地方、互联网上、某些文档、文本中看到过这些缩略词，即使你没有认真思考过。
But IP is certainly the more common of the two, perhaps. In common culture.
但 IP 肯定是两者中更常见的那个，也许是在大众文化中。
So what does TCP and IP do for us?
那么 TCP 和 IP 对我们有什么作用呢？
Well, really two primary things.
实际上是两个主要作用。
Any computer or any teaching staff member who understands TCP IP knows how to get data from point A to point B. But how?
任何理解 TCP/IP 的计算机或工作人员都知道如何将数据从 A 点传输到 B 点。但如何传输呢？
Well, let's break down what that problem to be solved is.
让我们来分解一下要解决的问题是什么。
IP, otherwise known as Internet Protocol, is a protocol that computers speak that allow them to know how to address computers on the internet.
IP，也称为互联网协议，是计算机之间交流的一种协议，它允许它们知道如何在互联网上寻址计算机。
And a protocol is just a set of conventions that computers adhere to.So someone wrote code that probably has a whole lot of conditionals that tells the computer what to do if something happens.
协议只是一组计算机遵循的约定。因此，有人编写的代码可能包含大量的条件语句，告诉计算机在发生某些事情时该怎么做。
Like if I receive a packet, then send it to the next server or something like that. In the human world, we have protocols too.
例如，如果我收到一个数据包，就将其发送到下一个服务器等等。在人类世界中，我们也有协议。
In healthier times, it was quite common to sort of extend your hand to another human in order to greet them.
在更健康的时代，人们通常会向另一个人伸出手来表示问候。
And if they're following human protocol, they would presumably grab your hand and shake it, at least in a culture like this one here on campus.
如果他们遵循人类的礼仪，他们可能会握住你的手并摇晃，至少在我们校园这样的文化中是这样。
And now that is a human protocol in that someone initiates it, someone responds to it, and you both sort of know what to do.
现在，这就是人类的礼仪，有人发起，有人回应，双方都知道该怎么做。
You're programmed to know what to do.
你被编程为知道该怎么做。
So same idea with internet protocol.
互联网协议也是一样的道理。
Computers just know what to do when they've been programmed to do so. So what does this mean?
计算机被编程后就知道该怎么做了。这意味着什么呢？
If IP decides that every computer in the world will have a unique address, just like the Science Center around the corner might have a unique address of 1 Oxford Street, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 02138USA.
如果 IP 规定世界上每台计算机都有一个唯一的地址，
就像拐角处的科学中心可能有一个唯一的地址：美国马萨诸塞州剑桥市牛津街 1 号，邮编 02138。
IP dictates that every computer on the internet have a unique address of this form.
IP 规定互联网上的每台计算机都有一个这种形式的唯一地址。
And this, too, is probably something you've seen in the real world, even if you haven't thought too hard about it.
你可能已经在现实世界中见过这个，即使你没有仔细想过。
It's a number in what's called dotted decimal notation, which means it's a decimal number, dot something, dot something, dot something.
这是一个用点分十进制表示法表示的数字，这意味着它是一个十进制数，点什么，点什么，点什么。
So four digits separated by convention by decimal points, although, There are newer and bigger versions of the same.
按照惯例，四个数字用小数点隔开，当然，还有更新、更大的版本。
And these so-called IP addresses that might be as simple as 1.2.3.4 uniquely identify a computer on the internet.
这些所谓的 IP 地址，可能像 1.2.3.4 这样简单，在互联网上唯一地标识一台计算机。
The numbers have to range from 0 to 255 each.
每个数字的范围必须在 0 到 255 之间。
And that's a bit of a hint just as you start to think more computationally.
当你开始更多地从计算角度思考时，这是一个提示。
If each of these is a number from 0 to 255, how many bits does that suggest each number is using?
如果每个数字都在 0 到 255 之间，那么每个数字使用多少位？
Feel free to shout it out.
请大声说出来。
How many bits gives us 256 total possibilities?
多少位可以提供 256 种可能性？
So 8 bits.
8 位。
That should just be sort of a heuristic in your mind.
这应该成为你脑海中的一种启发式方法。
Anytime you hear something that's in the range of 0 to 255, or 256 values total, think back to week 0, which gives us 8 bits plus another 8 bits, another 8 bits, and another 8 bits, which is to say an IP address typically is 32 bits in total.
每当你听到 0 到 255 范围内或总共 256 个值时，回想一下第 0 周的内容，
它给了我们 8 位加上另外 8 位，另外 8 位，以及另外 8 位，也就是说，一个 IP 地址通常总共是 32 位。
Now, if we do another bit of quick mental math or think back to week 0, if every IP address is 32 bits, how many computers can we have on the internet?
现在，如果我们再做一些快速的心算，或者回想一下第 0 周的内容，如果每个 IP 地址都是 32 位，那么互联网上可以有多少台计算机？
At once, give or take, roughly 4 billion is the ballpark.
粗略估计，大约是 40 亿。
And we don't need to be super precise for discussion's sake, but roughly 4 billion is how high you can account, assuming no negative numbers, if you have 32 bits in total.
为了讨论方便，我们不需要非常精确，但如果总共只有 32 位，假设没有负数，那么大约 40 亿就是你能计算的上限。
Now, that's not terribly many numbers of addresses, especially considering the number of humans in the world, the number of us that do have laptops or desktops or devices more generally, phones in our pockets and the like.
这个地址数量并不算多，特别是考虑到世界人口数量，拥有笔记本电脑、台式机或更普遍的设备、口袋里的手机等等的人数。
So let me just stipulate for today's purposes that there is even a newer and improved version of IP, otherwise known as version 6.
因此，让我今天先说明一下，甚至还有一个更新、改进版的 IP，也就是版本 6。
This is version 4, but still super popular.
这是版本 4，但仍然非常流行。
Version 6 uses 128 bits, which is a huge number of possible permutations.
版本 6 使用 128 位，这是一个巨大的排列组合数量。
I dare say I can't even pronounce that number.
我敢说我甚至无法读出这个数字。
It's so big.
太大了。
So there are ways around even this limitation already.
所以即使是这种限制，现在也有办法绕过。
So every computer has an address like this.
所以每台电脑都有一个这样的地址。
What does that really mean?
这到底是什么意思呢?
Well, suppose that I was Phyllis, and the story told visually earlier, and I want to send a message to Brian.
假设我是Phyllis，就像之前视频里讲的故事那样，我想给Brian发个消息。
Well, both Phyllis and Brian have IP addresses.
Phyllis和Brian都有IP地址。
And suppose that Brian's IP address happens to be 1.2.3.4 in that top left-hand corner.
假设Brian的IP地址是左上角的1.2.3.4。
Well, Phyllis' Mac or PC or phone would essentially do the equivalent on this human envelope by writing the to address in the middle of the envelope, as is our human convention, like this.
Phyllis的Mac、PC或者手机实际上会做和这个人类信封相同的事情，按照人类的习惯，把收件地址写在信封的中间，就像这样。
So this is an envelope, a piece of information, an email, a text message, whatever, destined for Brian.
这是一封信封，一条信息，一封邮件，一条短信等等，都是发给Brian的。
And so she would have her computer put Brian's IP address in the middle.
她会让她的电脑把Brian的IP地址放在中间。
Her IP address is maybe 5.6.7.8.
她的IP地址可能是5.6.7.8。
So just like our human convention, I might write 5.6.7.8 at the top of the envelope, 5, 6, 7, 8, thereby indicating what the return address is.
就像我们人类的习惯一样，我可能会在信封的顶部写上5.6.7.8，以此来表示寄信地址。
And this is helpful because if Brian's computer needs to acknowledge receipt, if he needs to reply in some form,
这很有用，因为如果Brian的电脑需要确认收到，或者需要以某种形式回复，
And this way, the envelope has all the information we need.
这样一来，信封上就有了我们需要的所有信息。
But in the real world, servers do a lot of things nowadays, not just email, but maybe chat, maybe video conferencing, maybe any number of other services as well.
但在现实世界中，服务器现在做的不仅仅是电子邮件，还可能是聊天、视频会议，或者其他任何服务。
And so it turns out that an address alone might not be sufficient, because how does Brian's computer know when he opens the envelope, so to speak, that this should be interpreted as an email?
事实证明，仅仅一个地址可能是不够的，因为Brian的电脑怎么知道，当他打开信封的时候，应该把它解释成一封电子邮件呢？
or interpret it as a chat message or interpret it as a video attachment that Phyllis has sent.
还是把它解释成一条聊天信息，或者解释成Phyllis发送的一个视频附件。
Well, we need some other mechanism, some other hint on this envelope to distinguish one type of internet service from another.
我们需要其他机制，在这个信封上添加其他提示，来区分不同类型的互联网服务。
And so that's where the other acronym in TCPIP comes in, which is TCP.
这就是TCP/IP中另一个缩写词TCP的由来。
So this stands for Transmission Control Protocol, which is just a different set of conventions. that computers adhere to in order to solve a couple of different problems.
它代表传输控制协议，这是另一套计算机遵循的惯例，用于解决一些不同的问题。
One is this problem of distinguishing one type of service from another.
其中一个问题是如何区分不同类型的服务。
Now, what does that mean?
这是什么意思呢？
Well, humans decades ago decided, as they started inventing all of these various internet services, the web being the first one, how they might, or the web now being one of the most popular ones, they decided to assign different services that can be used on the internet unique numbers.
几十年前，人们在开始发明各种互联网服务时，比如最早出现的网络，
以及现在最流行的网络之一，他们决定为互联网上可以使用的不同服务分配唯一的编号。
And so two of the most common are these.
其中最常见的两个是：
80 is the number that a bunch of humans decided years ago will represent what you and I know as HTTP.
80 是很多年前人们决定用来代表 HTTP 的数字，也就是我们现在所知的 HTTP。
And we'll talk more technically in a bit about what HTTP is.
稍后我们将更详细地从技术角度讨论 HTTP 是什么。
But obviously, it's the thing that's in the beginning of every URL nowadays.
但很明显，它是如今每个 URL 开头都有的东西。
Or HTTPS, which, of course, has the S added to it.
或者 HTTPS，当然它后面加了一个 S。
And that has its own unique number.
它也有自己唯一的编号。
And for now, the S just means secure.
目前，S 只代表安全。
One is encrypted or scrambled somehow for privacy's sake, and the other is unencrypted.
一种是为了隐私而加密或以某种方式加扰，另一种是未加密的。
It's a little more vulnerable to interception.
未加密的更容易被拦截。
So these two numbers are what the world decided when implementing TCP shall uniquely identify those services.
所以在实现 TCP 时，全世界决定使用这两个数字来唯一标识这些服务。
So what does this mean?
这是什么意思呢？
Well, this means that if Brian's computer in the story from before is hosting not like an email server, but maybe he has a website, and Phyllis is requesting Brian's home page or something like that, she would have her Mac or PC or phone not only write Brian's IP address,
这意味着，如果之前故事中的 Brian 的电脑不是在托管邮件服务器，而可能有一个网站，
Phyllis 正在请求 Brian 的主页或类似的东西，那么她的 Mac、PC 或手机不仅会在信封中间写上 Brian 的 IP 地址，
in the middle of the envelope, but also the number, otherwise known as a port number, that she wants this envelope to be routed to.
还会写上她希望这个信封被路由到的端口号。
Now, 80 would be insecure nowadays.
如今，80 已经不安全了。
HTTP colon slash slash is sort of passe.
HTTP 冒号// 已经过时了。
And we almost always see HTTPS colon slash slash now.
我们现在几乎总是看到 https ://。
So I'm just going to go with best practice.
所以我要说的是最佳实践。
And I'm going to add a colon and then the number 443 at the end of Brian's IP address.
然后我在 Brian 的 IP 地址末尾加上一个冒号和数字 443。
So now I have an IP address for Brian.
这样我就有了一个 Brian 的 IP 地址。
The port number for the service that this is relevant to.
这是与之相关的服务的端口号。
And I'm not going to bother writing it, but it turns out that Phyllis's computer would also choose a port number, maybe a random port number, so that Brian can conversely reply.
我就不写了，但事实证明，Phyllis 的计算机也会选择一个端口号，可能是一个随机端口号，这样 Brian 就可以反过来回复了。
And then the computer can know which response is coming back for which request.
然后计算机就可以知道哪个响应是对应哪个请求返回的。
But the most important one is this one in the To field, whereby this distinguishes this from an email, a chat message, a video conference session, or a Zoom or whatnot from anything else happening on Brian's computer at the same time.
但最重要的是“收件人”字段中的这个，它将此与电子邮件、聊天消息、
视频会议会话或 Zoom 等区分开来，也与 Brian 计算机上同时发生的任何其他事情区分开来。
So all this time, if you've seen these terms TCP and IP, those are really two of the most important things that they do.
所以一直以来，如果你见过 TCP 和 IP 这样的术语，它们确实是其中两个最重要的功能。
But TCP does one other thing that's super useful, too.
但 TCP 还做了一件非常有用的事情。
It turns out that it's super easy.
事实证明，这非常简单。
Common, nowadays especially, to transmit a lot of media on the internet, whether it's an image or maybe it's a movie file.
如今，在互联网上传输大量媒体是很常见的，无论是图片还是电影文件。
And it would be a little obnoxious, to say the least, if your downloading a really big file meant that no one else in your dorm room or your household could actually download anything until you're actually done.
至少可以说，如果你下载一个非常大的文件，这意味着在你下载完成之前，你宿舍或家里的其他人实际上都无法下载任何东西，这将有点令人讨厌。
So of course, multiple people nowadays can be on the internet at once, even if all of the connections are a little slower.
所以当然，现在多个人可以同时上网，即使所有的连接都慢一点。
But one person's usage does not block someone else's.
但一个人的使用不会阻止另一个人的使用。
Now, how does this work?
那么，这是如何工作的呢？
Well, TCP, in conjunction with IP, can also allow you to take a really big image of a cat, which the internet, of course, is filled with, and take a big image of a cat or a big video file of a cat and fragment it into multiple pieces.
TCP 与 IP 结合，也可以让你拍摄一张非常大的猫的图片，
当然互联网上到处都是，然后拍摄一张猫的大图片或猫的大视频文件，并将其分割成多个片段。
So I'm just going to. Sort of roughly tear it down the middle, and then maybe tear it down the middle again.
所以我要把它大致地从中间撕开，然后再从中间撕开。
So now it's four different fragments.
现在它变成了四个不同的片段。
And I'm sorry, but the computer will be reassembling these for us.
很抱歉，但是计算机将为我们重新组装这些片段。
And what Phyllis's computer could do now, if she's uploading this picture of a cat to Brian's web server, well, she could put one fragment
如果 Phyllis 要将这张猫的图片上传到 Brian 的网络服务器，那么她可以将一个片段
in this envelope, and then have three separate envelopes for the other three fragments.
放入这个信封中，然后为其他三个片段准备三个独立的信封。
And what you could then do on the outside of this envelope is just kind of number them somehow.
然后你可以在信封外面把它们编号。
And in fact, this is something else that TCP and IP together would do for us.
实际上，这也是 TCP/IP 协议能为我们做的事情。
This first envelope now might say something like 1, out of four in the memo field, so to speak, of the metaphorical envelope here.
第一个信封上可能会写着“1/4”，可以把它想象成是这个比喻中的信封上的备注字段。
Now, this should be enough information, because now if Brian gets all four of these envelopes, he presumably knows how to reassemble the picture of the cat in order, top to bottom, left to right.
这些信息就足够了，因为如果 Brian 收到了所有四个信封，他应该知道如何按顺序重新拼装猫的图片，从上到下，从左到右。
But more importantly, suppose that one of the routers, one of the TFs in the video,
但更重要的是，假设其中一个路由器，也就是视频中的一个助教，
is sort of distracted and they sort of drop one of the packets.
有点分心，不小心丢了一个数据包。
And that's a metaphor actually in practice for when a router gets really busy, it's got way too much data coming in, it might metaphorically drop packets.
这实际上是一个比喻，当路由器非常繁忙，有太多数据传入时，它可能会丢弃数据包。
What does that mean in practice?
这在实际中意味着什么？
I mean, it literally just ignores the 0's and 1's.
我的意思是，它实际上只是忽略了这些 0 和 1。
It doesn't save them to its memory because there's just no room left.
它不会把它们保存到内存中，因为已经没有空间了。
So it's equivalent to sort of dropping the packet.
所以这相当于丢弃了数据包。
So suppose now that Brian gets 1 of 4, 3 of 4, and 4 of 4.
假设现在 Brian 收到了 1/4、3/4 和 4/4。
What can his computer infer now?
他的电脑现在能推断出什么？
After receiving those three packets, 1 of 4, 3 of 4, and 4 of 4, what's the use there?
在收到这三个数据包后，1/4、3/4 和 4/4，有什么用？
Yeah, I think you're. You're signaling with your fingers.
是的，我认为你… 你在用手指示意。
Which one?
哪一个？
Can I call on you?
我可以请你回答吗？
Yeah, so he's missing two out of four, the second of the packets.
是的，他丢了四个数据包中的第二个。
And this is useful now, because you could imagine he can send some message back to Phyllis saying, hey, please retransmit number two of four without having to redownload the entirety of the cat.
这很有用，因为你可以想象，他可以给 Phyllis 回一条消息说，“嘿，请重新发送 2/4”，而不必重新下载整只猫的图片。
So there's an efficiency there as well.
所以这也提高了效率。
So TCPIP allows data, really, to go from point A to point B while solving a bunch of these problems along the way.
TCP/IP 允许数据从 A 点传输到 B 点，并解决途中的一系列问题。
So nowadays, if you ever see mention on your Mac or PC of your so-called IP address, that is the sort of problem that's being solved.
所以现在，如果你在 Mac 或 PC 上看到所谓的 IP 地址，那就是正在解决的问题。
Questions now on these protocols, these conventions called TCP and IP.
现在关于这些协议的问题，这些叫做 TCP 和 IP 的约定。
That's the extent to which we'll need to understand them.
这就是我们需要了解它们的程度。
Won't have to implement them, per se.
本身并不需要实现它们。
We'll just take them hereafter for granted.
我们以后会把它们视为理所当然。
Any questions that you've ever been wondering about your home network? Yeah?
关于你的家庭网络，你还有什么想知道的问题吗？
A really good question.
问得好。
How does TCP know that a user got a message?
TCP 如何知道用户收到了消息？
Another aspect, another feature of TCP is that Brian's computer, by design of this protocol, will also acknowledge the packets that he's received. And it will do it efficiently.
TCP 的另一个特点是，根据该协议的设计，Brian 的计算机也会确认他收到的数据包。而且效率很高。
If Brian receives all four packets in a pretty narrow window of time, his computer will send to Phyllis's computer a quick message saying, essentially, received all four.
如果 Brian 在很短的时间内收到所有四个数据包，他的计算机将向 Phyllis 的计算机发送一条快速消息，内容基本上是“已收到所有四个数据包”。
Otherwise, he'll say the opposite, which is that I'm missing, for instance, two out of four.
否则，他会说相反的话，例如“我丢了四个中的两个”。
And that just ensures, ultimately, that all of the data is indeed arrived so that you're not missing like a quarter, a quadrant of the cat in question.
这最终确保了所有数据都已到达，这样你就不会丢失相关信息的四分之一。
All right, but that's not the only problem that needs to be solved, ultimately.
但这并不是最终需要解决的唯一问题。
We also need to make the internet user friendly, if you will.
如果可以这么说，我们还需要让互联网更加用户友好。
And it would be really tedious if you had to visit websites, for instance, by way of their IP addresses.
如果你必须通过 IP 地址访问网站，那将会非常乏味。
1.2.3.4 is pretty memorable, but there's like 4 billion other possible addresses available.
1.2.3.4 很好记，但还有大约 40 亿个其他可能的地址。
And it would be super tedious to remember those.
记住这些地址会非常乏味。
It would be bad marketing to advertise those.
宣传这些地址的营销效果会很差。
In fact, most of you probably don't even know the phone numbers of your closest friends and family members anymore because you instead store them in your contacts or in your address book associating with numbers that are completely opaque with actual names or strings, if you will.
事实上，你们中的大多数人可能甚至都不记得自己最亲密的家人和朋友的电话号码了，
因为你们把它们存储在联系人或地址簿中，并与完全不透明的数字或字符串相关联。
The same goes for the internet, too.
互联网也是如此。
Even though every computer does have and must have a unique IP address numerically, why?
尽管每台计算机都有且必须有一个唯一的数字 IP 地址，但为什么呢？
Well, routers are computers.
因为路由器也是计算机。
Computers just crunch numbers very readily.
而计算机非常擅长处理数字。
But we humans work better with strings of text.
但我们人类更擅长处理字符串文本。
We need some system for converting user-friendly strings like harvard.edu or yale.edu or google.com to the underlying IP addresses.
我们需要某种系统，将用户友好的字符串（如 harvard.edu、yale.edu 或 google.com）转换为底层的 IP 地址。
And that's where the next acronym comes in today, which is DNS, Domain Name System.
这就是今天要介绍的下一个缩写词 DNS（域名系统）的由来。
So this is just another technology that's been in use for some time now.
这是一项已经使用了一段时间的技术。
And it's a collection of servers on the internet whose purpose in life is to convert domain names to IP addresses, and maybe vice versa as well.
它是互联网上一组服务器的集合，其作用是将域名转换为 IP 地址，反之亦然。
So let me stipulate for today's purposes, there are some root DNS servers in the world that, long story short,
为了便于今天的讲解，我们假设世界上有一些根 DNS 服务器，
know about all of the dot coms, all of the dot edus, all of the dot, dot, dot, all of the other top-level domains around the world, as well as in the US.
它们知道所有 .com、.edu、.（等等），以及世界上以及美国的所有其他顶级域名。
And then there are some smaller DNS servers owned by companies, owned by universities, and even in your apartments or homes, most likely.
公司、大学，甚至你的公寓或住宅中，都有一些更小的 DNS 服务器。
Indeed, if you have a home router plugged into the wall somewhere, that's not only routing your data in and out of your apartment or home or dorm room.
事实上，如果你家里或宿舍的墙上插着一个家用路由器，它不仅负责进出你公寓、住宅或宿舍的数据路由，
It's also typically serving as a local, therefore faster, DNS server, a cache, if you will.
它通常还充当本地（因此速度更快）的 DNS 服务器，一个缓存。
It's sort of locally saving your most frequently accessed websites and their IP addresses just to avoid bothering the bigger, more expensive, busier servers all day long.
它会在本地保存你最常访问的网站及其 IP 地址，以避免整天打扰更大、更昂贵、更繁忙的服务器。
So there's DNS servers all over.
所以到处都有 DNS 服务器。
If you poke around your settings in Windows or Mac OS or Android or iOS, you'll see mention of DNS.
如果你查看 Windows、Mac OS、Android 或 iOS 中的设置，你会看到 DNS 的字样。
And you'll probably see the IP addresses of the servers whose purpose in life is to do this conversion for you.
你可能会看到一些服务器的 IP 地址，它们的作用就是为你进行这种转换。
But this is a requisite feature if we just want the internet to be user-friendly and allow us to use words instead of numbers alone.
但如果我们想让互联网对用户友好，并允许我们使用文字而不是数字，那么这就是一项必不可少的功能。
What's inside of these DNS servers?
这些 DNS 服务器里面是什么？
You know, it's essentially a spreadsheet.
它本质上就是一个电子表格。
Or if we can say it more geekily, it's essentially like a hash table of some sort, which it has keys and values.
或者用更专业的说法，它本质上像一种哈希表，有键和值。
Like the key is the domain name, harvard.edu, yale.edu, google.com.
例如键是域名，harvard.edu、yale.edu、google.com。
And the value is the corresponding IP address, or in many cases, IP addresses, plural, of the corresponding servers.
值是对应的 IP 地址，或者很多情况下是多个对应的服务器的 IP 地址。
So here already, even though I've drawn it fairly abstractly, like you would on a chalkboard,
所以在这里，虽然我画的相当抽象，就像在黑板上画的那样，
It's really probably implemented as some kind of table, maybe a hash table, maybe a database table, maybe SQL or something like that.
它实际上可能是用某种表实现的，可能是哈希表，可能是数据库表，可能是 SQL 或类似的东西。
Or maybe it's even just a linked list or an array.
或者甚至可能只是一个链表或数组。
We just have to somehow enable this computer to convert one to the other.
我们只需要以某种方式使这台计算机能够将一个转换为另一个。
Now, just to be super precise.
现在，为了更加精确。
DNS servers actually convert what are called fully qualified domain names, which is generally not just harvard.edu, but more verbosely, www.harvard.edu and www.google.com.
DNS 服务器实际上转换的是所谓的完全限定域名，它通常不只是 harvard.edu，而是更详细的 www.harvard.edu 和 www.google.com。
So the whole thing that you would see as a substring of the URL.
也就是你在 URL 中看到的子字符串的完整形式。
So that's what DNS does.
这就是 DNS 的作用。
And that's what your university, your company, your home router are doing for you.
这也是你的大学、公司、家用路由器为你做的事情。
Let me pause here to see if there are any questions.
我先暂停一下，看看有没有什么问题。
This, too, is just a technology now we'll take for granted, just works.
这也是一项我们现在认为理所当然的技术，它就能工作。
Questions at all?
有问题吗？
All right.
好的。
So let's now transition among our protocols, really, to the last for today, which will set the stage for actually solving problems with these and writing some code, ultimately, HTTP.
现在让我们在各种协议之间进行转换，今天最后一个是 HTTP，这将为我们实际解决问题和最终编写代码奠定基础。
This is something that you see or hear all day long, even though you rarely have to bother typing it anymore.
这是你每天都能看到或听到的东西，尽管你很少需要自己输入它了。
Odds are, if you go to harvard.edu, yale.edu, google.com, you don't bother typing HTTP, let alone HTTPS, manually anymore.
如果你访问 harvard.edu、yale.edu、google.com，你很可能不会再手动输入 HTTP，更不用说 HTTPS 了。
Why? Because your browser autocompletes, that kind of thing, just to make life easier.
为什么？因为浏览器会自动补全，让操作更方便。
But it is officially at the beginning of every URL you visit, either HTTP,
但它实际上出现在你访问的每个 URL 的开头，要么是 HTTP，
or the more secure HTTPS whenever you're using your browser to access some website.
要么是更安全的 HTTPS，当你使用浏览器访问某些网站时。
So HTTP stands for Hyper Text Transfer Protocol.
HTTP 代表超文本传输协议。
And it's easily one of the most popular, dare say, one of the most powerful features of the internet nowadays.
它很容易成为当今互联网上最流行的，或者说，最强大的功能之一。
But the mental model to have here is that HTTP, or the web more generally, is kind of a service that runs on top of the internet.
但这里的思维模型是，HTTP，或者更广泛地说，Web，是一种运行在互联网之上的服务。
And maybe Zoom or Microsoft Teams is another service that runs on top of the internet.
也许 Zoom 或 Microsoft Teams 是另一种运行在互联网之上的服务。
And iMessage and technologies like it is another service that runs on top of the internet.
iMessage 和类似的技术是另一种运行在互联网之上的服务。
So the internet is really like the lower level plumbing, the TCP IP stuff, the DNS stuff that just gets data from point A to point B.
所以互联网实际上就像底层的管道，TCP/IP 的东西，DNS 的东西，它们只是把数据从 A 点传输到 B 点。
But now, and we're in a software development class, ultimately, here in CS50, HTTP is the application-level protocol.
但是现在，我们身处 CS50 这门软件开发课程中，HTTP 是应用层协议。
It's sort of what programmers use, what companies use, what developers use, ultimately, to use the underlying plumbing, to build interesting and powerful things.
它有点像程序员、公司、开发者最终用来利用底层管道，构建有趣而强大的东西。
So what does this mean?
这意味着什么？
when it comes to accessing services via HTTP or the more secure HTTPS.
当涉及到通过 HTTP 或更安全的 HTTPS 访问服务时。
Well, here is a representative URL.
这是一个典型的 URL。
Even though you might not type the whole thing, if you poke around your address bar, this is what's up there.
即使你可能不会输入全部内容，但如果你查看地址栏，就会发现它就在那里。
With that said, a lot of browsers nowadays are kind of simplifying, if not dumbing down, what you see with your human eyes.
话虽如此，现在很多浏览器都在简化，或者说简化了你用肉眼看到的内容。
just to shorten the strings, especially on mobile devices.
只是为了缩短字符串，尤其是在移动设备上。
But almost always, if you click the URL or highlight it, then you see the whole thing.
但几乎总是，如果你点击 URL 或高亮它，你就会看到全部内容。
But on many browsers, you might only ever see example.com, but all of this information is there.
但在许多浏览器上，你可能只会看到 example.com，但所有这些信息都在那里。
It's just getting more and more hidden just for user interfaces' sake.
它只是为了用户界面而被隐藏得越来越多。
Well, it turns out when you visit a URL, by default, especially if you type nothing after the .com in this case, you're technically implicitly adding a single slash.
访问 URL 时，默认情况下，尤其是在这种情况下 .com 后面什么都不输入，技术上隐式地添加了一个斜杠。
So a single slash denotes the root of the server.
单个斜杠表示服务器的根目录。
That is the default page or folder in the server.
这是服务器中的默认页面或文件夹。
And the slash, whether or not you type it or not, is implicitly going to be there.
无论是否输入，斜杠都会隐式存在。
And that just means give me the default.
这意味着给我默认值。
Whatever's at www.example.com, give me that page or that folder.
无论 www.example.com 是什么，都给我那个页面或文件夹。
But URLs can be longer than this.
但 URL 可以比这更长。
And more generally, there can be a path, so to speak. And this is a term of art.
更一般地说，可以有所谓的路径。这是一个专业术语。
A path is some sequence of folder and or file names after a URL like this.
路径是像这样的 URL 之后的一系列文件夹和/或文件名。
And so you might see more specifically that a URL contains a very specific file.
所以你可能会更具体地看到 URL 包含一个非常具体的文件。
That's common nowadays anymore, though we will begin today by using this technique.
这在现在很常见，不过我们今天将从使用这种技术开始。
But if there is a file called literally file.html or something else on the server, that file is going to be what this URL pulls up on the computer.
但如果服务器上有一个名为 file.html 或其他名称的文件，那么该文件将是此 URL 在计算机上提取的内容。
Meanwhile, you might have slash folder slash, which just means show me whatever is inside of this folder.
同时，你可能会有 /folder/，这意味着向我展示此文件夹内的内容。
Or you might have more verbosely slash folder slash file.html, which will show you that file in that folder.
或者你可能会有更冗长的 /folder/file.html，它将向你显示该文件夹中的该文件。
And meanwhile, just to give some other terms of art, this is the so-called fully qualified domain name.
同时，为了给出一些其他的专业术语，这就是所谓的完全限定域名（FQDN）。
And again, these vocab words don't matter all that much, but you'll hear or see them over time.
同样，这些词汇并不重要，但你会随着时间的推移听到或看到它们。
We generally colloquially just refer to this as the domain name, which is a little less precise, but gets the job done certainly in conversation.
我们通常将其称为域名，这不太精确，但在对话中肯定能达到目的。
And this part here I described briefly earlier.
我之前简要地描述过这部分。
What's the name for this suffix at the very end of the fully qualified domain name?
完全限定域名末尾的这个后缀叫什么？
The, yeah.
那个，是的。
Yeah, top-level domain, or TLD.
是的，顶级域名，或者说 TLD。
And this is just some form of categorization of the URLs.
这只是 URL 的一种分类形式。
Now, the internet got its start within the United States.
互联网起源于美国。
And a lot of the first websites, of course, came from the US.
很多第一批网站当然也来自美国。
And so for better or for worse, a sort of stake was planted in the ground.
无论好坏，一种标准就此建立。
So generally, .com indicated, at least early on, that it was some kind of commercial enterprise, a business that owned a domain name.
因此，一般来说，.com 至少在早期表示它属于某种商业企业，即拥有域名的是一家企业。
.edu is an educational institution.
.edu 是教育机构。
.net was some kind of network.
.net 指的是某种网络。
.gov was the US government.
.gov 是美国政府。
Now, there are also country code TLDs, ccTLDs, like .uk or .jp.
现在，还有国家代码 TLD，即 ccTLD，例如 .uk 或 .jp。
Every country in the world has its own two-letter TLD that might very well be restricted to only servers or companies or people in that country.
世界上每个国家都有自己的两个字母的 TLD，这些 TLD 很可能仅限于该国的服务器、公司或个人使用。
Many of them can be used by anyone.
其中许多任何人都可以使用。
You've used a lot of URLs in this class, ending in cs50.io.
你在这门课上使用过很多以 cs50.io 结尾的 URL。
That doesn't mean input-output.
这并不意味着输入输出。
It actually is a TLD from another country that lets anyone on the internet pay for, and on an annual basis, using that domain.
它实际上是另一个国家的 TLD，允许互联网上的任何人付费使用该域名，并且是按年付费。
.tv, for instance, you might see in some cases, like twitch.tv and the like.
例如，你可能在某些情况下看到 .tv，比如 twitch.tv 等等。
That, too, is owned by another country that allows others in the English-speaking world, in this case, to use it as though it connotes TV.
这也是另一个国家拥有的，它允许其他英语国家的人使用它，就好像它代表电视一样。
Those are just different types of TLDs that roughly categorize where the domain lives.
这些只是不同类型的 TLD，它们粗略地分类了域名的所在地。
But it doesn't necessarily mean it's commercial anymore.
但这并不一定意味着它仍然是商业性质的。
It doesn't necessarily mean it's a network anymore.
这也不一定意味着它仍然是一个网络。
For the most part, there are hundreds of TLDs now, for better or for worse, most of which are less common than these big ones.
现在有数百个顶级域名，无论好坏，大多数都没有这些常用的域名常见。
But most anyone can buy most of them with just some restrictions on things like .edu and .gov that are still very much regulated.
但大多数人都可以购买其中的大多数，只有一些像 .edu 和 .gov 这样的域名仍然受到严格监管。
This, meanwhile, is what we might call the hostname, www.
这部分，我们可以称之为主机名，www。
It's obviously a super common convention.
这显然是一个超级常见的惯例。
Like, almost every website uses www as its hostname.
比如，几乎每个网站都使用 www 作为主机名。
But that's a human convention.
但这只是一种人为的惯例。
It's not a requirement.
这不是必需的。
And indeed, some websites don't even bother having a hostname.
事实上，有些网站甚至都没有主机名。
They just use their domain to advertise their website.
他们只使用域名来宣传他们的网站。
This now is going to be the scheme or the protocol.
这部分是方案或协议。
And this is just going to indicate via what protocol the computer, your Mac, your PC, your phone, should use when accessing content at that address.
这表示你的电脑、Mac、PC 或手机在访问该地址的内容时应该使用的协议。
Because indeed, there are other protocols you can use.
因为确实还有其他协议可以使用。
But for the most part, we'll only focus on HTTP or equivalently HTTPS.
但在大多数情况下，我们只关注 HTTP 或等效的 HTTPS。
All right.
好的。
Any questions now on those just definitions, building blocks of URLs, just so we all sort of share a common vocabulary?
关于 URL 的定义和组成部分，还有什么问题吗？这样我们就能使用相同的术语。
Any questions at all?
还有什么问题吗？
Yeah?
有。
Sure.
请说。
We'll come back to this, actually, later today.
我们今天晚些时候会回到这个问题。
There's a technical term known as local host, which is a generic name for your computer, your Mac, your PC, your phone, especially when you're doing software development.
有一个技术术语叫做本地主机，它是指你的电脑、Mac、PC 或手机的通用名称，特别是在进行软件开发时。
And by convention, your own computer has not only whatever IP address you get from your university or your internet service provider, it also has a reflexive IP address, one that just always refers to itself, which is 127.0.0.1.
按照惯例，你自己的计算机不仅有从大学或网络服务提供商那里获得的 IP 地址，
它还有一个反射 IP 地址，这个地址总是指向自身，也就是 127.0.0.1。
And that's just a human convention.
这只是一个行业惯例。
Humans decided that shall refer always to your computer.
人们决定用这个地址来始终指向你的计算机。
And it's actually going to be useful today and onward, because we can use that when doing development on our own computers, ultimately.
这在今天以及以后都会很有用，因为我们最终可以在自己的计算机上进行开发时使用它。
Other questions on URLs, IP, DNS, or any of these building blocks?
关于 URL、IP、DNS 或任何这些基础知识，还有其他问题吗？
All right, so what do we mean by HTTP being a protocol?
那么我们说 HTTP 是一种协议是什么意思呢？
When I extended my hand earlier as a human handshake, a typical human in healthy times would know to respond in turn.
就像我之前伸出手和你握手一样，一个正常人在这种情况下会知道要回握。
Well, how does Brian's computer know to respond to Phyllis' envelope, whatever message is therein?
那么，Brian 的计算机怎么知道如何回应 Phyllis 的信封，以及里面的任何信息呢？
Well, assuming that Brian is indeed still a web server in the story, and Phyllis was trying to upload a cat or maybe download a cat,
假设 Brian 在这个例子中仍然是一个网络服务器，而 Phyllis 试图上传或下载一只猫的图片，
From Brian's web server, inside of Phyllis's envelope would have been a message, literally in text.
那么在 Phyllis 的信封里，会有一条发送给 Brian 网络服务器的文本信息。
And it's English, for the most part.
而且大部分都是英文。
And it would contain, at the beginning of that message, literally one of these English verbs, either get, which means just that, get me the home page, get me a picture of a cat, get me a picture of a dog, or a video, or anything else, or post, which often means
在这条信息的开头，会包含一个英文动词，要么是 get，意思是获取，
比如获取主页、获取猫的图片、获取狗的图片、获取视频等等；要么是 post，通常意思是上传
Post, that is, upload a picture of a cat or a dog or something else to the server instead.
也就是将猫、狗或其他东西的图片上传到服务器。
That's not strictly the only use cases for these, but you can generally think of them as one is just getting information and the other is posting from the client, from Phyllis to the server, in this case, Brian.
这并不是这两个词的唯一用途，但你可以简单地把它们理解为一个是获取信息，另一个是从客户端（在这个例子中是 Phyllis）向服务器（Brian）发送信息。
So those are the two keywords that we might see.
所以这两个是我们可能会看到的关键词。
And why is this useful? Well, it turns out we can start to see in our own Mac or PC Some of these very same messages.
为什么这很有用呢？因为我们可以在自己的 Mac 或 PC 上看到一些这样的信息。
For instance, if Phyllis were visiting not Brian's but example.com, that web server, inside of her metaphorical envelope, there would be a textual message that literally starts with get slash
例如，如果 Phyllis 访问的不是 Brian 的服务器，而是 example.com，那么在她发送的比喻信封中，会有一条文本信息，这条信息以 get / 开头，
Then the word HTTP.
然后是 HTTP。
Then the version she's using.
接着是她使用的版本。
1.1 is very common.
1.1很常见。
2 and 3 are becoming more common.
2和3正变得越来越普遍。
But HTTP generally looks like this.
但HTTP通常是这样的。
The next line of text in her envelope would probably say host colon, then literally the fully qualified domain name of the server she's accessing, just in case.
在她信封的下一行文字可能是“host:”，然后是她正在访问的服务器的完整域名，以防万一。
And this happens super commonly, especially on small websites.
这种情况非常普遍，尤其是在小型网站上。
If one server is hosting multiple domain names, multiple websites, this just distinguishes which one she actually wants.
如果一台服务器托管了多个域名、多个网站，这就能区分她真正想要访问的是哪一个。
And then there's usually a whole bunch of other lines of text as well.
通常还会有一大堆其他的文本行。
So where can you actually see this?
那么你在哪里能真正看到这些呢？
Well, let me actually go ahead and do this.
我来演示一下。
Give me just a moment.
稍等片刻。
And I'm going to open up on my computer here.
我要在我的电脑上打开。
An empty Chrome window in incognito mode.
一个处于隐身模式下的空白 Chrome 窗口。
Generally speaking, incognito mode or private mode is used when you don't want there to be left remnants of what websites you visited.
一般来说，当你不想留下你访问过哪些网站的痕迹时，就会使用隐身模式或隐私模式。
And it has the effect for software developers of just forgetting any things you might have tried already within your browser, including things called cookies.
对于软件开发者来说，它会忘记你在浏览器中已经尝试过的任何东西，包括叫做Cookie的东西。
More on those another time. Your autocomplete history and the like.
这些内容我们下次再讲。包括你的自动完成历史记录等等。
So for development purposes, incognito mode is especially helpful, because it's sort of like starting with a clean slate every time you open a new private or incognito mode.
因此，出于开发目的，隐身模式特别有用，因为它就像每次打开一个新的隐私或隐身模式时，都会从头开始一样。
So there's not going to be any remnants of previous testing or code that you've been playing with.
所以不会有任何之前测试或你一直在使用的代码残留。
And I'm going to go ahead and do this. I'm going to go ahead and right-click.
我要继续操作。我要右键单击。
Or Control-click on Chrome. I'm going to choose Inspect.
或者在 Chrome 上按住 Control 键并单击。我要选择“检查”。
And it's going to pull up this window, sometimes on the side, sometimes on the bottom.
它会弹出一个窗口，有时在侧面，有时在底部。
I'm going to move it to the bottom just so we can see it a little more readily.
我将它移动到底部，这样我们就能更容易地看到它。
And I'm going to zoom in.
我要放大。
And it's going to look a little arcane at first.
一开始它看起来可能有点神秘。
And I'm going to just highlight a few of these tabs.
我将重点介绍其中的一些选项卡。
We'll see here along the top that there's Elements, Console, Sources, Network, and a whole bunch of other things as well.
我们看到顶部有 Elements（元素）、Console（控制台）、Sources（源代码）、Network（网络）以及其他很多东西。
This is sort of the advanced mode in Chrome.
这是 Chrome 的高级模式。
And Safari and Firefox and Edge have their own equivalents of these features.
Safari、Firefox 和 Edge 也有自己相应的功能。
They've always been there, even if you've never clicked the right button to enable these features.
这些功能一直都在，即使你从未点击右键启用它们。
And I'm going to focus for a moment on network, like this.
我想先关注一下 Network（网络）。
This is a feature of the browser that's going to allow me, the programmer in this case, or the engineer, to just kind of look at what messages my browser is actually sending to a server.
这是浏览器的一项功能，它允许我，也就是这个案例中的程序员或工程师，查看我的浏览器实际发送给服务器的消息。
So let me go ahead and do something like this.
让我来演示一下。
Let me go ahead and visit.
我准备访问。
For instance, in my browser here, and I'm going to shrink the window just a little bit so we can see it exactly, I'm going to visit https://www.harvard.edu.
例如，在我的浏览器中，为了让我们能清楚地看到，我将缩小窗口，我要访问 https://www.harvard.edu。
And now I'm going to hit Enter. And a whole bunch of stuff just happened along the bottom of my screen.
现在我按下回车键。我的屏幕底部出现了一堆东西。
And I'm going to try to pull my window up just a little bit so we can focus on a subset of this.
我试着把窗口向上拉一点，这样我们就可以集中注意力看其中一部分内容。
Let me pull this up, covering up really the content of the page, focusing on these lower-level details down here.
让我把它拉上来，遮住页面的内容，重点关注下面这些底层细节。
And what I want to see first is
我想先看的是，
Let me go ahead and reload this page here after retaining the log so that we can see absolutely everything on the screen.
让我在保留日志的情况下重新加载这个页面，以便我们可以在屏幕上看到所有内容。
And to be clear, I just checked, because I forgot earlier, preserve log, because I wanted to preserve everything on the screen.
需要说明的是，我刚刚勾选了“Preserve Log（保留日志）”，因为我之前忘记了，我想保留屏幕上的所有内容。
I want to see everything all at once.
我想一次性看到所有内容。
And we'll see this.
我们来看看这个。
The very first line of output is completely overwhelming with detail at first glance.
第一行的输出信息非常多，乍一看让人眼花缭乱。
But what you'll see here, if I start to scroll down,
但你会看到，如果我开始往下滚动，
And down and down and down are the so-called request headers.
一直往下，这些就是所谓的请求头。
And let me zoom in here.
让我放大这里。
And what you're seeing inside of Chrome, inside of its Network tab, in its so-called Developer Tools, again, this is just for engineering types, you'll see all of the headers, all of the lines of text that magically were sent by my Mac
在 Chrome 浏览器中，在它的 Network（网络）选项卡里，
在它的开发者工具中，再说一遍，这只是给工程师看的，你会看到所有的头信息，所有由我的 Mac 发送的文本行，
to Harvard.edu, much like from Phyllis to Brian's server in that story, so I can see exactly what messengers are being sent.
发送到 Harvard.edu，就像从 Phyllis 发送到 Brian 的服务器一样，所以我可以看到发送了什么消息。
And a lot of this we haven't talked about yet, but we do see some mention of get, and we see some mention of slash, and a bunch of other arcane details.
这里面很多东西我们还没有讲到，但我们确实看到了一些 get 的字样，还有一些斜杠，以及其他一些神秘的细节。
But notice, they're all sort of key value pairs, with the colon here indicating
但请注意，它们都是键值对，冒号表示
What the corresponding value is.
对应的值是什么。
Now, most of this is not going to be interesting.
大部分内容都不太有趣。
And we're not going to focus too much on the weeds of all of this.
我们不会过多关注这些细节。
But it indeed gives us a sense of what's inside of that virtual envelope.
但这确实让我们了解了虚拟信封里的内容。
Now, harvard.edu is one thing.
现在，harvard.edu 只是一个网站。
But there's other websites we might visit as well.
但我们也可能会访问其他网站。
And no matter what they are, we're going to expect, ultimately, an HTTP response.
无论它们是什么，我们最终都期望得到一个 HTTP 响应。
So in addition to a computer, like my Mac or Phyllis's computer, sending a request containing gets and host and those details, too, you'll see here in my slide form just representative response from the server.
因此，除了像我的 Mac 或 Phyllis 的电脑这样的计算机
发送包含 get、host 和其他信息的请求之外，你还会在我的幻灯片中看到服务器的代表性响应。
And notice that key here is that the server is responding in the same version of HTTP in this example.
注意，这里的关键是服务器正在使用相同版本的 HTTP 进行响应。
It's sending back this so-called status code, just a numeric code that indicates, in this case, that everything's OK.
它返回了这个所谓的“状态码”，只是一个数字代码，在这种情况下表示一切正常。
And it includes this header, this HTTP header, which, again, is just a key value pair saying that the type of this content that's coming back from the server is text slash HTML.
它包含这个 HTTP 头信息，它也是一个键值对，表示从服务器返回的内容类型是 text/html。
More on HTML in just a little bit.
稍后会详细介绍 HTML。
But for our purposes now, this just means that harvard.edu is sending me back a web page.
就目前而言，这对我们来说意味着 harvard.edu 正在给我发送一个网页。
And indeed, if we hide all of this technical stuff, that's the web page that we saw up here with all of the usual imagery and the like.
确实，如果我们隐藏所有这些技术内容，这就是我们在上面看到的所有常见图像等组成的网页。
And in fact, I can see this if I scroll back up, not to request headers, but response headers.
事实上，如果我向上滚动，不是查看请求头，而是查看响应头，就可以看到这一点。
You'll see up here that we get back responses, including the date that the server responded and a whole bunch of other details as well.
你会在上面看到我们收到的响应，包括服务器响应的日期以及其他一堆详细信息。
And honestly, this has always been under your fingertips.
老实说，这些内容一直都在你的掌控之中。
And it will soon be useful as we start making web-based applications ultimately.
当我们最终开始制作基于网络的应用程序时，它很快就会派上用场。
But this very quickly gets overwhelming quickly.
但这很快就会让人不知所措。
And so better than this might actually be a tool that we can use within our code space itself.
因此，比这更好的方法可能是在代码空间内使用一个工具。
So let me go back to VS Code here.
让我们回到 VS Code。
I didn't open any code tabs.
我没有打开任何代码选项卡。
I'm just going to use my terminal window for a moment.
我只想暂时使用我的终端窗口。
And I'm going to run a couple of commands that are going to allow me to actually see what is going on when I request one website.
我要运行几个命令，这些命令可以让我看到当我请求一个网站时发生了什么。
Let me go ahead and use a command called curl.
让我继续使用一个名为 curl 的命令。
for connect URL.
代表连接 URL。
And this is like a command line, black and white program, that's going to pretend to be a browser.
这就像一个命令行，黑白程序，它将假装成一个浏览器。
And it's going to connect to the URL, show me the headers.
它将连接到 URL，向我显示标题。
But it's not going to show me the images or the graphics, which might very well be useful to the humans, but not to me right now as the developer.
但它不会向我显示图像或图形，这对人类来说可能很有用，但现在对我这个开发者来说却并非如此。
So I'm going to do curl.
所以我要运行 curl。
I'm going to do dash i. And then I'm going to do HTTPS colon slash slash www.harvard.edu slash, as though I'm pretending to be a browser requesting the home page.
我要输入 `-I`。然后输入 `https://www.harvard.edu/`，就像我假装成浏览器请求主页一样。
And what's nice about curl is, albeit overwhelming, too, you'll get back a whole response from the server containing only those header values, the key value pairs inside of the envelope.
curl 的优点在于，虽然它的响应内容很多，但你能从中获得服务器返回的完整响应，其中只包含那些头部值，也就是信封内的键值对。
And we'll ignore almost all of these.
我们几乎会忽略所有这些。
But here is the response from the server.
但这是来自服务器的响应。
It responded using a new and improved version of HTTP, in this case, version 2.
它使用更新改进的 HTTP 版本（这里是版本 2）进行响应。
And it gave me back a 200.
它返回给我一个 200。
There's my content type, text slash HTML.
这是我的内容类型，text/html。
And then this char set happens to do with the encoding, if it's Unicode or ASCII or something else.
这个字符集与编码方式有关，比如是 Unicode、ASCII 还是其他编码。
And then there's all this other overwhelming detail for now.
然后是所有其他暂时不需要关注的细节。
But this is the beginnings of my ability to just kind of poke around and see how the server works.
但这让我开始能够四处探索，看看服务器是如何工作的。
And it turns out, too, that we'll be able to see other potential responses as well.
事实证明，我们还能看到其他可能的响应。
So for instance, HTTP might not only return 100.
例如，HTTP 可能不会只返回 100。
What if I do this instead?
如果我这样做会怎么样？
Let me go ahead and visit curl-i http://www.harvard.edu.
让我访问一下 curl -I http://www.harvard.edu。
So notice I deliberately use the insecure version of the URL.
注意，我故意使用了不安全的 URL 版本。
which maybe Harvard's system administration doesn't like anymore.
这可能是哈佛的系统管理员不再支持的。
Well, how can they ensure that I, the end user, the student, nonetheless use HTTPS, even if I didn't type it myself?
那么，即使我没有亲自输入 HTTPS，他们如何确保我（最终用户，学生）仍然使用 HTTPS 呢？
Well, let me run just that command with just HTTP, not HTTPS.
让我只使用 HTTP 运行这个命令，而不是 HTTPS。
And you'll see that everything is not OK.
你会发现一切都不正常。
It didn't come back with a 200.
它没有返回 200。
It came back with 301 in this message saying, Harvard moved permanently.
它返回了 301，并在消息中说，哈佛已经永久迁移了。
But here's where you can look for another clue.
但你可以在这里寻找另一个线索。
Among all of these lines, most of which I don't care about, there's a location header, colon, that's a little hint to me that says where Harvard University has apparently moved to on the web.
在所有这些行中，大多数我都不关心，有一个位置标头，冒号，这对我来说是一个小提示，它表明了哈佛大学在网络上的新地址。
And what's different about this URL, just to be clear?
为了清楚起见，这个 URL 有什么不同？
It has the S included.
它包含了 S。
And what your browser will do by default, because Google and Microsoft and Mozilla programmed it this way, whenever it sees a 301 response instead of 200, it won't show you any web page.
你的浏览器默认会这样做，因为 Google、Microsoft 和 Mozilla 都是这样编程的，
每当它看到 301 响应而不是 200 时，它就不会向你显示任何网页。
It will look for a location header, find that URL, and then automatically, quote unquote, redirect you there, too.
它会查找位置标头，找到那个 URL，然后自动地，"重定向" 你到那里。
So this is why it doesn't matter what we type in the browser.
所以这就是为什么我们在浏览器中输入什么内容并不重要。
Harvard can have its servers send these semi-secret messages to our browsers, and then it will just visit a second URL all automatically.
哈佛大学可以让他们的服务器向我们的浏览器发送这些半秘密信息，然后它会自动访问第二个 URL。
And you can do this with host names as well.
你也可以对主机名这样做。
Suppose that Harvard does not want to standardize on harvard.edu.
假设哈佛大学不想标准化为 harvard.edu。
Why?
为什么？
They just want it to always be www. Maybe it's a branding thing. Maybe it's a technical thing. We can see the exact same response here.
他们只是希望它永远是 www。 也许是品牌问题。也许是技术问题。我们可以在这里看到完全相同的回应。
This first tells me, when I visit HTTP, harvard.edu with no www, Harvard minimally wants me to be using a secure connection.
这首先告诉我，当我访问没有 www 的 http，harvard.edu 时，哈佛大学至少希望我使用安全连接。
If I then, OK, fine, cooperate.
如果我同意了，好吧。
Let me go ahead and clear my screen.
让我继续清除屏幕。
Let me add the S, but not the www.
让我添加 S，但不要添加 www。
You can see here that it again responded with a 301.
你可以在这里看到它再次用 301 响应。
up here, and the location now adds the www.
在上面，现在的位置添加了 www。
So it's just a way of bouncing users from one place to another.
所以这只是将用户从一个地方弹到另一个地方的一种方式。
And this is all thanks to HTTP boiling down to relatively simple messages inside of the envelope that tell the computer, the browser in this case,
这都要归功于 HTTP，它归根结底是在信封中包含的相对简单的消息，这些消息告诉计算机，在本例中是浏览器。
How to respond.
如何响应。
Now, odds are you've seen others besides 301, even though you've probably never seen that actual number, unless you've done this kind of thing before.
可能你见过 301 以外的其他代码，即使你可能从未见过这个具体的数字，除非你以前做过这类事情。
But there probably is a number that everyone in this room has seen, even if you've never really wondered, why is it that number?
但是，这个房间里的每个人可能都见过一个数字，即使你从未真正想过，为什么是这个数字？
I think you're smiling. What number are you thinking of?
我觉得你在笑。你在想什么数字？
Yeah, so 404.
没错，是 404。
Why is 404?
为什么是 404？
Well, 404 indicates, by convention, not found.
按照惯例，404 表示未找到。
And now why the world decided years ago to show us normal humans on the internet 404 is anything significant is unclear.
多年前，网络世界决定向我们这些互联网用户展示 404 代码的原因尚不清楚。
That's sort of like bad design.
这有点像糟糕的设计。
Like, what do I care if the status code is 404?
比如，我为什么要关心状态码是 404？
But it's common enough on the internet that probably all of us have seen it.
但它在互联网上很常见，我们可能都见过。
But that just means that some server, when you visit a URL that's incorrect, maybe it's outdated, the URL has been changed,
但这仅仅意味着当你访问一个不正确的 URL 时，比如它过时了，URL 已经更改了，某些服务器会返回这个代码。
If you see a 404, it just means that the virtual envelope that came from the server back to your Mac or PC or phone contains not 200 OK, not 301 moved permanently, but 404 not found instead.
如果你看到 404，这仅仅意味着从服务器返回到你的 Mac、PC
或手机的虚拟信封中包含的不是 200 OK，也不是 301 永久移动，而是 404 未找到。
And it's usually accompanied by a technical message, maybe a cute picture of a cat sort of hiding because it means not found, or something like that.
它通常伴随着一条技术信息，也许是一张猫的可爱图片，因为它意味着未找到，或者类似的东西。
The aesthetics are entirely up to the server, but that's what the 404 means.
美学完全取决于服务器，但这就是 404 的含义。
And there's other codes, too, a few of which you'll use in the coming weeks as we transition from command line programs in C and Python to web-based ones.
还有其他代码，在接下来的几周里，当我们从 C 和 Python 的命令行程序过渡到基于网络的程序时，你会用到其中的一些代码。
We've seen a few of these already, and several of them are kind of variants of the same thing, like these 300 ones here.
我们已经见过其中的一些，其中有几个是同一事物的变体，比如这里的这几个 300。
But we'll see others, like 403 forbidden means you probably forgot to log in or you need to log in or something like that.
但我们还会看到其他的，比如 403 禁止访问，这意味着你可能忘记登录，或者你需要登录，或者类似的情况。
Internal server error, right now, no.
内部服务器错误，现在还没有。
In the coming weeks, you will absolutely encounter 500 errors.
在接下来的几周里，你肯定会遇到 500 错误。
And they're always your fault.
这些错误总是你的错。
It's going to be the equivalent of a segmentation fault in C. A 500 error means you or I screwed up when writing some code.
它相当于 C 语言中的段错误。500 错误意味着你或者我在编写代码时犯了错误。
So we're going to see that. But it's just going to be an opportunity for us to fix it.
我们会看到这种错误，但这只是一个让我们修复的机会。
If a server is overloaded, you often see 503, like something's unavailable because something's too popular or is maybe worse, getting attacked.
如果服务器过载，你经常会看到 503 错误，比如某些内容不可用，因为某些内容太受欢迎了，或者更糟糕，正在遭受攻击。
This is an old example.
这是一个旧例子。
April Fool's joke, 418 is not actually used in practice, but someone took the time to write up an entire formal technical proposal so that servers can respond saying, I am a teapot.
愚人节玩笑，418 实际上没有在实践中使用，但是有人花时间写了一份完整的正式技术提案，以便服务器可以回复说：“我是一个茶壶”。
So it's kind of part of internet lore, and there's other ones of these status codes as well.
所以这算是互联网传说的一部分，还有其他的状态码也是这样。
But this is useful because eventually we'll see in code you can use this understanding, high level as it might be of HTTP, to do some interesting and powerful things.
但这很有用，因为最终我们会在代码中看到，你可以利用这种对 HTTP 的理解（尽管它可能很高深）来做一些有趣且强大的事情。
So for instance,
例如，
We can even send fancier URLs to servers.
我们甚至可以向服务器发送更复杂的 URL。
It turns out, as we'll soon see, if you send a message like this, get slash search question mark q equals cat, and then HTTP 1.1 or whatever version, and you send that message to Google's server, www.google.com, this is how you can specify not just the path of a web page that you want, slash search in this case.
事实证明，正如我们很快就会看到的，如果你发送一条消息，比如 get/search?q=cat，
然后是 http 1.1 或任何版本，并将该消息发送到谷歌的服务器 www.google.com，你就可以指定你想要的网页路径，在本例中是/search。
The question mark, it turns out, is going to be a convention in the internet, in the web specifically, for passing user input to the server as well.
事实证明，问号将成为互联网上，特别是网络上的一种惯例，用于将用户输入传递给服务器。
In fact, you've probably never paid close attention to URLs, but they very often have question marks.
事实上，你可能从未密切关注过 URL，但它们经常有问号。
They very often have equal signs.
它们经常有等号。
And indeed, even google.com supports a certain key, Q in this case, for query.
实际上，即使是 google.com 也支持一个特定的键，在本例中是 Q，用于查询。
And you can put anything you want after that in order to search for actual cats.
你可以在它后面放任何你想放的东西，以便搜索真正的猫。
So if I actually go back to Chrome itself here for a moment,
所以如果我现在回到 Chrome 浏览器，
Let me pull back open my Chrome browser here.
让我打开我的 Chrome 浏览器。
Previously, I was using incognito mode for harvard.edu.
之前，我在访问 harvard.edu 时使用了隐身模式。
I've gone ahead and closed that window and opened a new one so we can start fresh by visiting Google.
我已经关闭了那个窗口，并打开了一个新窗口，这样我们就可以通过访问谷歌来重新开始了。
Normally, you and I are in the habit of going to google.com and searching via the form.
通常情况下，你我都会习惯性地打开 google.com，并通过搜索框进行搜索。
Or nowadays, you just type your search query in the browser itself, and it brings you automatically to Google or Bing or something else.
或者现在，你只需直接在浏览器中输入搜索内容，它就会自动跳转到 Google、Bing 或其他搜索引擎。
But I can really be pedantic here.
但我可以在这里稍微“迂腐”一下。
Let me go ahead and zoom in.
让我放大一点。
And I'll manually go to HTTPS colon slash slash www.google.com slash search.
我会手动输入 https://www.google.com/search。
Question mark q equals maybe cats.
问号 q 等于 比如 cats。
Now, this would not be a very user-friendly experience if all of us had to manually type out something crazy like that.
如果我们每个人都必须手动输入这样复杂的内容，那用户体验将非常糟糕。
But that's what the form is redirecting you to when you type in more user-friendly cats into a text box.
但这就是当你把 cats 这个词更友好地输入到文本框中时，表单将你重定向到的地址。
If I hit Enter here, we'll get back, indeed, a whole bunch of search results about cats.
如果我在这里按下回车键，我们会得到一大堆关于猫的搜索结果。
If I zoom back in, and maybe I change it from cats to dogs, that too is going to change.
如果我缩小一点，把 cats 改成 dogs，搜索结果也会随之改变。
And notice it's pre-populating the text box, because Google has written its code in order to do so as well.
注意，文本框会预先填充内容，因为 Google 已经编写了相应的代码来实现这一点。
Now, apropos of the video with which we began today from yesteryear, one of the better Yale pranks over the years, has anyone actually ever been to safetyschool.org?
说到今天开头播放的怀旧视频，这是耶鲁大学多年来最棒的恶作剧之一，有人真的去过 safetyschool.org 吗？
And to our friends at Yale watching live, hi, safetyschool.org.
向正在观看直播的耶鲁朋友们问好，safetyschool.org。
So it's kind of fun if you actually visit it, depending on who you are.
如果你真的访问了这个网站， depending on who you are，它会很有趣。
So if I open up a new window here, and I go to http://safetyschool.org, zooming in, Enter.
如果我在这里打开一个新窗口，输入 http://safetyschool.org，放大，回车。
My, oh, my.
我的天哪。
Look at where it goes.
看看它跳转到了哪里。
Now, how does that?
这是怎么做到的？
OK.
好的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
This is not a CS50 thing.
这不是 CS50 的东西。
Someone out there who I don't know who they are for like 20 years has been paying annually for that domain, safetyschool.org, for just this joke.
20 年来，有个我不知道是谁的人每年都为 safetyschool.org 这个域名付费，就为了开这个玩笑。
But if I now go back into VS Code here in my terminal window, and a little more sophisticatedly, let me do curl dash i HTTP colon slash slash SafetySchool.org.
但如果我现在回到 VS Code 终端窗口，用更高级一点的方法，让我用 curl -I http:// safetyschool.org。
The browser, of course, immediately redirected me to the website.
浏览器当然会立即跳转到这个网站。
But what's going on underneath the hood?
但是背后发生了什么呢？
Well, 20-some years ago, someone bought the domain, configured the server, quite simply to spit this out.
20 多年前，有人购买了这个域名，配置了服务器，只是为了显示这个。
SafetySchool.org, for years, has moved permanently to www.yale.edu.
safetyschool.org 多年来已永久迁移至 www.yale.edu。
So just a little demonstration of what you can do with just a little bit of understanding of HTTP.
这只是一个小小的演示，展示了只要稍微了解一下 HTTP 就能做到的事情。
That's been a lot already.
内容已经很多了。
We've laid the foundation for understanding how the internet works.
我们已经为理解互联网的工作原理奠定了基础。
Now we're going to use it with a language called HTML, Hypertext Markup Language, CSS, Cascading Style Sheets, and JavaScript, a proper programming language.
现在我们将使用 HTML（超文本标记语言）、CSS（层叠样式表）和 JavaScript（一种编程语言）来使用它。
But first, it feels opportune to take a 10-minute break.
但首先，我们应该休息十分钟。
We have some wonderful Halloween candy in the transept, and we'll be back in 10 with those languages.
我们在过道里准备了一些万圣节糖果，10 分钟后回来继续学习这些语言。
We're headed up to Boston.
我们要去波士顿。
Checking out the stadium for the prank.
去体育场看看那个恶作剧。
A few years ago, I was at a math conference.
几年前，我参加了一个数学会议。
And I was sitting around at the table at dinner with a few other mathematicians.
我和其他几位数学家围坐在餐桌旁。
And one of them went to Harvard and started telling the story of this amazing prank that was against Harvard.
其中一个人去了哈佛大学，开始讲述一个关于哈佛大学的惊人恶作剧的故事。
And at that point, I felt I had to interrupt and said, well, actually, I can tell you a lot more about that.
那时，我觉得我必须打断他，说，实际上，我可以告诉你更多关于这件事的信息。
The idea was perfected in a dorm room.
这个想法是在宿舍房间里完善的。
We came up with the idea, actually, to prank them with signs at the football game.
实际上，我们想出这个主意是为了在橄榄球比赛中用标语来捉弄他们。
We threw some ideas out there as far as what the signs would say.
我们为标语上写什么想了一些点子。
We eventually settled on, we suck.
我们最终决定用“我们很烂”。
And my immediate reaction was, no, this will never work.
我立刻的反应是，不行，这行不通。
However, the problem solver in me started thinking, well, maybe we can make this work.
然而，我内心深处解决问题的那一面开始思考，也许我们可以让这行得通。
Problem?
问题？
They had to infiltrate Harvard Stadium without getting caught, sneak in 1,800 placards, distribute them to unsuspecting Harvard fans, and then convince those fans to prank themselves.
他们必须潜入哈佛体育场而不被发现，偷偷带入 1800 个标语牌，把它们分发给毫不知情的哈佛球迷，然后说服这些球迷捉弄自己。
We thought about basically every possible thing that could go wrong and tried to come up with a solution for it.
我们基本上考虑了所有可能出错的地方，并试图想出解决方案。
They made fake Harvard IDs and fake backstories, fake placard designs, and a 28-member fake pep squad.
他们制作了假的哈佛身份证和假的背景故事、假的标语牌设计，以及一个 28 人的假啦啦队。
On November 20, 2004, the fake Harvard students smuggled the placards into the game.
2004 年 11 月 20 日，这些假哈佛学生将标语牌偷运进了比赛场地。
But then, trouble.
但是，麻烦来了。
I just showed him the front of this ID and all of a sudden he just ran away and he felt so embarrassed.
我刚给他看了这张身份证的正面，突然间他就跑开了，他感到很尴尬。
Having escaped one confrontation, they couldn't risk another.
躲过了一次冲突后，他们不能再冒险了。
It was time.
是时候了。
This just looks like a total mess.
这看起来简直一团糟。
We have absolutely no idea if this is going to work.
我们完全不知道这是否会成功。
What was once a prank became a legend.
曾经的恶作剧变成了一个传奇。
And immediately we started hearing chants from the other side, You suck!
我们马上就听到对面传来一阵阵的喊声，“你们很烂！”
You suck!
“你们很烂！”
And I think it was at that point in time that we knew we had pulled it off.
我想就在那时，我们知道我们成功了。
There it goes again!
又来了！
I really think it didn't matter that Harvard won because of the prank.
我真的觉得哈佛因为这场恶作剧赢了并不重要。
For a lot of Yale students and alumni, we definitely won that year.
对很多耶鲁学生和校友来说，那一年我们绝对赢了。
Thank you all.
谢谢大家。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Oh, here.
给你。
Oh, all right.
好吧。
A little Halloween candy.
一点万圣节糖果。
Thank you all.
谢谢大家。
So glad I wore the same thing today.
真高兴我今天穿了同样的衣服。
So in just a moment, thank you.
稍等片刻，谢谢。
OK, so in just a moment, we'll transition to understanding all the more now what we can do with this underlying infrastructure.
好，稍等片刻，我们将继续了解现在可以利用这个底层基础设施做些什么。
So again, HTTP and below it, TCP, IP is all about just getting the data from point A to point B in some standardized way.
同样，HTTP 以及它之下的 TCP、IP，都只是为了以某种标准化的方式将数据从 A 点传输到 B 点。
But now let's talk about HTML.
现在我们来谈谈 HTML。
This is the language in which web pages themselves are written, hypertext markup language.
这是编写网页本身的语言，超文本标记语言。
Now, some of you might have used this before to make personal home pages.
你们中有些人可能以前用过它来制作个人主页。
Some of you might have dabbled, even if using some website to create your own home page.
你们中有些人可能涉猎过，即使是使用某些网站来创建自己的主页。
But understanding this language is useful, certainly for creating the aesthetics of a web page, conveying data that's of interest.
但理解这种语言很有用，当然是为了创建网页的美感，传达感兴趣的数据。
But at the end of the day, it and the language we'll look at next, CSS, are not programming languages.
但说到底，它和我们接下来要学习的语言 CSS 都不是编程语言。
There's going to be no functions, no loops, no programming logic.
不会涉及函数、循环和编程逻辑。
But we will end today with a teaser of a proper programming language called JavaScript via which you can manipulate all of these various other languages as well.
但今天我们会以一个名为 JavaScript 的编程语言作为结束，你可以通过它来操作所有这些不同的语言。
So ultimately, HTML has two features.
最终，HTML 只有两个特点。
And this is a language that we spend very brief amount of time on because it really boils down to just a couple of basic ideas and then vocabulary that you'll build out over time just by googling, looking up references, looking at other pages, source code.
我们只会花很短的时间介绍这门语言，因为它实际上可以归结为几个基本概念和一些词汇，
你可以通过谷歌搜索、查阅参考资料、查看其他网页源代码来逐渐积累这些词汇。
But tags and attributes are what characterize HTML. Now, what do I mean by that?
但标签和属性是 HTML 的特征。这是什么意思呢？
Here, for instance, is the HTML code via which you can make probably the simplest of all web pages, one that quite simply says in the browser window, hello, title, and hello, body, for instance.
例如，这是一段 HTML 代码，通过它可以创建最简单的网页，它只在浏览器窗口中显示“hello, title”和“hello, body”。
Now, what does this actually mean?
这到底是什么意思呢？
If you imagine opening up.
想象一下打开。
This code, in a browser, be it on a Mac or PC or phone, you'll see typically some kind of rectangular window.
这段代码，在浏览器中，无论是在 Mac、PC 还是手机上，你通常会看到一个矩形的窗口。
And there's usually a tab that has the title of that page.
通常会有一个显示页面标题的标签页。
And then most of the rectangular region is the web page itself.
矩形区域的大部分是网页本身。
What you're looking at, then, is the code that's going to put hello title in the title bar in the tab at the very top.
你所看到的代码，会将“hello title”放在顶部的标签页标题栏中。
And down at the bottom, hello body is going to be all that's in the big black and white box that composes the rest of the browser window itself.
而“hello body”会显示在构成浏览器窗口其余部分的黑白框中。
Now, what are the salient characteristics here that we'll now start to take for granted?
那么，这里有哪些显著的特点，我们将开始习以为常呢？
Well, first, whoops.
首先，哎呀。
First, let's go ahead and give me just a moment here and actually do something with this code.
首先，稍等一下，让我用这段代码做点什么。
So I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我要做的是。
Back in VS Code here, I'm going to first create a file called, say, hello.html.
回到 VS Code 中，我首先创建一个名为“hello.html”的文件。
And in this tab, I'm going to go ahead and really repeat exactly that same code.
在这个标签页中，我将完全重复相同的代码。
Now, I had this line first, doctype HTML.
首先是这一行，"DOCTYPE html"。
Then I had this line, HTML lang equals quote, unquote, EN, close quote. Then I had inside of that head. Then I had inside of that title. Then inside of that, I had hello, title.
然后我写了这行代码：html lang 等于引号，引号，en，结束引号。
然后我在 head 标签里，写了 title 标签，然后在 title 标签里，我写了 hello, title。
And I'm doing this quickly, because we'll tease apart in a moment what it actually all means.
我快速地演示一下，稍后我们会详细解释这些代码的含义。
And then down here, below that so-called head, I had just the text, hello, body.
然后在下面，在所谓的 head 标签下面，我只写了文本：hello, body。
So at the moment, that, I claim, is the entirety of a web page.
我认为，目前这就是一个完整的网页了。
But it currently lives in my code space, so to speak, in a file called hello.html.
但它目前存在于我的代码空间中，在一个名为 hello.html 的文件中。
That's fine if I want to create it.
如果我只想创建它，这样就可以了。
But how do I, how do you, how does anyone on the internet actually view it?
但是我，你，互联网上的任何人，如何才能真正地查看它呢？
Well, to serve a web page, you indeed need a web server.
要提供网页服务，你需要一个网络服务器。
And it turns out that Codespaces comes with one of these pre-installed, because we, CS50 staff, did so for you.
事实证明，Codespaces 预装了网络服务器，因为我们 CS50 的工作人员已经为你准备好了。
And what you can do in a terminal window, once you have an HTML file ready to go that you want the world to see, you can literally run in your terminal window HTTP dash server.
当你准备好了一个 HTML 文件并希望全世界都能看到它时，你可以在终端窗口中运行 http-server 这条命令。
Single command.
一条简单的命令。
And what that's going to do for you is start a web server, that is to say,
这将为你启动一个网络服务器。
A program whose purpose in life is just to serve web pages.
也就是说，这是一个以提供网页服务为目的的程序。
And even though probably up until now, for years, you probably, if you're like me, equate server, quote unquote, with a physical device, server is really a piece of software.
尽管到目前为止，你可能已经认为“服务器”是一个物理设备很多年了（如果你和我一样），但服务器实际上是一段软件。
It just tends to run on big, fancy devices.
它只是倾向于在大型、复杂的设备上运行。
So when we say server, we often all think of, in our mind's eye, big, expensive devices, perhaps.
所以当我们说“服务器”时，我们脑海中浮现的通常是大型、昂贵的设备。
But a server is just a program whose purpose in life is to respond to requests with responses.
但服务器只是一个程序，它的作用是用响应来回应请求。
And that's the vernacular there.
这就是行话。
Now, once you run HTTP server, and I'm going to do a bit of magic because I set this up before class just to make sure it goes smoothly, you'll see some output like this.
现在，一旦你运行 http-server，你会看到一些这样的输出（为了确保课程顺利进行，我已经提前设置好了）。
whereby your server is now available on a very long URL.
你的服务器现在可以通过一个很长的 URL 访问。
Mine here is a very long URL that will be different from yours.
我的这里是一个很长的 URL，它和你的会不一样。
But what this is is a unique identifier that your code space has temporarily generated so that you can now access, and ideally only you can access, that file using your browser.
但这是一个你的代码空间临时生成的唯一标识符，这样你就可以访问这个文件，理想情况下只有你可以使用浏览器访问。
Now, if I flip the URL or you flip the URL to public by right-clicking or control-clicking the right features of VS Code, you can enable anyone in the world to visit it.
现在，如果你通过右键单击或 Ctrl+单击 VS Code 的相应功能将 URL 设为公开，你就可以让世界上任何人都可以访问它。
But we're not going to ultimately host our websites in your code space, because as soon as you log off for the night and the thing shuts down, the website will go down.
但我们最终不会把我们的网站托管在你的代码空间里，因为一旦你晚上退出登录，网站就会关闭。
But at the end of the semester, particularly for final projects, we'll show you ways that you can put your own website, your own code, on the actual internet 24-7, 365,
但在学期末，特别是对于期末项目，我们会告诉你如何将你自己的网站、你自己的代码放到互联网上，全天候、全年无休地运行，
even with your own domain name if you want to get one, so that it lives independent of your own sleep schedule and usage schedule of VS Code here.
甚至如果你想的话，还可以使用你自己的域名，这样它就可以独立于你自己的作息时间和 VS Code 的使用时间表而存在。
So I'm going to go ahead now and visit.
所以我现在要继续访问。
This URL in another tab of my browser.
我在浏览器另一个标签页中打开这个 URL。
And what I'll see here is this.
我将看到的是这个。
This is the output of that program called HTTP Server.
这是名为 http-server 的程序的输出。
And essentially, what it is doing is it's using TCP and IP in conjunction with HTTP to just run your very own web server on GitHub's own servers as well.
本质上，它所做的是结合使用 TCP 和 IP 以及 HTTP，在 GitHub 自己的服务器上运行你自己的网络服务器。
And that's because of different ports.
这是因为端口不同。
Again, we won't go too much into the weeds of the TCP, the IP, and all of that stuff.
同样，我们不会过多地讨论 TCP、IP 以及所有这些东西的细节。
But recall that different port numbers can allow you to distinguish one service from another.
但请记住，不同的端口号可以让你区分不同的服务。
Now, one of the services is, of course, your code space, VS Code in the cloud that we've been using for weeks.
当然，其中一项服务是你的代码空间，也就是我们已经使用了几周的云端 VS Code。
But if you want to use the same physical server that GitHub controls, but actually visit your own web server that I just ran in my terminal window in another tab, that's fine.
但是，如果你想使用 GitHub 控制的同一台物理服务器，但在另一个标签页中访问我刚刚在终端窗口中运行的你自己的网络服务器，那也是可以的。
They're just going to be using different TCP ports.
它们只是使用不同的 TCP 端口。
And you and I don't have to care what they are, but just that this is a feature.
你我都无需关心它们是什么，只需要知道这是一个功能。
that TCP supports.
TCP 支持的功能。
So what you see here is somewhat arcane.
所以你在这里看到的有点晦涩难懂。
This is not like a thing that most people on the internet should ever see.
这不是大多数互联网用户应该看到的东西。
I'm just doing this for development purposes.
我只是为了开发目的才这样做。
But this is the index, that is, the directory, the folder contents of my code space.
但这是索引，也就是目录，我的代码空间的文件夹内容。
And because I deleted everything from prior weeks already, all we see right now is hello.html, which I just created.
因为我已经删除了前几周的所有内容，所以我们现在看到的只有我刚创建的 hello.html。
So if I click on hello.html within this folder listing, you'll be a little underwhelmed.
所以如果我点击文件夹列表中的 hello.html，你会觉得有点乏味。
And I'll zoom in just so there's something more interesting there.
我放大一点，这样看起来更有趣些。
But now you see hello, body.
现在你看到了 hello，body。
But what's interesting, perhaps, is that after this long, very cryptic, and uninteresting URL, notice at the very end of it, and I'll zoom in in a moment, what do you see?
但有趣的是，在这个很长、很神秘、很无趣的 URL 后面，注意它的最后，我一会儿会放大，你看到了什么？
Slash hello.html, which follows the convention I claimed before break
斜杠 hello.html，这遵循了我之前提到的惯例
is how a browser would allow you to access a specific file on a server by doing slash and then the name of the file name.
浏览器就是通过斜杠加文件名来访问服务器上的特定文件的。
Everything before it is very cryptic.
它前面的所有内容都非常神秘。
It would be better if I buy a domain name that's a little more easy to remember and set that up some other time.
如果我买一个更容易记住的域名，并在其他时间进行设置，那就更好了。
But for now, let's just focus on only the file names that I'm actually creating.
但现在，让我们只关注我实际创建的文件名。
All right, so the code is up and running, underwhelming though it might be, with the body in the middle of the page.
代码已经启动并运行了，虽然可能很乏味，页面中间是 body。
And let me zoom in up here, too.
让我把这里也放大。
Hello, comma, title is indeed in the tab, just as promised.
正如承诺的那样，Hello，逗号，标题确实出现在标签页中了。
So what's actually going on with code like this that we just created?
那么，我们刚刚创建的这样的代码究竟是怎么回事呢？
Well, let's go back to the slide version of the same.
让我们回到幻灯片版本的代码。
And let me just highlight a few of these lines.
让我来突出显示其中的一些行。
The very first line is what's called your document type declaration.
第一行是所谓的文档类型声明。
Doesn't really matter to remember that by phrasing.
记住这个短语并不重要。
And this is just something you copy, paste, or do from memory at the top of any .html file that you create when making your own web page.
这只需要你复制、粘贴，或者根据记忆在创建网页时创建的任何 .html 文件的顶部输入。
It's a implicit indicator to the browser that you're using the very latest version of HTML, which is version 5.
它是浏览器的一个隐式指示符，表明你正在使用最新版本的 HTML，即版本 5。
You don't mention the number 5.
你不需要提及数字 5。
Just browsers nowadays are programmed to look for this to know that you're using the very latest version of the language.
只是现在的浏览器都被编程为查找这个，以了解你正在使用该语言的最新版本。
Languages, just like human languages, evolve over time.
语言就像人类语言一样，随着时间的推移而发展。
We're up to version 5 of HTML. But new features get added every few years.
我们现在使用的是 HTML 版本 5，但每隔几年就会添加新功能。
So indeed, this lecture, this class, has been evolving over time, too.
这节课，这门课，也一直在发展。
So let's now focus on the next line, as well as the bottom line.
现在让我们关注下一行以及最后一行。
And you'll notice some deliberate symmetry here.
你会注意到这里刻意设计的对称性。
This here is what we're going to call a tag.
这个叫做标签。
And it's technically different from this.
它在技术上与这个不同。
This is a document type declaration.
这是一个文档类型声明。
It's got the weird exclamation point.
它有一个奇怪的感叹号。
That's the only anomaly.
这是唯一的异常。
Everything else follows a pattern.
其他所有内容都遵循一个模式。
This is a tag in HTML, and it's the HTML tag.
这是一个 HTML 标签，它是 HTML 标签。
And a tag generally both starts and stops, or opens and closes at some point.
标签通常在某个点开始和停止，或者打开和关闭。
So this is the so-called start tag or open tag.
这就是所谓的开始标签或打开标签。
And this just means essentially to the browser, hey, browser, here comes some HTML, the language in which web pages are written.
这实际上是对浏览器说，浏览器，这里有一些 HTML，网页是用这种语言编写的。
This here, with the forward slash after the angled bracket,
这个在尖括号后面有一个斜杠，
Means, hey, browser, that's it for the HTML of this page. So that's what I mean by symmetry.
意味着，浏览器，这就是页面的 HTML 内容。这就是我对称性的意思。
I started a thought here, finished it down here.
我在这里开始了一个想法，在这里结束。
What's in between those two thoughts?
这两个想法之间是什么？
Well, here, browser, or rather, let me clarify one thing.
在这里，浏览器，或者让我澄清一件事。
This thing here is that other keyword, an attribute.
这里的这个东西是另一个关键字，一个属性。
An attribute is something that modifies the behavior of a tag.
属性是修改标签行为的东西。
So it's similar to an argument in C or in Python, like a parameter to a function.
它类似于 C 语言或 Python 中的参数，就像函数的参数一样。
These aren't functions, but it's the same idea.
这些不是函数，但意思相同。
It just modifies the default behavior of something instead.
它只是修改了默认行为。
Lang equals en, you can probably guess, just means that, hey, browser.
lang= en，你可能已经猜到了，意思是浏览器。
Assume that everything hereafter is in English.
假设后面的所有内容都是英文的。
And that might be used for Google Translate or just search engine optimization so that just the server, the browser, know what human language you have actual content in, like hello, title, hello, body, even though a good computer can probably infer from context often.
这可能用于谷歌翻译或搜索引擎优化，以便服务器和浏览器知道你实际内容使用的是哪种人类语言，
比如 hello、title、hello、body，即使一台好的计算机可能经常可以从上下文中推断出来。
All right, so that's an attribute.
这是一个属性。
That's a tag.
这是一个标签。
And the whole thing here, everything in between the start tag and end tag, we would also call an HTML element.
这里的所有内容，开始标签和结束标签之间的所有内容，我们也称为 HTML 元素。
That just means everything related to that
这意味着所有与之相关的内容。
Open and close tag.
打开和关闭标签。
All right, now notice, indented inside of, so to speak, the HTML open and close tag are another pair of tags, the head tag and the body tag, or the head element collectively and the body element collectively.
现在注意，在 HTML 打开和关闭标签内部缩进的是另一对标签，head 标签和 body 标签，或者统称为 head 元素和 body 元素。
And same idea.
同样的道理。
Hey, browser, here comes the head of my page.
浏览器，这是我页面的头部。
Hey, browser, that's it for the head.
嘿，浏览器，这就是 head 部分的内容。
Hey, browser, here comes the body of my page.
嘿，浏览器，接下来是我的网页的 body 部分。
Hey, browser, that's it for the body.
嘿，浏览器，这就是 body 部分的内容。
The head is essentially the tiny little strip at the very top, including the tab itself.
head 基本上就是最顶部的窄条，包括选项卡本身。
The body is like 95% of everything else, the big rectangular region.
body 就好像其他所有内容的 95%，那个大的矩形区域。
What's inside of your title, of your head, of the web page?
你的网页的 title、head 里面有什么？
At the moment, just the title.
目前，只有标题。
So this indicates, hey, browser, here comes my title.
所以这表示，嘿，浏览器，这是我的标题。
Hey, browser, that's it for the title.
嘿，浏览器，标题到此结束。
The title, of course, is literally, quote unquote, hello, comma, title.
当然，标题的内容就是，引号，hello，逗号，title，引号。
Meanwhile, if we bounce back out, here is the, Second element inside of the HTML tag, this says, hey, browser, here comes the body.
同时，如果我们跳回去，这是 HTML 标签内的第二个元素，它表示，嘿，浏览器，这是 body 部分。
Hey, browser, that's it for the body.
嘿，浏览器，body 部分到此结束。
And hey, browser, this is the contents.
还有，嘿，浏览器，这是内容。
These are the contents of the body itself.
这些是 body 本身的内容。
Now, the indentation is a stylistic thing.
现在，缩进是一种格式上的事情。
I did it just to be sort of neat and tidy, because it suggests what is inside of what.
我这样做只是为了整洁有序，因为它暗示了什么在什么的内部。
But it also suggests a sort of hierarchy.
但它也暗示了一种层次结构。
And in fact, we'll use terminology from the world of family trees.
事实上，我们将使用来自家谱世界的术语。
If this is like a parent, so to speak, Head and body would be the child elements of the HTML tag.
如果这像是一个父级， 那么 head 和 body 将是 HTML 标签的子元素。
Meanwhile, title is a child of the head tag, or equivalently, title is a grandchild of HTML.
同时，title 是 head 标签的子元素，或者说，title 是 HTML 的孙元素。
So you can use the same sort of vernacular as in the human world when it comes to familial relationships, too.
你也可以使用人类世界中相同的家族关系来描述它们。
And that just hints at, again, the same hierarchy.
这再次暗示了相同的层级结构。
So we have tags, and they include HTML, head, title, body.
我们有标签，它们包括 html、head、title、body。
And that's it for now.
目前就这些。
We have attributes.
我们有属性。
We've seen one example of them, lang.
我们已经见过一个例子，lang。
But we'll see many other examples of the same idea.
但我们会看到许多相同概念的其他例子。
But these building blocks are exactly the same.
但这些构建块完全相同。
Generally, you start a thought, you finish a thought, and you might do something in between.
通常，你开始一个想法，你结束一个想法，你可能在两者之间做一些事情。
Questions on this basic structure of any web page?
关于任何网页的这种基本结构，有问题吗？
Any questions at all?
有任何问题吗？
All right, so let's now allow things to ramp up a little more interestingly and do something with these building blocks.
现在让我们来点更有趣的东西，用这些构建块做点什么。
But so that you have a mental model for everything that's going on here on after, think of this same HTML being related in spirit to week five when we talked all about data structures.
为了让你对接下来发生的一切有一个心理模型，可以把这个 HTML 和第五周我们讨论数据结构时的精神联系起来。
If I really wanted to, I could take to heart this idea of children and parents and grandparents and really depict this thing graphically.
如果我真的想，我可以认真对待孩子、父母和祖父母的概念，并以图形的方式来描述它。
And in fact, this tree here, if you will,
事实上，这棵树，如果你愿意的话，
And it's not a binary tree.
它不是二叉树。
It's not a binary search tree.
它不是二叉搜索树。
It's just a tree using Week 5's terminology.
它只是一棵使用第五周术语的树。
If this special node here represents the whole document, well, the root element, as I called it, is HTML.
如果这个特殊的节点代表整个文档，那么，我称之为根元素的元素就是 HTML。
HTML has two children, head and body.
HTML 有两个子元素，head 和 body。
The head tag has, in turn, a title child and, in turn, has some text, just as the body has some text.
head 标签里又有一个 title 子元素，title 里面是一些文本，就像 body 里面也有一些文本一样。
And so this is what your browser is doing.
这就是浏览器正在做的事情。
You and I, the programmers, write this stuff.
作为程序员，你我写的是这些东西。
The browser reads this code, top to bottom, left to right, whenever you visit a website.
当你访问一个网站时，浏览器会从上到下，从左到右地读取这些代码。
And inside of the computer's memory, Chrome, Edge, Firefox, Safari, whatnot, they build this data structure in the computer's memory so as to know what it is you have told them to do.
在计算机内存中，Chrome、Edge、Firefox、Safari 等等，它们会在计算机内存中构建这种数据结构，以便知道你指示它们做什么。
And we'll see over time, at the end of today, you can write code in an actual programming language, JavaScript, to maybe dynamically add or remove things from this tree.
我们稍后会看到，在今天结束的时候，你可以使用一种实际的编程语言 JavaScript 编写代码，来动态地向这棵树添加或删除元素。
And this is how things like Gmail work.
Gmail 就是这样运作的。
When you open up your Gmail inbox, if you're a Gmail user,
如果你是一个 Gmail 用户，当你打开你的 Gmail 收件箱时，
If you just stay there long enough, you'll probably get more and more mail.
只要你停留在那里的时间足够长，你可能会收到越来越多的邮件。
And what happens? You don't have to reload the page or rebuild the tree, per se.
然后会发生什么？ 你不需要重新加载页面或重建这棵树。
It just all of a sudden appears at the top, at the top, at the top.
它只是突然出现在顶部，顶部，顶部。
What's happening there is that Google wrote some code that just keeps adding more nodes to this tree every time they realize you've got a new message again and again.
发生的事情是，Google 编写了一些代码，每次他们意识到你有一条新消息时，就会向这棵树添加更多的节点，一次又一次。
So that's the relationship now, even with this world of HTML, with all of the programmatic ideas we looked at. In the past.
所以这就是现在 HTML 的关系，以及我们之前看过的所有编程思想。
All right, so let's go ahead and do something with this that's a little more interesting than just hello itself.
让我们继续，用它来做一些比简单的 hello 本身更有趣的事情。
I'm going to go ahead and hide my terminal window, because the server is now running.
我要隐藏我的终端窗口，因为服务器现在正在运行。
And all I want to do now is experiment with hello and other examples as well.
我现在要做的就是用 hello 和其他例子做实验。
Let me go ahead and, actually, before I do that,
让我继续，实际上，在我这样做之前，
Let me go ahead and run a code of paragraphs.html just so I can keep my code separate.
让我先运行一段 paragraphs.html 的代码，这样我就可以保持代码分离。
And now I'll hide the terminal window again.
现在我将再次隐藏终端窗口。
Paragraphs.html, I'm going to do almost exactly the same.
Paragraphs.html，我几乎会做完全相同的事情。
Let me go ahead and start with something familiar.
我先从一些熟悉的内容开始。
And eventually, I'll start copying and pasting just to save time.
最终，为了节省时间，我会开始复制粘贴。
So doc type html is always there.
所以 <!DOCTYPE html> 始终存在。
Open the html tag.
打开 <html> 标签。
And now notice, I didn't type the rest of that.
现在注意，我没有输入剩下的内容。
Just like with C, just like with Python, we try to save you some keystrokes by closing parentheses, adding quotes.
就像使用 C 语言和 Python 一样，我们尝试通过自动添加结束括号和引号来帮助减少按键次数。
The HTML support in VS Code is pretty good, too.
VS Code 中的 HTML 支持也非常好。
And it tries to finish your thought when it comes to tags as well.
当涉及到标签时，它也会尝试完成你的想法。
It can screw things up if it does something you don't want it to do. So sometimes you have to delete. But it's just autocomplete, as we've seen before.
如果它做了你不希望它做的事情，它可能会把事情搞砸。所以有时你必须删除。但这只是自动完成，就像我们之前看到的那样。
Let's go ahead and let me add lang equals en, as all of my examples today will be.
我们继续，让我添加 lang = en，我今天所有的例子都将是这样。
Let's add the head tag.
添加 <head> 标签。
Let's go and proactively add the body tag.
我们继续并主动添加 <boby> 标签。
And now let's go ahead and give this a title tag, which has a, I'll just call this paragraphs, just so I remember which example is what.
现在，我们继续给它一个 <title> 标签，我将称之为 paragraphs，这样我就能记住哪个例子是什么了。
Now, notice all of this white space and all of this neat and tidy indentation, the browser ultimately is not going to care about.
现在，注意所有这些空白和所有这些整齐的缩进，浏览器最终不会关心这些。
This is just for us humans to kind of keep ourselves sane when we look at the code.
这只是为了让我们人类在查看代码时保持清醒。
It's just easier to read.
这样更容易阅读。
But strictly speaking, I could minimally delete all of this whitespace.
但严格来说，我可以最小限度地删除所有这些空格。
And I could just move all of this tag up to the same line.
我可以把所有这些标签都移到同一行。
Both, I think, are fine.
我认为两者都很好。
I'm just going to follow a certain convention.
我打算遵循一种特定的惯例。
But this, too, would have the exact same meaning.
但这也具有完全相同的含义。
But we'll see where that detail about whitespace could potentially get us into trouble later.
但我们稍后会看到有关空格的细节可能会给我们带来麻烦。
In my paragraphs tag, let's do this.
在我的段落标签中，我们这样做。
In advance, I've written up some Latin-like text, a really long paragraph of Latin-like text like this.
我提前写了一些类似拉丁语的文本，像这样很长一段类似拉丁语的文本。
It's actually random nonsense.
这实际上是随机的废话。
It's not real Latin, even though a couple of the words might look familiar. And so here we have three paragraphs of text.
它不是真正的拉丁语，即使其中几个单词可能看起来很熟悉。所以这里我们有三段文字。
And I've deliberately hit Enter in between them so that, just like an essay in Google Docs or Microsoft Word, hopefully I'll see three separate paragraphs.
我特意在它们之间按了回车键，这样，就像在 Google Docs 或 Microsoft Word 中的文章一样，希望我会看到三个独立的段落。
Let me now change tabs, and I'll close hello.html from before.
现在让我切换标签页，我将关闭之前的 hello.html。
I'm going to go back to my other tab here.
我要回到我的另一个标签页。
I'm going to click Back to go back to that index of all of my files, which I started at earlier.
我要点击“返回”以返回到我之前开始的所有文件的索引。
And you'll see now that I have two files, because I obviously just created a second file called paragraphs.html.
你会看到我现在有两个文件，因为我显然刚刚创建了第二个名为 paragraphs.html 的文件。
So let's click on this to see our three paragraphs of Latin-like text.
所以让我们点击这个来查看我们的三段类似拉丁语的文本。
And voila, I'll zoom out.
瞧，我会缩小。
All right, first bug, if you will.
第一个错误，如果你愿意这样说的话。
This just looks like one massive blob of text, not three blobs of text.
这看起来只是一大块文本，而不是三块文本。
And why might that be?
这可能是什么原因呢？
Borrowing the hint I offered a moment ago.
借用我刚才提供的提示。
Why are we not seeing break?
为什么我们没有看到换行？
Yeah, so we need some kind of line breaks here, because the browser, turns out, is only going to take us literally.
是的，所以我们需要在这里进行某种换行，因为事实证明，浏览器只会从字面上理解我们。
And if you just give it text, text, text, it's just going to show you text.
如果你只输入文本，文本，文本，它只会显示文本。
And any time there's more than a single white space, whether it's 2, or 20, or 200, it's going to just assume that you did that just to be neat and tidy.
任何时候只要有多个空格，无论是 2 个、20 个还是 200 个，它都会认为你这样做只是为了整洁。
And it's going to collapse them into just one space visually, like this.
它会在视觉上将它们折叠成一个空格，像这样。
So there are, in fact, a couple of solutions.
所以实际上有几种解决方案。
One is this here.
一种是这样的。
I could add some explicit line breaks.
我可以添加一些显式的换行符。
And it turns out. that there's a br tag like this.
事实证明，有一个像这样的 br 标签。
And just for visibility's sake, let me do two of them.
为了便于查看，让我用两个。
So like hitting Enter, Enter on my keyboard.
就像敲击键盘上的 Enter，Enter。
I'll do it here too, br for break, break.
我在这里也这样做， <br>  代表换行，换行。
And now let me go back to my other tab.
现在让我回到另一个标签页。
Nothing's changed yet, but that's because I have to reload.
还没有变化，但那是因为我必须重新加载。
I've changed it on the server, but now I need to change it in the browser by reloading.
我已经在服务器上更改了它，但现在我需要通过重新加载在浏览器中更改它。
And now it looks a little better, albeit nonsensical.
现在看起来好多了，尽管毫无意义。
But you'll notice a curiosity.
但你会注意到一个奇怪的地方。
Per this br tag, this is kind of poorly designed.
根据这个 <br> 标签，这种设计很糟糕。
It's a little hackish to just say, enter, enter, and make the browser do this.
仅仅说回车，回车，然后让浏览器这样做，有点像是在耍花招。
Breaks, line breaks, don't actually require close tags or end tags.
换行符，实际上不需要结束标签。
So not all tags need to be closed, at least those that it just makes no semantic sense to close them, right?
所以并不是所有标签都需要闭合，至少那些在语义上不需要闭合的标签，对吧？
Like the break is there or it's not.
比如换行符，要么有，要么没有。
You can't imagine starting to move to the next line and then eventually getting around to finishing.
你无法想象开始移动到下一行，然后最终绕回来完成它。
It's either there or it's not.
它要么在那里，要么不在。
So some tags do not have closed tags, as necessary.
所以有些标签不需要闭合标签。
But there's a more elegant way here, I dare say, not just sort of hackishly putting in these line breaks.
但我敢说，这里有一种更优雅的方式，而不仅仅是强行插入这些换行符。
Let me do this instead.
让我这样做。
I'll delete those.
我要删除这些。
And let me go ahead and, as the name of this file suggests, let me add a paragraph tag.
让我继续，顾名思义，让我添加一个 <p> 标签。
Now, here I need to fight with VS Code's autocomplete, because I don't want to finish the thought there.
现在，我需要和 VS Code 的自动完成功能作斗争，因为我不想在那里完成输入。
Let me go ahead and open the paragraph tag and close a paragraph tag.
让我继续打开 <p> 标签并关闭它。
And just to keep things tidy, I'll go ahead and indent to, even though the indentation itself doesn't matter.
为了保持整洁，即使缩进本身无关紧要，我也会继续缩进。
Let me go ahead and create another tag for opening this paragraph.
让我继续创建另一个标签来打开这个段落。
And I'll close this one here.
我会在这里关闭这个。
And now let me see.
现在让我看看。
Sometimes it's fighting with my autocomplete.
有时它会和我的自动完成功能冲突。
But that's fine, because I did this sort of the wrong way at first.
但这没关系，因为我一开始就做错了。
And now let me go ahead and finish this thought by closing this paragraph tag here.
现在，让我继续在这里关闭这个 </p> 标签来完成这个想法。
And I've manually fixed all of my indentations.
我已经手动修复了所有的缩进。
So now on line 10, I have the equivalent of, hey, browser, start a paragraph.
所以在第 10 行，我相当于告诉浏览器，开始一个段落。
And then it does the Latin-like text.
然后它会显示类似拉丁语的文本。
Then on line 12, hey, browser, that's it for this paragraph.
然后在第 12 行，告诉浏览器，这个段落结束了。
And repeat, repeat.
重复，重复。
If I now go back to my other tab.
如果我现在回到另一个标签页。
And reload again shouldn't be all that different.
再次刷新，应该没什么不同。
But semantically, it's a little bit better.
但在语义上，它要好一些。
Why?
为什么？
Because just saying break break doesn't really mean anything.
因为只说 break break 并没有什么意义。
But by saying paragraph, paragraph, paragraph, now there's some more semantic information there.
但如果说 paragraph，paragraph，paragraph，现在就有了更多语义信息。
Now if Google is analyzing your page, or if the programmer is trying to understand what it is you did in the past when writing this code,
如果 Google 正在分析你的页面，或者程序员试图理解你在过去编写这段代码时做了什么，
You just know semantically, oh, this is a paragraph, this is a paragraph, this is a paragraph, just like in a book or an essay.
你就能从语义上知道，这是一个段落，这是一个段落，这是一个段落，就像在一本书或一篇文章中一样。
So it's a little more clear, focusing more on what it is, not how you want to display it.
所以它更清晰，更注重内容是什么，而不是你想如何显示它。
Any questions, then, on these paragraphs?
关于这些段落，还有什么问题吗？
Now, all right, so a few more tags.
现在，还有一些标签。
And indeed, these first few examples will really just be like sort of bang, bang, bang, just a bunch of different vocabulary words in the form of these new tags.
事实上，前面几个例子就像是一连串的“砰，砰，砰”，只是一堆以新标签形式出现的词汇。
But we won't go through the entire laundry list of tags.
但我们不会把所有的标签都过一遍。
This is indeed the thing for which web references and books and the like are ultimately helpful, just like a dictionary in the real world.
这就像现实世界中的字典一样，网络参考、书籍等最终都是有用的。
So I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我要继续做了。
Let me go ahead and copy this.
让我把它复制一下。
Let me create a new file called headings.html, just so we have a new file for this.
让我创建一个名为 headings.html 的新文件，以便为此准备一个新文件。
To save time, I'm just going to paste that exact same code just to get me started.
为了节省时间，我直接粘贴相同的代码来开始。
I'm going to change the title of it for clarity for the code online to Headings.
为了代码在线上的清晰度，我将把它的标题改为 Headings。
And now, just like a book or an essay or a thesis, let me actually put some actual headings here.
就像写书、写文章或论文一样，我们现在来添加一些标题。
Now, if my first heading, like Chapter 1, I could do something like this up here.
如果这是我的第一个标题，比如第一章，我可以像这样在上面添加。
I could have a paragraph, like I just learned.
我可以像刚学过的那样，添加一个段落。
And I could say something like Chapter 1 here.
然后在这里写上“第一章”。
But that's not really a paragraph.
但这并不是真正的段落。
And so it's sort of better designed to tell the browser and really tell the world what it is.
所以最好使用更合适的标签来告诉浏览器以及全世界它是什么。
So it turns out there's another tag I can use, like h1, for heading and most important heading.
事实证明，我可以使用另一个标签，比如 h1，表示标题，而且是最重要的标题。
And in here, I'm just going to keep it simple, and I'm going to say something like 1.
在这里，为了简单起见，我只写个“One”。
And in fact, this is so short, here's a good candidate for just keeping this all on the same line.
事实上，这行代码很短，可以把它们都放在同一行。
But this has no functional difference, but it'll just make it a little more terse on the screen.
这没有任何功能上的区别，只是让屏幕上的代码更简洁一些。
Now let me go ahead down here.
现在我们继续往下看。
And I could have multiple headings, so H1, 2.
我可以有多个标题，比如 h1，Two。
And down here, I could have another one, H1, 3.
在这里，我可以再写一个，h1，Three。
And if I go back to my other tab, I reload it.
如果我回到另一个标签页，重新加载它。
Now we should see, just like a book or an essay, now we have some proper.
现在，就像一本书或一篇文章一样，我们应该能看到一些合适的标题了。
Now we have some, oops, I have to go to the right file, sorry.
现在我们有一些... 抱歉，我得打开正确的文件。
If I go back to the index, now we see the new third file called headings.html.
如果我回到 index.html，现在我们可以看到名为 headings.html 的新文件。
And now we indeed see some fairly pretty, if simple, headings as well.
现在我们确实看到了一些相当漂亮、简洁的标题。
Now, if these aren't three chapters, 1, 2, 3, but maybe it's a chapter, then a section, then a subsection, such that just visually you want things to get smaller and smaller, well, those exist too.
假设这些不是三个章节，1、2、3，而是一个章节，然后是一个小节，再然后是一个子小节，你想让它们在视觉上越来越小，其实也有这样的标签。
And in fact, you can do h1 through h6.
实际上，你可以使用从 h1 到 h6 的标签。
h1, a little paradoxically, is the biggest and boldest.
h1 有点矛盾，是最大最粗的。
h6 is the smallest, but still bold.
h6 最小，但仍然是粗体。
So it might make sense to make this h2 both open and close, and maybe this h3 open and close if, again, this is a section or a subsection inside of that chapter.
把这个 h2 作为开始和结束标签可能是有意义的，如果这是一个章节中的一部分或小节，那么 h3 也作为开始和结束标签。
If I reload now, notice it just gets a little smaller.
如果我现在重新加载，你会发现它只是变小了一点。
So it's more similar to what you'd see on the printed page.
所以它更类似于你在打印页面上看到的内容。
But this now is just another three tags that I might use in my own code.
但这现在只是我可能在我自己的代码中使用的另外三个标签。
All right, well, how about lists of things?
那么，事物列表呢？
I have three paragraphs here, but let's do this.
这里有三个段落，但是让我们这样做。
Let me go back to VS Code.
让我回到 VS Code。
I'm going to copy this code so I have a starting point.
我要复制这段代码，这样我就有了一个起点。
I'm going to create a new file called, say, list.html.
我要创建一个名为 list.html 的新文件。
Here, I'm going to copy-paste.
在这里，我要复制粘贴。
I'm going to change my title to be List, just for clarity.
为了清楚起见，我要把标题改为 List。
And in here, I'm going to go ahead and get rid of this whole body, because let's move away from these massive paragraphs and keep it simpler for now.
在这里，我要继续删除整个 body，因为让我们暂时放弃这些大段落，保持简单。
If I want to have a list of things, for instance, if you haven't seen these already, a computer scientist, when they're fishing for just some arbitrary, meaningless words,
例如，如果你还没有见过这些，一个计算机科学家在寻找一些任意的、毫无意义的词时，
They often use foo, bar, and baz, just as their go-to.
他们经常使用 foo、bar 和 baz 作为他们的首选。
Just like a mathematician might use x, y, z for variables.
就像数学家可能会用 x、y、z 来表示变量一样。
So foo, bar, and baz are on three separate lines.
所以 foo、bar 和 baz 分别在三行中。
And maybe this is like my to-do list or my shopping list.
也许这就像我的待办事项清单或购物清单。
But you can probably imagine if I go back to my other tab, go back to the index, I now see my new file, list.html.
但你可以想象，如果我回到另一个标签页，回到 index，我现在看到了我的新文件 list.html。
But it's probably going to look wrong.
但这看起来可能不太对。
I think I'm just going to say, yeah, foo bar baz, all in one breath, if you will, not on new lines.
我觉得我会直接说，foo、bar、baz，一口气说完，而不是分行显示。
And you can try to fight this.
你可以尝试解决这个问题。
You can be like, I really want to put some line breaks there, go back and reload.
你可能会想，我真的想在那里加一些换行符，然后返回并重新加载。
It's still not going to make any change.
但这并不会有任何改变。
How do I want to fix this? Well, I can do this in a few ways.
我想怎么解决这个问题呢？ 好吧，我可以通过几种方法来做到这一点。
I could make them paragraphs. But they're not really paragraphs. They're a list.
我可以把它们做成段落。 但它们并不是真正的段落。 它们是一个列表。
So I'm going to use a different tag instead.
所以我打算用一个不同的标签来代替。
I'm going to create, for instance, an unordered list using the ul tag, open and close.
例如，我要创建一个无序列表，使用 ul 标签，打开和关闭。
Inside of that, I'm going to use the list item tag, li, and I'm going to say foo.
在里面，我要使用列表项标签 li，然后输入 foo。
Inside of another tag, I'm going to say bar.
在另一个标签内，输入 bar。
Inside of a third tag, open and close, I'm going to say baz.
在第三个标签内，打开和关闭，输入 baz。
So it's getting a little verbose, but it's still relatively succinct.
所以它变得有点冗长，但仍然相对简洁。
Li is all you need type for list item.
li 就是列表项的缩写。
Ul is all you need type for unordered list.
ul 就是无序列表的缩写。
So there's some shorthand syntax here that's adopted.
所以这里采用了一些简写语法。
If I now reload, you're going to see a so-called unordered list, like not sorted, which means by convention to show it as bullets, though it could be displayed in different ways visually as well.
如果我现在重新加载，你将看到一个所谓的无序列表，就像没有排序一样，
这意味着按照惯例将其显示为项目符号，尽管它也可以以不同的方式进行视觉显示。
If you actually change your mind and you realize, oh, I'd really like to number this, well, you could obviously just add one, And 2 and 3. But that's going to get annoying, especially if the list grows.
如果你真的改变了主意，并且意识到，我真的想给它编号，那么你显然可以只添加 1、2 和 3。 但这会变得很烦人，特别是当列表很长的时候。
You want to change something, insert something in the middle, then you have to reorder it.
你想更改一些内容，在中间插入一些内容，然后你必须重新排序。
I mean, we're using computers here.
我的意思是，我们在这里使用的是计算机。
They can do this for us.
它们可以帮我们做到这一点。
So we can change the ul, too. Any guesses?
所以我们也可以改变 ul，猜猜是什么？
OL, maybe, for ordered list, which is sort of the opposite here.
可能是 ol，代表有序列表，这里有点相反。
So let's try changing that to OL.
我们试试把它改成 ol。
Let me go back to my browser.
让我回到浏览器。
And I'm just hitting Command-R or Control-R to reload the page instead of clicking the button every time.
我只需按下 Command-R 或 Control-R 即可重新加载页面，而不用每次都点击按钮。
Now I automatically get 1, 2, and 3.
现在我自动获得了 1、2 和 3。
And you can even override the aesthetics using different numerables or symbology instead.
你甚至可以使用不同的数字或符号来覆盖美学效果。
But that would be perhaps the most common there as well.
但这可能也是最常见的。
All right, it's a lot of tags quickly, but any questions on lists, paragraphs, headings, or the like?
很快就有很多标签了，但关于列表、段落、标题等还有什么问题吗？
All right, so let me go ahead and propose this here.
让我继续，在这里提出这个建议。
Let's go ahead and create what we'll call a table.
我们来创建一个我们称之为表格的东西。
So let me copy and paste this into a new file, code of table.html.
让我把它复制粘贴到一个新文件 table.html 中。
And in table.html, let me again rename the title to table.
在 table.html 中，让我再次将标题重命名为 table。
Let me get rid of that ordered list from before.
让我摆脱之前的有序列表。
And let me now use a table tag, open and close.
现在让我使用 table 标签，打开和关闭。
This one's a little weird, but inside of a table, you typically have a head of the table.
这有点奇怪，但在 table 中，通常会有一个表头。
I'll say, well, let's say the first row.
我会说，假设是第一行。
We'll keep this one simple.
我们先从简单的开始。
A table row, or TR.
一个表格行，或者说是 TR。
Inside of a table row, you would ideally have columns.
在表格行内部，你理想情况下会放一些列。
But that's not the nomenclature.
但这不是专业术语。
Instead, you have data.
相反，你拥有的是数据。
So TD for table data.
所以 td 代表表格数据。
And let me go ahead and just have the first datum be 1.
我先把第一个数据设为 1。
I'm just going to arbitrarily do 1, 2, 3, just so we have something to play with.
我随意地设置为 1、2、3，这样我们就有东西可以操作了。
And you know what? Just for demonstration's sake, I am going to deliberately copy paste this twice.
为了演示，我打算故意复制粘贴两次。
And I'm just going to manually change the numbers, just so we can see what I'm creating. 789.
我要手动更改数字，以便我们能看到我创建的内容。7 8 9。
And then maybe just for good measure, if you're seeing where this is going, let me copy this one more time and give myself a final row with an asterisk, a 0, and a pound sign, if maybe you see where this is going.
为了更好地演示，如果你明白我要做什么，我再复制一次，最后一行的内容是星号、0 和井号，你应该能猜到我要做什么。
Let me go back to my other tab.
我回到另一个标签页。
Let me go back to the index.
回到 index 页面。
There's my new file, table.html.
这是我的新文件 table.html。
I'll click that.
我点击它。
And while it's not very pretty, I'll zoom in.
虽然它看起来不怎么样，我放大一下。
It's indeed a table of data.
它确实是一个数据表。
I happen to mimic a telephone keypad.
我碰巧模仿了一个电话键盘。
But you could imagine this being much juicier, much more interesting scientific or financial data or the like laid out into these rows, TRs, and these columns, a.k.a. table data as well.
但你可以想象，这可能会是更丰富、更有趣的科学或金融数据等等，它们被排列在这些行（TR）和列（也就是表格数据）中。
So we have that ability as well for structured data.
所以我们也有能力处理结构化数据。
Now, of course, the internet has lots of images on it.
当然，互联网上有许多图片。
And in fact, this is all just text.
事实上，这些都只是文本。
How can we introduce images?
我们如何引入图像？
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
我来演示一下。
Let me first. Sort of semi-secretly copy an image file that I brought from earlier just so we have something to play with.
首先， 我偷偷地复制了一个之前准备好的图像文件，这样我们就有东西可以操作了。
And I have in my account here now an image called harvard.jpeg.
现在我的账户里有一张叫做 harvard.jpeg 的图片。
And I uploaded this semi-secretly a second ago into my account so that I can reference a second file.
我刚刚偷偷地把它上传到我的账户，这样我就可以引用第二个文件了。
Let me go ahead and copy this HTML just to save myself some keystrokes.
让我复制这段 HTML 代码，以节省一些打字时间。
Let me go ahead and do code of image.html.
让我创建一个名为 image.html 的文件。
And let me paste that code and hide my terminal window.
让我粘贴代码并隐藏终端窗口。
I'm going to get rid of all of this table as just uninteresting now.
我要把整个表格都删掉，因为它现在已经不重要了。
We're going to make this even simpler by changing my title to Image to keep all these demonstrations separate.
为了区分演示，我们把标题改成 Image，让它更简洁一些。
And now, if I want to make a web page that, when visited, shows us a picture of Harvard, well, there's an image tag, abbreviated IMG for short.
现在，如果我想创建一个网页，当访问时，会显示一张哈佛的图片，可以使用 image 标签，简写为 IMG。
I can specify what the source of that image is.
我可以指定图像的来源。
And if my file, a JPEG in this case, is literally in the same folder, I can just say, quote unquote, harvard.jpeg.
如果我的文件，在这个例子中是一个 JPEG 文件，与 HTML 文件在同一个文件夹中，我就可以直接写上 "harvard.jpeg"。
If it's in a folder, I should mention the folder name in a slash or something like that.
如果在文件夹中，我应该用斜杠或类似的方式指明文件夹名称。
If the image is on the internet somewhere with a URL, I could also have a whole URL, HTTPS colon slash slash, and then the URL of the image. But I upload it in advance.
如果图像在互联网上的某个地方，我可以使用完整的 URL，https ://，然后是图像的 URL。但我提前上传了。
Now, this is just going to visually display on the screen.
现在，这只是在屏幕上显示图像。
But not everyone, of course, can see images.
但并不是每个人都能看到图像。
Screen readers might need a bit of assistance.
屏幕阅读器可能需要一些帮助。
And even search engines might want to analyze the page and know what this is an image of.
甚至搜索引擎也可能想要分析页面，并知道这是一张什么图片。
Now, machine learning and artificial intelligence are maybe getting better, to be fair, at figuring out.
机器学习和人工智能现在可能在识别图像方面做得更好了。
just by analyzing images what they are. But they're certainly imperfect.
但它们还不完美。
I am a human. I know pretty well what I took a photo of, for instance.
我是一个人，我很清楚自己拍的是什么照片。
So maybe what I should do proactively, which would be good for accessibility, is have this alt tag for alternative text, and then literally say, like, Harvard University, so that someone who can't see or so that a server can actually know with higher probability what it is they're looking at.
所以也许我应该主动做一些事情，这对可访问性很有帮助，
比如添加这个 `alt` 标签来替代文本，然后写上“哈佛大学”，这样看不见的人或服务器就能以更高的概率知道他们在看什么。
And I could be even more detailed than just a phrase. I could describe the image as well.
我甚至可以提供比短语更详细的描述。
All right, let me go back to my index in the second tab.
好，让我回到第二个标签页的 `index.html`。
Let me go back and zoom back out.
让我回去，缩小一点。
There's my new file, and there's my new JPEG that I quickly uploaded before.
这是我的新文件，这是我之前快速上传的新 JPEG 图片。
I can click now on image.html, and albeit a little overwhelming, that is a really big image of Harvard.
我现在可以点击 `image.html`，虽然有点夸张，但这是一张非常大的哈佛大学的照片。
Now, apparently, it's too big to fit on the screen, so this isn't the best
很明显，它太大了，屏幕都放不下，所以这不是最好的
user experience to have to scroll up.
用户体验，必须向上滚动才能看到全部。
OK, so there's the image.
这就是那张图片。
Horrible, horrible design, if you will, at least in terms of my code.
至少从我的代码来看，这是一个非常糟糕的设计。
But there's going to be ways where I can sort of rein that in and affect the height or the width as well.
但我有一些方法可以控制它，比如调整高度或宽度。
But for now, it's just deliberately a little overwhelming instead.
但现在，我故意让它有点夸张。
Now, we can do something a little more fun and topical today.
现在，我们可以做一些更有趣、更应景的事情。
Which might be to use a video instead.
比如使用视频。
So let me go ahead here and very quickly grab another file today, which I brought in advance and that you might have seen briefly earlier, which is an MP4, an actual video file.
让我快速地获取另一个文件，我提前准备好了，你可能之前也看到了，它是一个 MP4 文件，一个视频文件。
And what I'm going to do here, by revealing VS Code again, is I'm going to code a file called video.html.
我将在这里打开 VS Code，创建一个名为 `video.html` 的文件。
Yet another demonstration here.
这是另一个演示。
I'm going to change my title to video, just to keep these things straight.
为了区分文件类型，我把标题改成了 video。
And instead of the image tag, you might imagine using now, indeed, a video tag.
你可以想象一下，现在要用 video 标签来代替 image 标签。
And this is a relatively newer tag that has increasing support among browsers, so it's good now to use.
这是一个相对较新的标签，浏览器对它的支持度越来越高，所以现在用它很合适。
And inside of this, the syntax is a little different.
它的语法略有不同。
You specify, and this is weirdly, annoyingly inconsistent, not SRC for source.
奇怪的是，它不使用 src 作为 source 属性，这让人很恼火，前后不一致。
You literally say source.
你得直接写 source。
And then in source, you use a source attribute.
然后在 src 中使用 source 属性。
Horrible design, semantically. But this is what we're stuck with.
从语义上来说，这个设计太糟糕了，但我们只能这样用。
Halloween.mp4 is the name of the video we upload in advance, made by some of Harvard's digital artists.
halloween.mp4 是我们预先上传的视频名称，由哈佛大学的一些数字艺术家制作。
And the type of this video, so that the browser knows for sure, is video slash mp4.
这个视频的类型是 video/mp4，这样浏览器就能确定它的格式。
That's a so-called content type that you just know or you look up to figure it out.
这是一种所谓的内容类型，你得知道它，或者查阅相关资料才能明白。
And just so that this is as animated as possible, I'm going to tell the video tag with a few attributes to autoplay.
为了让它尽可能动起来，我要给 video 标签添加一些属性，让它自动播放。
And it turns out that attributes often have key value pairs, whereby it's the key, the attribute name, equals quote, unquote, some value, just like lang equals quote, unquote, en for English.
属性通常有键值对，其中键是属性名，后面跟着等号，等号两边用引号引起来的则是值，就像 lang = "en" 表示英语一样。
But not all attributes need values.
但并非所有属性都需要值。
In fact, if you read the documentation for HTML's video tag, there's an autoplay attribute where you can literally just say the key, and it needs no value.
事实上，如果你阅读 html video 标签的文档，你会发现有一个 autoplay 属性，你只需写上键，它就不需要值。
It's just going to mean autoplay.
它就表示自动播放。
And if you don't want to autoplay, you just omit it altogether.
如果你不想自动播放，就直接把它省略掉。
So you don't necessarily need a value on or off.
所以你不需要设置  on 或 off 的值。
I want the thing to loop just so it keeps going.
我想让它循环播放。
I want it to be muted so that we don't hear any sound.
我想让它静音，这样我们就听不到任何声音。
In fact, there is no sound.
实际上，没有声音。
But browsers nowadays, for anti-spam and advertising reasons, often will not play a video if it has sound because it's just kind of obnoxious if you visit a page and all of a sudden your speakers start blaring.
但是现在的浏览器，出于反垃圾邮件和广告的原因，通常不会播放有声音的视频，因为如果你访问一个页面，扬声器突然开始大声播放，这会很烦人。
So I know this from having read up on this that I should mute it if I wanted to actually autoplay for real.
我知道这一点是因为我读过一些资料，如果我想真正地自动播放，我应该把它静音。
And then I'll set the width manually for now.
我现在要手动设置宽度。
to be like 128 pixels across, just from some trial and error earlier.
通过之前的一些尝试和错误，设置为 128 像素宽。
And that with attribute does have a value.
而且 `width` 属性确实有一个值。
Now, I'm being a little uptight here by alphabetizing all of my attributes.
现在，我有点过于谨慎，把我的所有属性都按字母顺序排列了。
Not at all necessary.
完全没有必要。
I do it just so I can skim things faster and know if something is there or not.
我这样做只是为了能够更快地浏览内容，并知道某些内容是否存在。
So for me, it's just a matter of style.
所以对我来说，这只是一个风格问题。
Let me go back to my other tab, go back to my index, and you'll see two new files again, the mp4 file and video.html.
让我回到另一个标签页，回到我的 `index.html`，你会再次看到两个新文件，`mp4` 文件和 `video.html`。
I'll click on the latter.
我将点击后者。
And if I did this well, here we have, thanks to our friends in Harvard, our artistic friends at Harvard, very
如果我做得好，在这里我们有，感谢我们在哈佛的朋友，我们在哈佛的艺术朋友们，非常...
Like an ooh would help with the drama here. But OK. But we have a very dramatic, nice Halloween-type view here as well.
就像一声“哦”会有助于这里的戏剧性。不过好吧。但我们在这里也看到了一个非常戏剧性的、很棒的万圣节类型的视图。
So we have videos embedded as well.
所以我们也嵌入了视频。
And suffice it to say, there's ways to embed YouTube videos or Vimeo or other services as well using yet more tags too.
可以说，还有其他方法可以嵌入 YouTube 视频或 Vimeo 或其他服务，也可以使用更多标签。
But the web is, of course, all about Hyperlink, hypertext markup language, where you click on something and you end up somewhere else.
但网络，当然，都是关于超链接，超文本标记语言，你点击某个东西，就会被带到另一个地方。
And this is how the web is so powerfully interconnected.
这就是网络如此强大地相互连接的方式。
So how do we start creating links from one website or web page to another, either that I made or someone else?
那么，我们如何开始创建从一个网站或网页到另一个网站或网页的链接呢，无论是到我自己创建的网站还是到其他人创建的网站？
Well, let me go ahead and open back up my terminal window.
好吧，让我继续打开我的终端窗口。
And let's create a file called link.html, just to demonstrate what you and I know as a link.
我们来创建一个名为 link.html 的文件，演示一下我们所知道的链接。
I'll hide my terminal window now.
我现在隐藏终端窗口。
Let me copy-paste just to save myself some keystrokes.
让我复制粘贴一下，省点力气。
And let me get rid of the video tag so we can focus now on links.
让我去掉 video 标签，以便我们可以专注于链接。
Suppose that I want you to visit Harvard virtually.
假设我想让你虚拟参观哈佛大学。
Well, I could say something like, visit Harvard, period.
我可以说“访问哈佛”。
This is uninteresting because it's just going to be text.
这没意思，因为它只是一段文字。
I probably want you to actually visit harvard.edu instead, more specifically.
我可能想让你实际访问 harvard.edu。
And I'll lowercase it just to be consistent with what browsers do in the address bar.
为了与浏览器地址栏保持一致，我把它改成小写。
All right, let me go now back to this Video tab and go back where we now see my index.
让我回到这个 Video 选项卡，回到我们现在看到我的 index 的地方。
I'll zoom back in, and there's link.html.
我放大，这里有 link.html。
Unfortunately, when I click this and I'll zoom in, you literally just see the text that I wrote.
不幸的是，当我点击它并放大时，你看到的只是我写的文字。
And yet, on every social media platform nowadays, except like Instagram, when you type a URL or what looks like a URL, even if you didn't bother with the HTTP or HTTPS,
然而，现在除了 Instagram 之外，在每个社交媒体平台上，当你输入 URL 或看起来像 URL 的内容时，即使你没有使用 HTTP 或 HTTPS，
It usually automatically links it for you on Facebook, on Twitter, and other sites as well.
它通常会在 Facebook、Twitter 和其他网站上自动为你链接。
That's just a convenience.
这只是一个便利的功能。
Discord and Slack do that too.
Discord 和 Slack 也是如此。
But they're just doing it to make things more user-friendly.
但他们这样做只是为了让事情更方便用户使用。
But they have to generate HTML with the proper tags and attributes.
但他们必须使用正确的标签和属性生成 HTML。
So to get this to actually work, it's not even good enough to say HTTPS colon slash slash www.harvard.edu.
所以要让它真正起作用，即使写成 https ://www.harvard.edu 也是不够的。
Because if I go back now and reload now, you'll literally just see all of that as text.
因为如果我现在回去刷新，你会看到所有这些都只是文本。
If you want the browser to treat this as a link, you need to use the anchor tag.
如果你希望浏览器将其视为链接，则需要使用锚标记。
It'd be great if it were called the link tag, but it's not. It's called the anchor tag, or A for short.
如果它被叫做链接标签就好了，但它不是。 它被称为锚标记，或简称为 A。
And the way you reference the URL to which you want to lead the user is via href, for hyper-reference.
你要引领用户访问的 URL 的引用方式是通过 href，表示超链接引用。
One of the earliest tags, perhaps among the most arcane now.
最早的标签之一，也许是现在最神秘的标签之一。
But if I then put that whole URL in quotes and close my tag, I now have an opportunity to finish my thought in between the start tag and the end tag for this anchor.
但是，如果我把整个 URL 放在引号中并关闭标签，我现在就有机会在这个锚标记的开始标签和结束标签之间完成我的表达。
And what I put in between the start and end tag is whatever the human's going to see.
我在开始标签和结束标签之间放的是用户将要看到的内容。
So here I can say Harvard.
所以这里我可以写“哈佛”。
I can go back to my other tab.
我可以回到我的另一个标签页。
I can reload the page.
我可以重新加载页面。
And now you see the familiar blue underline.
现在你看到了熟悉的蓝色下划线。
This now is an actual link.
这现在是一个实际的链接。
And if I click it, I'll be whisked away to the actual Harvard website.
如果我点击它，我就会被带到实际的哈佛网站。
But there's a risk here.
但这其中有风险。
Can anyone imagine, pretty simply, after, like, what, 60 seconds of the anchor tag, how could someone, an adversary, misuse this tag alone?
谁能想象，非常简单地，在介绍了大约 60 秒的锚标记之后，攻击者会如何滥用这个标签？
How could a website run by an adversary, how could a spammer misuse this tag, do you think?
你认为攻击者运营的网站，垃圾邮件发送者会如何滥用这个标签？
Yeah?
是吗？
Yeah, absolutely.
是的，没错。
You could have it say one thing but lead elsewhere.
你可以让它显示一样东西，但链接到其他地方。
So I could say, Yale in here.
所以我可以在这里写“耶鲁”。
Nothing's stopping me as the developer.
作为开发者，没有什么能阻止我。
Go back to the page, reload.
返回页面，重新加载。
Now it says, visit Yale.
现在它显示，访问耶鲁大学。
You click on Yale, and voila, you end up applying to the wrong place instead.
点击耶鲁大学，瞧，你最终申请错了地方。
Now, there's some hints of this.
有一些提示。
I could hover over this, and super small.
我可以将鼠标悬停在此处，非常小。
This isn't very good for your anti-hacking techniques.
这对你的反黑客技术没有好处。
But way down here, you can actually see the URL that it's going to go to.
但在这里，你可以看到它要跳转到的 URL。
And most browsers, indeed, do this, at least on desktops and laptops.
实际上，大多数浏览器都会这样做，至少在台式机和笔记本电脑上是这样。
So it's a little bit of a hint.
所以这是一个小小的提示。
But what you're seeing here, even though this is kind of a silly, playful example, this is exactly how phishing attacks work, P-H-I-S-H-I-N-G work,
但你在这里看到的，即使这有点傻，像是在玩，但这正是网络钓鱼攻击的工作原理，
Whereby an adversary tells you to log into your PayPal account, but it doesn't go to paypal.com.
攻击者会让你登录你的 PayPal 帐户，但它不会跳转到 paypal.com。
It goes to some other random website that they bought and built that then tries to collect your username and password and store it in their database.
它会跳转到他们购买并搭建的其他随机网站，然后尝试收集你的用户名和密码并将其存储在他们的数据库中。
So now they can log into your PayPal account as you.
这样他们就可以用你的身份登录你的 PayPal 帐户。
And it boils down to that simple primitive.
它可以归结为这种简单的原始形式。
And you can be even more manipulative, too.
你可以更有操控性。
You can even say the whole URL for Yale, like yale.edu, or worse, https://www.yale.edu, reload that.
你甚至可以写出耶鲁大学的完整 URL，比如 yale.edu，或者更糟糕的，https://www.yale.edu，重新加载它。
And now, I mean, who among you and people in your lives are necessarily going to be so paranoid as to not just blindly click on that URL?
现在，我的意思是，你们和你们生活中的人，有谁会偏执到不去盲目地点击那个 URL？
This is why just being a defensive, real-world person nowadays digitally is just ever more so important.
这就是为什么在如今的数字时代，做一个有防御意识的人越来越重要。
So these same things that can be used for good or benign use cases can also be used for ill purposes, too.
因此，这些可以用于良好或良性用例的东西，也可以用于不良目的。
And it is literally that simple.
就这么简单。
Questions now on any of these tags thus far?
到目前为止，关于这些标签还有什么问题吗？
Just a few more to offer up.
还有一些要讲。
Any questions on this here?
对此还有什么问题吗?
No?
没有？
Well, let me open up a couple that I brought in advance just so we don't have to type all of them here.
为了不用在这里全部输入，我先打开一些预先准备好的例子。
If you, for instance, have a web page that's got quite a bit of code, let me go ahead and grab from the website a couple of examples real fast here, namely one that we'll call, how about, meta.html.
例如，如果你有一个包含大量代码的网页，我将从网站上快速获取几个例子，我们将其中一个命名为 meta.html。
And in this example here, give me just a moment to full screen it, we're going to have a file.
在这个例子中，稍等片刻，我把它全屏显示，我们将看到一个文件。
So code meta.html.
代码是 meta.html。
I'll open this up next.
我接下来会打开它。
No relationship to what we now know as meta the company.
它与我们现在所知的公司 meta 没有关系。
But rather, this is going to be a page that I copied and pasted the same chunk of Latin-like text from earlier.
相反，这将是一个页面，我复制并粘贴了前面相同的类似拉丁语的文本块。
So it's going to be a really big paragraph of text.
所以这将是一个非常大的文本段落。
And this is an example where if you were to open this web page, not on my own Mac or your PC, but on your phone,
这是一个例子，如果你在手机上打开这个网页，而不是在我的 Mac 或你的 PC 上，
The font might actually be really annoying and difficult to read. Why?
字体实际上可能非常烦人，难以阅读。为什么？
Because your phone's going to try to squeeze all of the content onto the tiny viewport, the rectangular region of your phone instead.
因为你的手机会试图将所有内容压缩到手机的矩形区域——视窗中。
So it turns out there are ways, pretty easy ways, to make your website mobile-friendly as well, otherwise known technically as responsive.
事实证明，有一些非常简单的方法可以让你的网站也适合移动设备浏览，技术上称为响应式。
And the easiest way to do this is to include this tag here.
最简单的方法是包含这个标签。
A meta tag, again, no relationship to Facebook.
一个 meta 标签，同样与 Facebook 无关。
This has been here much longer.
它已经存在很久了。
And this case here, this meta tag on line 5, has its own sort of approach to key value pairs.
在这个例子中，第 5 行的这个 meta 标签，有它自己的键值对方法。
This is a good example of where it'd be nice if it looked just like everything else.
这就好比是，如果它看起来和其他所有东西一样就更好了。
But this is what we have historically.
但这就是我们一直以来的做法。
You can have a meta tag with an attribute called name that refers to the name of some feature of the browser.
你可以使用一个带有 name 属性的 meta 标签来引用浏览器某些功能的名称。
In this case, viewport is the technical term for the big rectangular region to which I keep referring, the body, really, of your page.
在这种情况下，viewport 是指我一直提到的那个大的矩形区域的技术术语，也就是页面的主体部分。
The content for the viewport, you can say some esoteric details like this.
对于 viewport 的内容，你可以说一些像这样的深奥细节。
The initial scale should be 1.
初始缩放比例应该是 1。
That is, no matter who visits your site, it shouldn't start zoomed in.
也就是说，无论是谁访问你的网站，它都不应该一开始就放大。
It shouldn't start zoomed out.
也不应该一开始就缩小。
It should start at just the default sizing.
它应该从默认大小开始。
And then this here, width equals device width, is a very arcane way of saying, if the user has a small screen, Show the text proportional to that size.
然后这里的 width=device-width 是一种非常神秘的说法，意思是如果用户使用的是小屏幕， 就按比例显示文本。
Don't just try to cram it all into a tiny little window.
不要试图把所有东西都塞进一个小小的窗口里。
So it's super simple.
所以这超级简单。
But if, for the next problem set or future projects as well, you find that just things look really bad on mobile, this kind of tag is the place to start meta.
但是，如果在下一个问题集或未来的项目中，你发现有些东西在移动设备上看起来很糟糕，那么这种 meta 标签就是一个很好的起点。
There aren't terribly many of these that you'll use, but they're useful for other mechanisms as well.
你不会用到太多这样的标签，但它们对其他机制也很有用。
In fact, let me go ahead and semi-secretly pull up one other example as well.
事实上，让我来偷偷地再举一个例子。
whereby I'm going to grab another example that uses more of these tags.
我将获取另一个使用更多这类标签的例子。
And in just a moment, I'll reveal it here.
稍等片刻，我将在这里展示它。
Give me just one second here.
稍等一下。
I'll propose that in this example of meta,
我建议在这个 meta 的例子中，
We now add these properties instead.
现在我们改为添加这些属性。
So I copy pasted this from an existing file, just so as to not waste time typing all of these out.
我从现有文件中复制粘贴了这段代码，这样就不会浪费时间把所有内容都打出来了。
If you've ever shared a URL on Facebook, or Twitter, or Slack, or Discord, or any number of websites nowadays that automatically show a nice preview, where you suddenly see the default image of the page, maybe
如果你曾经在 Facebook、Twitter、Slack、Discord
或现在任何一个能自动显示漂亮预览的网站上分享过 URL，你可能会突然看到页面的默认图片。
Maybe a few sentences or words of text or something like that.
也许还有一些句子、文字或类似的东西。
Sometimes those applications, those websites, will just choose the first image it finds on the website or the first sentence it sees and show that.
有时，这些应用程序、网站只会选择它在网站上找到的第一张图片或第一句话并显示出来。
But that might not be very user-friendly or search engine friendly.
但这可能不太方便用户或不利于搜索引擎优化。
And so a developer might want to control what it is that Slack, Discord, Facebook, Twitter, and other such sites show by default.
因此，开发人员可能希望控制 Slack、Discord、Facebook、Twitter 和其他类似网站默认显示的内容。
For that, you can use nowadays what are called open graph tags, which is to say there's other uses of the meta tag.
为此，你现在可以使用所谓的开放图谱标签，也就是说 meta 标签还有其他用途。
And you just look these things up.
你可以自己去查一下。
Even I had to look this up to remember what the key value pairs are.
甚至我都得查一下才能想起键值对是什么。
The meta tag can also have a property attribute that can be these very specific strings, ogTitle, ogDescription, ogImage, which denotes open graph, which, again, is this standard that's evolved in recent years.
meta 标签还可以有一个 property 属性，
它可以是这些非常具体的字符串：ogTitle、ogDescription、ogImage，它们表示开放图谱，这又是近年来发展起来的一种标准。
And what you can do here is tell browsers, and in turn servers, what you want them to show as the default title of the page, the description of the page, and even the default image, just so you can exercise more control when sharing things socially nowadays as well.
你可以在这里告诉浏览器，进而告诉服务器，你想让他们将什么显示为
页面的默认标题、描述，甚至是默认图片，以便你在如今的社交分享中更好地控制内容。
Again, it just boils down to these key value pairs.
同样，这也归结为这些键值对。
This is absolutely the kind of thing you look up as needed to cross-check.
这绝对是你在需要时进行交叉检查的内容。
But those capabilities are there.
但这些功能是存在的。
And so literally, the next time you paste a link into Slack or Discord or any online site that then displays it in embedded fashion, just know that all this time, a little bit of textual code like this in HTML has been there by whoever authored the site.
下次当你把链接粘贴到 Slack、Discord 或任何以嵌入方式显示链接的网站时，
你要知道，一直以来，网站的作者都在 HTML 中写入了这样一小段文本代码。
All right, let's do one final example in HTML alone before we transition to just cleaning up the aesthetics and improving the visuals of everything we've been creating.
在我们开始整理美观并改进我们创建的所有内容的视觉效果之前，让我们用 HTML 再做一个最后的例子。
Let me go ahead here and close meta.html.
让我在这里关闭 meta.html。
Let me code up a new file called howaboutsearch.html and see if we can't draw some inspiration from our cursory understanding earlier of how URLs work to see if we can't reinvent google.com itself.
让我编写一个名为 howaboutsearch.html 的新文件，
看看我们是否可以从之前对 URL 工作原理的粗略理解中获得一些灵感，看看我们是否可以重塑 google.com 本身。
So recall that a canonical URL might look like this here.
回想一下，规范的 URL 可能是这样的。
And in particular, if you want to pass in user input to that URL, again, you can potentially have a question mark and then a key equals value pair.
如果你想将用户输入传递到该 URL，同样地，你可以潜在地使用问号，然后是键值对。
Or for that matter, you can even have multiple key value pairs that, by convention, are separated by ampersand.
或者，你甚至可以有多个键值对，按照惯例，它们之间用“&”符号分隔。
These things are everywhere.
这些东西随处可见。
Like later today, when you pull up almost any website in your browser, look at the URL, and you'll just see a lot of this, a lot of noise, too, and distractions.
就像今天晚些时候，当你在浏览器中打开几乎任何网站时，查看 URL，你会看到很多这样的东西，很多噪音和干扰。
But there's going to be some equal signs, most likely, and or some ampersands as well.
但很可能还会有一些等号，或者一些“&”符号。
And those are just separating key value pairs.
这些只是用来分隔键值对的。
Now, what can I do here?
现在，我能做些什么呢？
Well, if you think back to how we manually searched for cats earlier, Let me quickly do this.
如果你回想一下我们之前是如何手动搜索猫的，让我快速演示一下。
I'll do this one manually.
我将手动完成这个。
Doc type HTML as my very first line.
`DOCTYPE html` 作为我的第一行代码。
HTML tag with, how about my lang attribute for English up here. And then inside of this, I'll have a head tag.
`HTML` 标签，这里是我的 `lang` 属性，设置为英语。然后在它里面，我会有一个 `head` 标签。
Inside of this, I'll have a title. I'll call this example Search.
在它里面，我会有一个 `title`，我将其称为“示例搜索”。
And then down here, I'll have my beginning of a body tag.
然后在这里，我将开始写我的 `body` 标签。
And now, let me introduce you to really a final tag for now, a form tag, which will create a web form, the thing with text boxes and buttons that you and I use every day on any number of websites.
现在，让我向你介绍一个目前为止最后的标签，`form` 标签，
它将创建一个网页表单，也就是你在任何网站上每天都能看到和使用的，带有文本框和按钮的东西。
Inside of this form, I'm going to have an input, like a text box, whose name is going to be Q for query, because I'm trying to reimplement Google here.
在这个表单中，我将有一个 `input`，就像一个文本框，它的 `name` 将是 `Q`，代表查询，因为我试图在这里重新实现 Google。
The type of that, I want to be a text box
它的 `type`，我希望是一个文本框。
Or if I know I'm using this for search, I can actually change this to a search box.
或者，如果我知道我要用它来搜索，我可以把它改成搜索框。
And it's going to let me, it's going to generally put a little x there so you can clear it quickly.
它会让我，它通常会在那里放一个小 `x`，这样你就可以快速清除它。
That's a nice little enhancement as well.
这也是一个不错的小改进。
And then I'm going to give myself a Submit button by doing input.
然后我要通过 `input` 给自己一个“提交”按钮。
Whoops, I'm going to give myself a Submit button by doing input type equals Submit.
哎呀，我要通过输入类型等于 Submit 来给自己一个提交按钮。
And then I'll leave that as such here.
然后我就把它留在这里。
All right, now I need to do a little bit more. But let's see how this looks.
现在我还需要做更多的事情。但让我们看看效果如何。
Let me go over to my other tab.
让我转到另一个标签页。
Let me go back to my index.
让我回到我的 index 页面。
And if I zoom out.
如果我缩小一点。
There is search.html. I'll click it.
这里有 search.html。我将点击它。
And there's not much going on here, even if I zoom in.
即使我放大，这里也没有太多内容。
But I do, indeed, have a really big text box and a Submit button.
但我确实有一个非常大的文本框和一个提交按钮。
But I haven't, in my HTML, told anyone anywhere that I want this input, whether I type cat or dog, to go to google.com.
但是我还没有在我的 HTML 中告诉任何人，我希望这个输入，无论我输入的是 cat 还是 dog，都跳转到 google.com。
So for that, I need a couple of more attributes. And I know this from having done this before, and any online reference will say the same.
为此，我还需要几个属性。我以前做过这个，所以我知道这一点，任何在线参考资料都会这么说。
You can add an action attribute, like, what do you want the action of this form to be?
你可以添加一个 action 属性，比如，你希望这个表单的动作是什么？
And you can put the URL to which you want this form to be submitted.
你可以把你想让这个表单提交到的 URL 放进去。
And I know from tinkering that it should be https://www.google.com search.
通过尝试我知道它应该是 https://www.google.com/search。
I don't need to put any question marks here myself, but I do want the, browser to do that for me.
我自己不需要在这里放任何问号，但我希望浏览器能帮我做这件事。
So let me go back to my other tab.
让我回到另一个标签页。
Let me reload.
让我重新加载。
And nothing visually has happened.
视觉上没有任何变化。
But watch this. When I now type in cats, but before I hit Enter, notice that I'm currently at some long, crazy URL slash search.html is expected.
但是看这里。当我现在输入 cats 时，在我按下回车键之前，请注意我当前所在的位置是一个很长很奇怪的 URL，后面是/search.html。
If I now go down to the Submit button and click Submit, watch what happens to the URL and the page itself.
如果我现在移动到提交按钮并点击提交，观察 URL 和页面本身会发生什么。
I'm whisked away to the actual google.com.
我被带到了真实的 google.com。
And indeed, there are those same cats.
确实，这里也有相同的猫咪图片。
And if I zoom in here, you'll see that my URL has changed to be indeed slash search question mark q equals cats.
如果我放大这里，你会看到我的 URL 已经变成了 /search?q=cats。
So this is just how web forms work.
这就是网页表单的工作方式。
When you submit any form on the web in this way, the browser automatically goes to that action URL, adds a question mark, puts any key value pairs that you manually typed into the text boxes, and lets the server do its thing.
当你以这种方式在网页上提交任何表单时，浏览器会自动跳转到 action URL，
添加一个问号，将你手动输入到文本框中的任何键值对放进去，然后让服务器处理。
Now, here's where Chrome is starting to simplify things. Safari does this too.
现在，Chrome 开始简化这些事情了，Safari 也是如此。
If you double-click on your URL, now you see the full URL.
如果你双击 URL，现在你就会看到完整的 URL。
But if any parts are missing, that's just a UI thing to eliminate visual distractions nowadays.
但如果缺少任何部分，那只是一种 UI 设计，为了消除视觉干扰。
Meanwhile, if I go back to my own form, if I search this time for dogs and hit Enter, now again, the URL changes to be q equals dogs.
同时，如果我返回我自己的表单，这次搜索 dogs 并按下回车键，URL 再次改变，变成了 q=dogs。
And it all reduces to this basic building block of using a form tag.
所有这些都归结为使用 form 标签这个基本构建块。
Now, I can be more explicit.
现在，我可以更明确一些。
If I know I want to use get, which is actually the default, I can literally say, quote unquote, get in all lowercase, even though the verb earlier was by design in uppercase.
如果我知道我想使用 get，它实际上是默认的，我可以直接写 "get"，全部小写，即使之前的动词是大写的。
But here now, I'm just being ever more explicit.
但现在，我只是想更加明确。
If I don't want the label of this button,
如果我不想要这个按钮的标签，
to be very generically submit.
是非常普通的 "submit"。
Maybe I want it to be Google Search, quote unquote.
也许我想要它是 "Google Search"。
Well, if you read the documentation for forms, you can actually change the value of the button to be, quote unquote, Google Search.
如果你阅读表单的文档，你会发现实际上可以将按钮的 value 改为 "Google Search"。
And if I now go back here and reload, I get a fresh form.
如果我现在回到这里重新加载，我会得到一个新的表单。
And now I get a button that literally says Google Search.
现在我得到了一个按钮，上面写着 "Google Search"。
And if I tinker with this further, because this isn't very user-friendly, there's even more attributes I can do, I can add on my Search input, a autocomplete equals off if I don't want to see my own history for whatever reason.
如果我进一步修改它，因为它不是非常用户友好，我还可以添加更多属性，
我可以在我的搜索输入框中添加 autocomplete="off"，如果我因为某些原因不想看到我自己的历史记录。
I don't want people knowing I'm searching for cats and dogs on this page.
我可不想让别人知道我在这个页面上搜索猫猫狗狗。
I can autofocus on the text box so that it shows the cursor blinking in that box by default.
我可以自动聚焦到文本框，这样默认情况下光标就会在框中闪烁。
And I can even do something like this.
我还可以这样做。
I can have a placeholder attribute that says something like query or some other documentation for the user.
我可以添加一个 placeholder 属性，显示“query”之类的提示信息，为用户提供一些说明。
And if I now go back and reload, You'll see, notice, it says query, and it's subtle.
如果我现在返回并重新加载， 你会注意到，它显示了“query”，很微妙。
But my cursor is already positioned there.
但我的光标已经在那里了。
It gave it focus.
它已经获得了焦点。
And I can type cats now without having to click in the box manually, which is just marginally better for the user's experience.
我可以直接输入“cats”，而不需要手动点击输入框，这对用户体验来说稍微好一些。
Any questions now on all of this here?
关于这些内容，大家还有什么问题吗？
Any questions?
还有什么问题吗？
All right, that too was a lot.
这些内容也挺多的。
Why don't we take a casual five-minute break?
我们休息五分钟吧？
And when we resume, we'll take a look at CSS, add in some JavaScript, and then wrap up.
回来之后，我们学习 CSS，添加一些 JavaScript，然后就下课。
So five minutes only for now.
休息五分钟。
All right, we are back.
我们回来了。
So that's technically it for HTML.
以上就是 HTML 的内容了。
Here on out, it'll be up to online resources and references we point you to just to fill in your vocabulary for more tags and attributes.
接下来，你可以通过我们提供的在线资源和参考资料来学习更多标签和属性。
But conceptually, that's it.
但从概念上讲，就是这样。
There's attributes.
还有属性。
There are tags.
这里有标签。
And there are attributes.
这里还有属性。
And the rest of it really is just kind of a laundry list of possible features.
剩下的其实只是一些可能功能的清单。
But it turns out, too, you'll see over time that you can even see the HTML for websites.
但事实证明，随着时间的推移，你甚至可以看到网站的 HTML 代码。
So for instance, if I go over to harvard.edu in my browser.
例如，如果我在浏览器中访问 harvard.edu。
which I'll go ahead in just a moment here and do here, and do HTTPS colon slash slash www.harvard.edu slash Enter.
我马上就会在这里输入 https ://www.harvard.edu/ 回车。
It, again, will pull up today's version of Harvard's website.
它会再次打开今天版本的哈佛大学网站。
And if I right-click or Control-click on it again and go to Inspect, you'll see those so-called developer tools.
如果我再次右键单击或 Control+单击它，然后选择“检查”，你就会看到那些所谓的开发者工具。
And earlier, we focused on the Network tab, just so we could see the HTTP stuff going on.
之前，我们关注的是“网络”选项卡，以便查看正在进行的 HTTP 操作。
But what I glossed over earlier was the so-called Elements tab, which actually shows you the HTML underlying any web page on the internet.
但我之前忽略的是所谓的“元素”选项卡，它实际上向你展示了任何网页背后的 HTML 代码。
And so, for instance, here is the underlying HTML for Harvard's home page as of right now.
例如，这里就是截至目前哈佛大学主页的 HTML 代码。
And aesthetically, some of it's been collapsed.
从美观角度来看，其中一些代码已被折叠起来。
So if I click on these various triangles, I'll see what's actually inside of, that is, the children of some of these HTML tags.
如果我点击这些三角形，我就会看到其中的一些 HTML 标签的子元素。
But here on out, if you're ever curious as to how a web page made some feature visually, you can just literally use these developer tools built into your own browser just to see what the web developer actually did.
但在这里，如果你想知道网页是如何实现某些视觉功能的，你可以直接使用浏览器内置的开发者工具，看看网页开发者到底做了什么。
And you can do things, too, like this.
你也可以做这样的事情。
Maybe, let's see, if you really like this menu in the top right-hand corner of Harvard's website, you can even right-click that or Control-click that specifically, choose Inspect.
假设，让我们看看，如果你真的很喜欢哈佛大学网站右上角的这个菜单，你甚至可以右键单击它，或者 Control+单击它，然后选择“检查”。
And what browsers will do is jump to the HTML core.
浏览器会跳转到相应的 HTML 代码。
corresponding to that visual element on the page.
对应于页面上的那个视觉元素。
And here you can see, though we've not talked about this tag before, there's a button tag, there's an ID attribute, and there's some other attributes as well that define that button.
在这里你可以看到，虽然我们之前没有讲过这个标签，但这里有一个 button 标签，一个 id 属性，以及一些其他的属性来定义这个按钮。
You can do other things, too, in the web page.
你也可以在网页上做其他的事情。
Let me scroll down, for instance, here.
比如，让我往下滚动到这儿。
And let's go, actually, let's go to another one, like Yale.edu here in today's theme.
咱们再打开一个，就今天这个主题，比如 Yale.edu。
And suppose we want to do something like,
假设我们想做一些事情，比如
Change the aesthetics of this website.
改变这个网站的美观。
Well, let's do how about this over here, Life at Yale.
咱们来试试这个，Life at Yale。
Let's right-click on this, choose Inspect.
右键单击，选择“检查”。
That's going to jump to that part of the page.
这会跳转到页面的那一部分。
And notice what you can do here in this Elements tab.
注意在这个“元素”选项卡中可以做什么。
We can be a little playful and return today, Life at Harvard.
我们可以稍微玩一下，把今天的内容改成 Life at Harvard。
And voila, we've now changed Yale's website, it would seem.
瞧，我们现在似乎改变了耶鲁大学的网站。
So have we really?
但我们真的改变了吗？
Hopefully, hacking is not actually this easy.
希望黑客攻击实际上没那么容易。
What did we actually do?
我们到底做了什么？
Based on today's mental model.
根据今天的思维模型。
Like, I have changed the page.
好像是我改变了页面。
Yeah, I've just changed how it is for me, right? Because my browser, just like with Phyllis and Brian from the get-go, requested Yale's web page.
是的，我只是改变了它在我这里的显示，对吧？因为我的浏览器，就像一开始的 Phyllis 和 Brian 一样，请求了耶鲁大学的网页。
I got back a virtual envelope containing that HTML, as we've now called it.
我收到了一个包含 HTML 的虚拟信封，就像我们现在所说的那样。
My browser has a local copy.
我的浏览器有一个本地副本。
It's got its own tree, otherwise known as a DOM, Document Object Model, built up in its memory.
它有自己的树，也称为 DOM，即文档对象模型，构建在它的内存中。
And yeah, I went to town and changed my copy of it.
是的，我随意修改了我的副本。
But of course, hopefully, I've not changed the actual server.
当然，希望我没有改变实际的服务器。
And in fact, if I reload Yale's website now, hopefully,
事实上，如果我现在刷新耶鲁大学的网站，希望，
It will revert back to, indeed, yep, what it should be instead, life at Yale.
它会恢复到，是的，它应该是什么样子，耶鲁的生活。
But this ability in your own browser, be it Chrome or Firefox or Edge or Safari, to have these built-in developer tools are very powerful because it's going to enable you to not only diagnose problems that will invariably arise in the coming weeks with your own code, but it's also going to allow you to learn from other sites how you can do things and tinker as well.
但是你的浏览器（无论是 Chrome、Firefox、Edge 还是 Safari）
中内置的开发者工具非常强大，因为它不仅能让你诊断未来几周代码中出现的问题，还能让你从其他网站学习如何操作和修改。
But up until now, we focused only on tags and attributes and on the structure of a web page.
但到目前为止，我们只关注标签、属性和网页的结构。
Let's now focus more on the aesthetics and fine-tuning that.
现在让我们把重点放在美学和微调上。
It turns out that HTML has very limited support for anything aesthetic, like font sizes and colors and so forth.
事实证明，HTML 对任何美学方面（如字体大小、颜色等）的支持都非常有限。
And in recent years, people have used, necessarily, a second language called CSS, not a programming language, again, a markup language, if you will,
近年来，人们一直在使用一种名为 CSS 的第二语言，它不是一种编程语言，而是一种标记语言，
To just fine-tune the aesthetics of a page, font sizes, colors, margins, and all of that.
用于微调页面的美观程度，如字体大小、颜色、边距等。
So CSS is going to allow us to define a whole bunch of properties, which is just another group of people's terminology for key-value pairs.
因此，CSS 将允许我们定义一堆属性，这只是人们对键值对的另一种说法。
Indeed, ever since week 5, key-value pairs are everywhere in the world, not just at Sweetgreen and restaurants, but indeed under inline code.
事实上，从第 5 周开始，键值对就无处不在，不仅在 Sweetgreen 和餐馆，而且在内联代码中也是如此。
and languages and technologies like these.
以及类似的语言和技术。
So properties is the new word in CSS for what a moment ago we called attributes in HTML.
因此，属性是 CSS 中的新词，指的是我们刚才在 HTML 中所说的属性。
But it's the same idea, just different vocabulary that you get used to over time.
但它也是同样的概念，只是不同的词汇，你需要随着时间的推移慢慢习惯。
A few phrases I might use now and you'll hear in the coming days would be these, type selector, class selector, ID selector, attribute selector, which just refer to
我现在可能会用到，而且你在未来几天会听到的一些短语是：类型选择器、类选择器、id 选择器、属性选择器，它们指的是
Different techniques we're about to see that are going to allow you to control more precisely the aesthetics of specific things on the page.
我们将要看到的不同技术，这些技术将允许你更精确地控制页面上特定内容的美观程度。
And the way we're going to do this is we're going to take our basic HTML, like we saw earlier, and we're going to introduce in the next few minutes just a couple of more tags and or attributes, one,
我们要做的就是采用我们之前看到的基本 HTML，并在接下来的几分钟内介绍几个标签和/或属性，
We're going to introduce you to a tag called style, which, nicely named, allows you to control the style, the aesthetics, the visuals of the web page.
我们将向你介绍一个名为 style 的标签，顾名思义，它允许你控制网页的样式、美观和视觉效果。
Or we're going to introduce you to a link tag, which, very confusingly, does not give you a link that you can click on.
或者我们将向你介绍一个 link 标签，它很容易让人混淆，因为它并不能提供一个可以点击的链接。
It just links to another file that then gets automatically
它只是链接到另一个文件，然后自动
Included or imported, to borrow our language from C or in Python.
包含或导入，借用 C 语言或 Python 中的术语。
But same idea.
但意思相同。
This will allow us to include secondary files.
这允许我们包含辅助文件。
And we're going to ultimately show you how you can leverage third-party frameworks, libraries that other people wrote, so as to not get stuck in the weeds of all the fine-tuning of aesthetics and just make pretty things fast.
我们最终将向你展示如何利用第三方框架（其他人编写的库），这样你就不会被所有美学上的微调所困扰，从而快速制作出漂亮的东西。
So you can focus really on the intellectually interesting part, if that's your choice, of building the content, the site out, the application out yourself.
所以你可以真正专注于构建内容、网站、应用程序的有趣部分，如果这是你的选择的话。
All right, so with that said, let me go back to VS Code here.
话虽如此，让我们回到 VS Code。
And let me go ahead and create a simple example called home.html, like a very simple home page for John Harvard, for instance.
让我们继续创建一个名为 home.html 的简单示例，比如一个非常简单的约翰·哈佛主页。
Let me give myself three paragraphs initially, the first of which is just going to have the person's name.
让我先给自己三个段落，第一个段落只写这个人的名字。
The second paragraph is going to say something like, welcome to my home page. To greet visitors.
第二段会写一些类似于“欢迎来到我的主页”之类的话来问候访客。
And the third is going to be like a little footer, like copyright, how about John Harvard 1636, or something like that.
第三段将像一个小页脚，比如版权，比如约翰·哈佛 1636，或者类似的东西。
All right, let me go back to my other tab as before, reload my index.
让我们像之前一样回到另一个标签页，重新加载 index。
There's my new file, home.html.
这是我的新文件，home.html。
And I'll click that.
我会点击它。
And you'll see, OK, I mean, this is sort of 1636 style web page, super simple, all text, nothing really interesting going on there.
你会看到，好吧，我的意思是，这有点像 1636 年风格的网页，超级简单，全是文字，没有任何有趣的东西。
But we can start to style it a little differently.
但我们可以开始用不同的方式来设计它。
Like, if the title of the page is John Harvard, and then it's welcome to my home page, and then this less important footer, why don't we have the text be large, then medium, then small?
比如，如果页面的标题是约翰·哈佛，然后是欢迎来到我的主页，
然后是不太重要的页脚，为什么我们不让文本是大号的，然后是中号的，然后是小号的呢？
So something arbitrary, but a little more nuanced.
一些随意的东西，但更细致入微。
So let me go back to VS Code here.
让我们回到 VS Code。
And in my home.html file, let me introduce not yet the style tag, but what I'm going to call temporarily the style attribute.
在我的 home.html 文件中，让我介绍的不是 style 标签，而是我暂时称之为 style 属性的东西。
Both indeed exist.
两者确实都存在。
This one's simpler, and it's going to be correct, but we'll see in a moment not as well designed, arguably, as is often our narrative.
这个例子更简单，而且结果正确，但我们稍后会看到，它在设计上可能没有我们经常讲到的那样好。
So inside of the style tag, you can put this language called CSS.
在 style 标签中，可以放入这种叫做 CSS 的语言。
Key-value pairs, otherwise known as properties.
键值对，也称为属性。
The only way you know what properties exist, what keys exist, is by taking a class, reading a book, looking at an online reference.
要知道有哪些属性、哪些键，唯一的方法是上课、看书或查阅在线参考资料。
And we're going to give you just a sampling of what's out there.
我们会向你展示其中的一部分。
So suppose I want to control the font size of this first paragraph.
假设我想控制第一段的字体大小。
I can literally say font-size, in all lowercase, colon, and then a word like large, or I can specify 12-point, or 18-point, or something more precise like that, like from Google Docs or Microsoft Word.
我可以写上 font-size，全部小写，然后是冒号，然后是一个单词，
比如 large，或者我可以指定 12-point 或 18-point，或者更精确的数字，就像 Google Docs 或 Microsoft Word 那样。
And suppose I want to make this text down here medium.
假设我想把这里的文本设置为中等大小。
Well, I'll do, quote unquote, font-size colon medium.
我会写上“font-size: medium”。
And down here, I'll do style equals font-size small.
在这里，我会写上 style 等于“font-size: small”。
So I'm going to start with just these three key value pairs.
我先从这三个键值对开始。
Same key, but different values.
相同的键，但值不同。
I'll go back to my page, and in a moment, I'll reload.
我会回到我的页面，稍后刷新。
And it's going to be somewhat subtle, but watch how the font size do change when I reload now.
变化可能不太明显，但请注意在我刷新页面后字体大小的变化。
All right, so I've got a little bigger.
现在大了一些。
Middle one's about the same.
中间的和原来差不多。
And the last one is a little smaller.
最后一个小了一些。
What if I want to center it, just like many web pages have the text like this centered?
如果我想让它居中，就像很多网页上的文本都是居中显示的那样，该怎么办？
Well, I can separate these key value pairs with semicolons.
可以用分号分隔这些键值对。
And I'm sorry, semicolons are kind of sort of back with CSS.
抱歉，分号在 CSS 中又回来了。
But I can do text-align colon center.
我可以设置 `text-align: center`。
Strictly speaking, I don't need the last semicolon if there's no more key value pairs.
严格来说，如果后面没有键值对，最后一个分号可以省略。
But I'll just do it to be consistent, text-align Colon center, and then down here, after another semicolon, text align colon center.
但为了保持一致，我还是加上它，`text-align: center`，然后在这里，在另一个分号后面，也是 `text-align: center`。
All right, let's go back.
我们回去看看。
Reload.
刷新。
Now it's going to be much more obvious, the change.
现在变化就很明显了。
And we now have the beginnings of a home page.
我们现在有了一个主页的雏形。
Still pretty basic, but at least it's a little more interesting.
虽然还很基础，但至少比之前有趣多了。
Turns out we can do a little better with the copyright symbol.
我们可以把版权符号做得更好一点。
Most computers actually have support for a circle with a C in it.
大多数计算机实际上都支持带 C 的圆圈符号。
But you can't just do that with text like this.
但不能直接用这样的文本输入。
There's different ways to do this.
这有很多方法。
You could copy-paste it from a website that already has it, so you don't have to figure out the magical keystroke on your Mac or PC.
你可以从已经有这个符号的网站上复制粘贴，这样就不用费尽心思去想在 Mac 或 PC 上输入它的神奇按键了。
But there's also in HTML what are called entities.
在 HTML 中，也有一种叫做实体的东西。
And you can actually specify, using hexadecimal or decimal codes, numbers like this, hash 169 semicolon after an ampersand.
你可以用十六进制或十进制代码来指定，比如像这样，`&#169;`，一个与符号后面跟着一个十六进制数，再加一个分号。
And this is a special symbol that you can look up in any online reference for special characters that are hard or impossible to type manually at your keyboard.
这是一个特殊符号，你可以在任何在线参考中查找那些难以或无法在键盘上手动输入的特殊字符。
And this, let me zoom in just so it's obvious, if I reload now, instead of being two parentheses and a C character, now it's a proper copyright symbol.
让我们放大一下，这样看得更清楚，如果我现在刷新，它就不再是两个括号和一个 C 字符了，而是一个正确的版权符号。
So you'll see these out there. They're not necessarily that frequently used nowadays, but it's good to know that they exist.
你会在很多地方看到这些符号，现在它们不一定经常使用，但了解一下它们的存在还是很有用的。
But let me go back now to my code and propose that, while correct,
但现在让我回到代码，虽然这是对的，
This is arguably not very well designed.
但这可以说设计得并不好。
And even if you've never seen HTML, never seen CSS before, what instinct might you have for why this is poorly designed? Yeah?
即使你以前从未接触过 HTML 或 CSS，你能凭直觉说说为什么这个设计很糟糕吗？
There's repetition, right?
有很多重复，对吧？
In general, in the past several weeks, C, Python, SQL, repetition generally bad and sloppy and is not going to scale well.
总的来说，在过去几周，无论是 C、Python 还是 SQL，重复通常都是糟糕、草率的，而且不利于扩展。
So the repetition I think you're probably alluding to is text-aligned center, text-aligned center, text-aligned center.
我认为大家指的重复应该是 text-aligned center，它出现了很多次。
Well, we can factor that out in CSS. The C in CSS means cascading.
我们可以用 CSS 把它提取出来。CSS 中的 C 代表级联。
And this means that if you move some properties to a parent or a grandparent, the children or grandchildren will inherit those properties.
这意味着如果你将某些属性移动到父元素或祖先元素，则子元素或后代元素将继承这些属性。
That is, they will cascade down the family tree, so to speak.
也就是说，它们会沿着家族树向下级联。
And so let me go ahead and remove all of these, since I claim they're indeed redundant.
我先把这些都删掉，因为它们确实是多余的。
And let me preserve just one of them by, well, let me do this.
只保留其中一个，我这样做。
It's not quite right to put a paragraph inside of a paragraph.
把一个段落放在另一个段落里是不太对的。
Like, that's just not a thing in English writing or in writing more generally.
无论是在英文写作还是其他任何写作中，这都是不允许的。
So I'm going to do one thing first.
所以我先做一件事。
It turns out that these two are arguably not paragraphs, right?
可以说这两个不算是段落，对吧？
This is like a header, the body, the essence of the page, and then the footer.
这更像是页面的标题、正文和页脚。
paragraph isn't quite the right English semantics, you can actually use more generically a tag that's all over the internet called div for division of the page.
paragraph 的语义不太准确，你可以使用更通用的标签 div，它代表页面的 division（分区）。
And this is just a very generic term for a big rectangular region that divides the page again and again, just so that you can think about different regions.
它只是一个非常通用的术语，表示页面上的一个大的矩形区域，可以用来划分页面，让你可以考虑不同的区域。
Now that I have div, which really has no more meaning than that.
现在我有了 div，它本身没有更多含义。
It's a division of the page, interpret as you will.
它只是页面的一个分区，你可以根据需要解释它。
Now I can have multiple ones of these.
现在我可以有多个这样的分区。
And let me go ahead and open a div tag here.
我在这里打开一个 div 标签。
Let me close a new div tag here.
让我在这里关闭一个新的 div 标签。
And then just to keep everything tidy, I'm going to highlight everything in between and hit Tab.
为了保持整洁，我要选中所有内容，然后按 Tab 键。
And that just automatically indents everything for me.
这会自动为我缩进所有内容。
Now I have three divs inside of another div.
现在我在另一个 div 中有三个 div。
And that's totally fine.
这完全没问题。
This is very commonly done.
这样做很常见。
Now I'm going to do this, style equals quote unquote
现在我要这样做，style 等于引号
text-align colon center semicolon or not.
text-align 冒号 center 分号，要不要都行。
And now I have some cascading capabilities.
现在我有一些级联功能。
Now the parent of those three children, John Harvard will come to my home page, and the copyright will now all inherit that property.
现在，这三个孩子的父级，John Harvard 将会出现在我的主页上，版权声明现在都将继承该属性。
So when I hit reload, nothing aesthetically has changed.
所以当我点击重新加载时，外观上没有任何变化。
Whoops, sorry.
哎呀，抱歉。
I should have done reload slightly earlier.
我应该早点重新加载。
When you use a div instead of a paragraph, it actually gets rid of the space between those paragraphs.
当你使用 div 而不是段落时，它实际上会消除段落之间的间距。
It just sandwiches them a little closer together.
它只是让它们之间的距离更近了一点。
I can fix this in another way.
我可以通过另一种方式解决这个问题。
But that aside, everything is still centered, and the text is still large, medium, and small.
但除此之外，所有内容仍然居中，文本仍然是大、中、小。
But I should have called out that change in the paragraph spacing.
但我应该提醒大家注意段落间距的变化。
But we could bring that back before long if we wanted.
但如果我们愿意，我们可以很快地把它改回来。
Now, what more could I do to maybe improve this?
现在，我还可以做些什么来改进它呢？
Well, strictly speaking, I don't really need that parent div, right?
其实我不需要那个父 div，对吧？
Because these three divs inside already had a parent.
因为这三个内部的 div 已经有一个父元素了。
So let me actually get rid of that new div just to undo what I did.
让我把新加的 div 删除，撤销之前的操作。
I'll highlight this. And if you haven't seen this trick, Shift-Tab will unindent nicely, which is perhaps helpful.
我先选中这些代码。如果你没见过这个技巧，`Shift-Tab` 可以很方便地取消缩进，这可能会有帮助。
I could just put that text align center on the body tag.
我可以直接把 `text align center`  放到 body 标签上。
So text align colon center, quote unquote.
也就是 `text align: center`。
This, too, would work as well, so long as you go up the family tree, so to speak, reload.
只要你沿着“家族树”向上找到合适的标签，这样做也是可以的。刷新一下。
And now, indeed, there's nothing aesthetically that has changed this time.
可以看到，这次在外观上没有任何变化。
But it turns out, nowadays, the web is getting a little more sophisticated.
但事实证明，现在的网络正在变得越来越复杂。
And even though you will see so many examples online in tutorials and books using div, div, div, div all over the place, there are newer semantic tags.
尽管你会在网上教程和书籍中看到很多到处使用 div 的例子，但现在出现了一些更新的语义化标签。
Semantic just means they have more meaning than this generic notion of a division.
语义化意味着它们比“分区”这个通用概念表达的含义更丰富。
a documentation for HTML, you'll see that if you want to have a header on a page, not a heading like H1, H2, but a header, there's literally nowadays a header tag.
如果你去查阅 HTML 文档，你会发现如果你想在页面上添加页眉
（不是像 h1、h2 那样的标题，而是一个页眉区域），现在可以直接使用 header 标签。
And this is marginally better because it now says what it is.
这样做会稍微好一些，因为它现在明确说明了它的作用。
Search engines like Google and Bing can detect, oh, that's the header of the page.
像谷歌和必应这样的搜索引擎可以识别出来，这是页面的页眉。
Maybe we should use this and give it more prominence in the search results.
也许我们应该使用它，并在搜索结果中赋予它更高的权重。
You can then have a main part of the page, so literally a tag called main nowadays.
然后你可以为页面的主要内容使用 main 标签。
You can literally have a footer of the page.
你也可以直接使用 footer 标签来表示页脚。
And again, these are often useful for, Screen readers to help recite things verbally for folks who might otherwise not be able to read them.
同样，这些标签通常对屏幕阅读器很有用，可以帮助那些无法阅读的人朗读内容。
And probably these screen readers might highlight the header and the main part, but maybe might not spend time for the user on the footer, which is arguably a little less important semantically usually.
这些屏幕阅读器可能会突出显示页眉和主要内容，但可能不会在页脚上花费太多时间，因为页脚通常在语义上不那么重要。
Or search engines, again, now know what's the header, what's the footer, what's the main part of the page, so they know what to search and analyze.
搜索引擎现在也能识别页面的页眉、页脚和主体内容，从而精准搜索和分析。
So this would arguably be a better design nowadays as well.
可以说，这也是现今较好的设计方式。
But what else remains as a problem?
但还有什么问题呢？
Well, this is now getting a little bit more subtle and takes some experience.
这个问题比较微妙，需要一些经验才能发现。
But this practice of putting HTML and CSS all in the same file, it's a little sloppy.
把 HTML 和 CSS 都放在同一个文件里的做法有点草率。
Why?
为什么？
Because it means I'm co-mingling my data with the presentation thereof, like the juicy stuff I care about, like John Harvard and the phrase, welcome to my home page, and all of the aesthetics that I might want to change over time.
因为这意味着我把数据和数据的呈现方式混在一起了，比如我关心的重要内容，
像 John Harvard、“欢迎来到我的主页”这句话，以及所有我可能想随时更改的样式。
And honestly, because everything is currently in one big file,
而且说实话，因为所有东西目前都在一个大文件中，
It's going to make it really hard for me to collaborate with a classmate or a colleague at work so that maybe I do the HTML, they do the CSS.
这会让我很难和同学或同事合作，比如我写 HTML，他们写 CSS。
Like, uh-uh. Not if you're all working in the same file.
如果你们都在同一个文件中工作，那是不可能的。
It would be a nightmare.
那将是一场噩梦。
Even if you use the VS Code sharing feature like Google Docs and both are typing at the same time, you're going to mess up somehow.
即使你使用了像 Google Docs 那样的 VS Code 共享功能，两个人同时输入，也肯定会出错。
It'd be nice if we could separate these two languages.
如果能把这两种语言分开就好了。
Well, one way to do that would be as follows.
有一种方法可以实现。
Let me get rid of all of the style tags, sorry, style attributes that I've added up until now.
让我把到目前为止添加的所有 style 标签，抱歉，是 style 属性都删除掉。
on all four now of these tags.
现在这四个标签上的都要删除。
And let me introduce the style tag that we saw on the slide earlier instead.
让我引入之前幻灯片中看到的 style 标签来代替。
I'm going to go up here into the head of the page, which is where technically these style tags must go so that they're already loaded into memory before the body is even analyzed by the browser.
我要把它放到页面的 head 部分，从技术上讲，这些 style 标签必须放在这里，这样在浏览器分析 body 部分之前，它们就已经加载到内存中了。
And inside of this style tag, I'm actually going to select the HTML elements that I want to stylize, if you will.
在这个 style 标签里面，我要选择想要设置样式的 HTML 元素。
So if I want to change the body's aesthetics, I'm going to literally type the name of that tag, body.
所以如果我想改变 body 的样式，我就要输入标签的名字 body。
And then, I'm sorry, curly braces are back also from C. Inside of these curly braces, I'm going to put text align center.
不好意思，花括号也从 C 语言中借用过来了。在这些花括号中，我要放上 text align center。
So the key value pairs are the same.
所以键值对还是一样的。
The only new thing I've done is I've moved some of the syntax up to this new style tag in the head.
我唯一做的改变是，我把一些语法移到了 head 中这个新的 style 标签里。
If I want to now control the header tag as well, I can use the same curly braces.
如果我现在也想控制 header 标签，我可以用同样的花括号。
This is convention to put the open curly brace on the same line, the closed curly brace on another.
按照惯例，左花括号和右花括号分别写在同一行和另一行。
The browser doesn't really care, but this is a common CSS style convention.
浏览器并不关心这些，但这是一种常见的 CSS 代码风格规范。
I'm going to do font-size large, semicolon.
我要写上 font-size: large，分号。
Then for the main tag, I'm going to do font-size medium.
然后对于 main 标签，我要写上 font-size: medium。
And then for the footer tag, I'm going to do font-size small.
然后对于 footer 标签，我要写上 font-size: small。
So same exact thing.
所以完全一样。
And it's admittedly a little bit more verbose.
不得不承认，这确实有点冗长。
It's taking up more lines of code.
占用了更多行代码。
It doesn't all quite fit on the screen.
并不能完全显示在屏幕上。
But if you scroll back down now.
但如果你现在向下滚动。
And you'll acquire an eye for this.
你会对此有所感触。
This is just better.
这样写只是更好。
Like, it's just more compact.
更简洁。
It's more readable.
可读性更强。
The content, the data jumps out.
内容和数据更加突出。
And there's no visual distractions like the CSS properties as before.
而且不像之前那样，有 CSS 属性这样的视觉干扰。
Upside here, too, is that we don't actually need to, this doesn't actually change the aesthetics.
好的一面是我们不需要，实际上这并不会改变外观。
If I reload the same page, it still looks the same.
如果我重新加载相同的页面，它看起来还是一样。
But I've taken a step toward some slightly better design.
但我已经向更好的设计迈进了一步。
But let me propose that there's other ways to do this, too.
但是，我建议还有其他方法可以做到这一点。
We just selected things by way of their type.
我们只是通过它们的类型来选择东西。
So that was a so-called type selector, when I literally just specified the type of tag, body, header, main, footer.
这就是所谓的类型选择器，当我准确地指定了标签的类型：body、header、main、footer。
But there's other ways that now we can lay the foundation for making reusable CSS that you and colleagues and classmates can use and reuse in multiple files and even in multiple projects.
但是，还有其他方法可以为可重用的 CSS 奠定基础，你和同事以及同学可以在多个文件甚至多个项目中使用和重用这些 CSS。
So let me actually go ahead and do this.
让我继续这样做。
Instead of just very explicitly saying, I want the body to be centered, let me invent an adjective, if you will.
与其明确地说，我希望 body 居中，不如让我们发明一个形容词。
And let me change this to .centered.
让我们把它改成.centered。
And this new vocabulary word, centered, will literally mean text-aligned center.
这个新的词汇“centered”字面意思就是文本对齐方式为居中。
Let me go ahead here.
让我们继续。
And I'm just going to create a new adjective called large, a new adjective called medium, and a new adjective called small.
我将创建一个名为“large”的新形容词，一个名为“medium”的新形容词，还有一个名为“small”的新形容词。
They are deliberately consistent with what the properties do.
它们故意与属性的功能保持一致。
But these are now my own vocabulary words.
但这些现在是我自己的词汇。
And they are called classes.
它们被称为类。
So a class is just a collection of key value pairs, a collection of properties that you get to invent for yourself.
所以类只是一组键值对，一组你可以自己发明的属性。
And what it lets you do now is this.
它能让你做到的是这样的。
Now, if I want the whole body to be centered, I can add this tag, which we actually saw briefly in Yale's HTML, class="center".
现在，如果我希望整个 body 都居中，我可以添加这个标签 class="center"，我们实际上在耶鲁大学的 HTML 中简单地看到了它。
Down here in the header, if I want this to be large, I can say class="large".
在 header 中，如果我希望它是大的，我可以写 class="large"。
Down here on main, I can say class="medium".
在 main 这里，我可以写 class="medium"。
And down here, I can have class equals quote, unquote, small.
在这里，我可以写 class =  "small"。
Now, I have taken one step backward by re-adding some of the aesthetics to the page, but it's not the actual properties.
现在，我通过重新添加一些美化页面的元素，后退了一步，但这不是真正的属性。
It's not the key value pairs.
这不是键值对。
It's now more semantically nice, because now I just know from reading the HTML what these things are going to look like, whereas the implementation details for all four of those adjectives is now relegated up above.
现在语义上更好了，因为现在我只要阅读 HTML 代码就能知道这些东西会是什么样子，而这四个形容词的实现细节现在都归到上面了。
And these are literally my words.
这些实际上是我的文字。
I could change it to dot foo and use class equals quote unquote foo.
我可以把它改成 .foo，并使用 class = "foo"。
But obviously, that would not be the best choice of words in this case.
但显然，在这种情况下，这不是最佳的用词选择。
All right.
好的。
Any questions on this?
对此有任何问题吗？
This now is what we would call a class selector by using literally the dot, even though the dot does not appear elsewhere.
这就是我们所说的类选择器，通过使用点号，即使点号没有出现在其他地方。
But dot means this is a class.
但点号表示这是一个类。
These are not always the best syntactic design decisions that the world makes.
这些语法设计决策并不总是世界上最好的。
All right, well, one last trick then.
最后一个技巧。
Notice that this is a little annoying that I'm still working in the same file.
请注意，我仍在同一个文件中工作，这有点烦人。
And if my classmate wants to clean up my aesthetics, make my home page look way better, if my colleague wants to do the same, wouldn't it be nice if we could actually move all of this code to a different file, like a Python library or a C header file?
如果我的同学想清理我的美学设计，让我的主页看起来更好，如果我的同事也想这样做，
如果我们可以把所有这些代码移到另一个文件中，就像 Python 库或 C 语言头文件一样，那不是很好吗？
Well, you can.
是的，可以。
Let me go ahead and delete that whole style tag.
让我继续删除整个 style 标签。
Let me add a confusingly named link tag, the href of which, let's call a new file styles.css.
让我添加一个名称令人困惑的 link 标签，它的 href，我们称之为新文件 styles.css。
And let's say that the relationship of that file is that of stylesheet.
并且我们说，该文件的关系是样式表。
So this is a term of art in the world of web development.
这是 Web 开发领域中的一个专业术语。
A stylesheet is a text file that contains lots of styles, lots of CSS properties.
样式表是一个包含大量样式、大量 CSS 属性的文本文件。
Let me open my terminal real fast.
让我快速打开终端。
And let me do code of styles.css.
然后执行 `code styles.css`。
Enter.
回车。
And in this file, I'm going to paste all of those same lines as earlier.
在这个文件中，我要粘贴之前的所有相同行。
But now they're in a separate file.
但现在它们在一个单独的文件中。
And indeed, if I hide my terminal window and I give this file to a colleague, they can now work on the aesthetics of the page and make things a lot prettier than this, maybe use specific font sizes, maybe add colors and the like, whereas I can focus entirely on the HTML, because this file now will reference that other.
实际上，如果我隐藏终端窗口并将此文件交给同事，他们现在可以处理页面的美观性，
并使内容比这漂亮得多，也许使用特定的字体大小，也许添加颜色等，而我可以完全专注于 HTML，因为此文件现在将引用另一个文件。
And if I go back to my other tab and reload, the content's going to be exactly the same, but now I'm using some separate file instead.
如果我回到另一个选项卡并重新加载，内容将完全相同，但现在我使用的是另一个单独的文件。
Any questions now about these techniques here?
对这些技术还有什么问题吗？
All right, so with that said, let me show just one example now of what I called a moment ago frameworks.
话虽如此，让我现在展示一个我刚才所说的框架示例。
And this is where web development gets kind of fun, at least if you like this, especially if you like the sort of logical design, the presentation of information you care about, but you really don't want to struggle with font sizes and colors and getting everything pixel perfect, so to speak.
这就是 Web 开发变得有趣的地方，至少如果你喜欢这种逻辑设计、信息呈现的方式，
但你真的不想纠结于字体大小、颜色以及让所有东西都像素完美，可以这么说。
Let me propose that I open up here an example in just a moment in VS Code that I prepared in advance, and this one is going to be
让我建议我在 VS Code 中打开一个我提前准备好的示例，这个示例将是
an opportunity to consider how you might take some of the data from last week, wherein we collected everyone's favorites, and lay it out in a really big HTML table.
一个思考如何把你上周收集到的关于大家最喜欢的食物的数据，放到一个很大的 HTML 表格中的机会。
So I wrote this out in advance because it was a huge amount of data.
我提前写好了这些，因为数据量很大。
But it's the same data from the Google form from last week.
但它与上周 Google 表单中的数据相同。
And you'll see already the hints of a table tag and these TRs.
你会看到表格标签和这些 TR 的迹象。
And I added a few other tags for aesthetics.
我添加了一些其他的标签来美化。
It turns out when you have a more visually interesting header for your table,
事实证明，当你的表格有一个更有趣的视觉标题时，
There's another tag called t-head.
还有一个叫做 t-head 的标签。
There's another tag called t-body.
还有一个标签叫做 t-body。
These are not all that intellectually interesting.
这些标签本身并不有趣。
I just read the documentation and realized, oh, to make things prettier, I need a t-head, a t-body, and so forth.
我只是读了文档，发现要让页面更漂亮，需要用到 t-head、t-body 等等标签。
But what's interesting here is that if I go to my index here and open this file called favorites.html, here is all of the data from last week's Google spreadsheet, which we exported as CSV and I manually, before class, converted to just HTML.
有趣的是，如果我打开 index 文件夹下的 favorites.html 文件，
就会看到上周 Google 表格中的所有数据，我们将其导出为 CSV 格式，并在课前手动转换为 HTML 格式。
It's indeed a table.
这确实是一个表格。
But it's really not pretty.
但它真的不好看。
The columns are really close together.
列与列之间挨得太近。
It's kind of hard to distinguish one row from another.
很难区分行与行。
But this is just raw HTML written by me.
但这只是我写的原始 HTML 代码。
Now, I could use CSS and some of the tricks we just saw to maybe change font size.
现在，我可以使用 CSS 和一些我们刚才看到的技巧来改变字体大小。
There's ways to change color, background color, and a lot of things like that.
还可以改变颜色、背景颜色等等。
But honestly, surely other people in the world have presented tabular data in pretty ways, right?
但说实话，世界上肯定有人用更漂亮的方式展示过表格数据，对吧？
I've been to many websites that have prettier tables than mine.
我去过很多网站，它们的表格都比我的漂亮。
Can I maybe use someone else's framework, someone else's CSS, include it in my page, but then stand on their shoulders and just make my stuff look prettier?
我能否借用别人的框架或 CSS 代码，将其包含在我的页面中，站在巨人的肩膀上，让我的页面看起来更漂亮呢？
Well, I dare say I can.
我敢说我可以。
Let me go ahead here and semi-secretly
让我悄悄地...
Open up VS Code again, and let me grab a slightly different version of favorites.html that I also opened in advance, wherein I add this line of code instead.
打开 VS Code，选择另一个版本的 favorites.html 文件，我在其中添加了这行代码。
Give me just a moment to foreground this version.
稍等，我把这个版本放到前面。
And the data is all the same as before, but I've added one of these link tags.
数据和之前一样，但我添加了一个 link 标签。
And I'm not linking to my own styles.css. I'm using a popular library called Bootstrap.
我没有链接到自己的 styles.css 文件，而是使用了一个流行的库，叫做 Bootstrap。
And Bootstrap is just one of many popular libraries out there, free at that, that has a whole bunch of CSS files and soon JavaScript files that you can just use for free in your own projects, personally or professionally, that just make things look and behave better without you having to reinvent wheels.
Bootstrap 只是众多流行库中的一个，而且是免费的，它包含大量的 CSS 文件和即将推出的 JavaScript 文件，
你可以在个人或商业项目中免费使用它们，这可以让你的项目外观和行为更出色，而无需你自己重复造轮子。
Now, to access their CSS, I had to read their documentation and grab this very long URL here.
为了访问它们的 CSS，我必须阅读他们的文档并获取这个很长的 URL。
But it's the same idea, link a for tref equals quote unquote something.
但思路是一样的，用 link 标签，href 属性等于引号中的一些内容。
And I read their documentation, and they told me to add this.
我阅读了他们的文档，他们告诉我要添加这个。
They told me that if I want my tables to be prettier, I have to add a class attribute to my own table tag and specify, a little weirdly, but this is what Bootstrap told me to do, a class called table.
他们告诉我，如果我想让我的表格更漂亮，
我必须在我的 table 标签中添加一个 class 属性，并指定一个类名为 table，虽然有点奇怪，但这是 Bootstrap 告诉我要做的。
And that will make it a prettier Bootstrap table.
这会使它成为一个更漂亮的 Bootstrap 表格。
And if I want to stripe it, like every other row is gray instead of white, just to make it pop a little more visually, I can also add a second class separated by a space called table striped.
如果我想让它有条纹，比如每隔一行是灰色而不是白色，只是为了让它在视觉上更突出，我还可以添加第二个类，用空格隔开，叫做 table-striped。
That's all I did.
这就是我所做的全部。
I added line 5, and I changed line 9, and that is it.
我添加了第 5 行，并修改了第 9 行，仅此而已。
The rest of the hundreds of lines in favorites.html are the same.
favorites.html 中其余的数百行代码都是一样的。
But if I go back here now and reload the browser, now, thanks to Bootstrap, voila, like it's much prettier.
但如果我现在回到这里重新加载浏览器，现在，感谢 Bootstrap，瞧，它漂亮多了。
Now I can zoom out, and that changes the font size just locally for me.
现在我可以缩小，这只会局部地改变我的字体大小。
And even if you don't love their aesthetics, I mean, this is easily better than my own there.
即使你不喜欢他们的美学，我的意思是，这很容易比我自己做的要好。
And it turns out we can do even better by adding interactivity to this, too.
事实证明，我们还可以通过添加交互性来做得更好。
But to do that, we're going to need one final language for today.
但要做到这一点，我们今天还需要学习最后一门语言。
And this one is an actual programming language.
而这是一种真正的编程语言。
And we won't use it all that much in CS50, but we introduce it here as we begin web stuff because there's just so many free libraries and professional libraries that you can use just to make your web applications fancier and more interactive.
在 CS50 中我们不会过多地使用它，但我们在这里介绍它，因为我们开始学习 Web 相关内容，
并且有太多免费的库和专业的库可以使用，可以让你的 Web 应用程序更漂亮、更具交互性。
Mobile applications, as well, increasingly use HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to power our iPhones and Android devices, as well.
移动应用程序也越来越多地使用 HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript 来驱动我们的 iPhone 和 Android 设备。
So a quick tour of some syntax, and then we'll conclude with just some hopefully inspiring examples to give you a taste of what JavaScript can do.
快速浏览一些语法，然后我们将以一些鼓舞人心的例子来结束，让你体验一下 JavaScript 的功能。
So JavaScript supports conditionals, just like C and Python before it.
JavaScript 支持条件语句，就像之前的 C 和 Python 一样。
If we rewind to our scratch days, here, of course, is a conditional.
如果我们回顾 Scratch，当然，这里也有条件语句。
Here is the corresponding JavaScript code as of today.
这就是今天对应的 JavaScript 代码。
It's pretty much identical to C with the syntax here.
它的语法与 C 语言几乎完全相同。
If we had an if else, in Scratch it looked like this.
如果我们有一个 if else 语句，在 Scratch 中它看起来像这样。
In JavaScript, it's going to look like this instead.
而在 JavaScript 中，它看起来像这样。
So it's a bit of a regression vis-a-vis Python, like the parentheses are back, the curly braces are back, the semicolons I mentioned in CSS are also back in JavaScript potentially.
所以相对于 Python 来说，这有点倒退，比如括号回来了，花括号回来了，我在 CSS 中提到的分号也可能回到了 JavaScript 中。
But it's familiar is the point here.
但重点是它很熟悉。
And it's a different language that's frequently used for the web, whereas you can't use Python in the ways we're about to use JavaScript.
它是一种经常用于 Web 的不同语言，而你不能以我们即将使用 JavaScript 的方式使用 Python。
It just wasn't designed for that purpose.
它不是为这个目的设计的。
Meanwhile, if you have an else if else in Scratch, well, in JavaScript, just like in C, it's going to look like this instead.
同时，如果你在 Scratch 中有一个 else if else 语句，那么在 JavaScript 中，就像在 C 语言中一样，它看起来会是这样。
Variables in JavaScript, of course, are a thing, too.
当然，JavaScript 中也有变量。
And in Scratch, we might have initialized a counter variable to 0.
在 Scratch 中，我们可能已经将一个计数器变量初始化为 0。
In JavaScript, a few different ways to do this.
在 JavaScript 中，有几种不同的方法可以做到这一点。
And just for now, the keyword is let.
现在，关键字是 let。
It's sort of a polite way of asking for a variable, let. Counter equals zero semicolon.
这是一种请求变量的礼貌方式，let。counter 等于 0 分号。
So you don't mention the type, but you do use a keyword here in this case called let.
所以你没有提到类型，但是你在这种情况下确实使用了一个叫做 let 的关键字。
If you want to increment counter by one, a few different ways.
如果你想把 counter 加 1，有几种不同的方法。
In JavaScript, you can do this, just like in C. In JavaScript, you can do this, just like in C and in Python.
在 JavaScript 中，你可以这样做，就像在 C 语言中一样。在 JavaScript 中，你可以这样做，就像在 C 语言和 Python 中一样。
In JavaScript, you can also get this.
在 JavaScript 中，你也可以这样做。
So plus plus is back.
所以 ++ 又回来了。
So maybe that counterbalances the other syntax as well.
那也许这也弥补了其他语法。
That was not the case in Python.
这在 Python 中是不存在的。
Loops are back, of course, in JavaScript.
当然，循环在 JavaScript 中也回来了。
Whereas in Scratch, you could repeat three times like this.
而在 Scratch 中，你可以像这样重复三次。
In JavaScript, it's pretty much just like C. The only difference here is that you say let instead of int for an example like this.
在 JavaScript 中，它和 C 非常相似。唯一的区别是，像这样的例子中，你使用 let 而不是 int。
Meanwhile, if you want to do something forever in Scratch, in JavaScript, just like in C, you say while true in this case.
同时，如果你想在 Scratch 中永远做某事，在 JavaScript 中，就像在 C 中一样，在这种情况下，你会使用 while true。
So this is to say, we're sort of comfortable spending relatively little time on JavaScript, at least for today's purposes, because syntactically,
也就是说，我们相对来说可以花很少的时间在 JavaScript 上，至少就今天的目的而言，因为从语法上讲，
It's really the same as we've seen before, with maybe a slight variance here or there.
它和我们之前看到的真的没什么区别，可能只是这里或那里略有不同。
But what's interesting today, arguably, is just what kinds of things you can do with it.
但可以说，今天有趣的是你可以用它做什么样的事情。
So with that said, what kinds of things can we do?
那么，话虽如此，我们可以用它做什么呢？
It all comes back to this picture.
这一切都可以追溯到这张图。
If this is a simple web page on the left.
如果左边是一个简单的网页。
And this is the corresponding tree, or DOM, document object model on the right.
右边是对应的树，或者说是 DOM，文档对象模型。
That is the tree the browser automatically creates in memory, or RAM, for you.
这是浏览器自动在内存或 RAM 中为你创建的树。
JavaScript is now a proper programming language that lets us dynamically manipulate, like read data from this, change this.
JavaScript 现在是一种合适的编程语言，它让我们可以动态地操作，比如从这里读取数据，修改它。
And this is how Google, for instance, implements your inbox.
例如，谷歌就是这样实现你的收件箱的。
In your inbox, it's like a table, so tr, tr, tr, tr probably, something like that, or heck, maybe div, div, div, div.
在你的收件箱里，它就像一张表，所以可能是 tr、tr、tr、tr，或者也可能是 div、div、div、div。
Using JavaScript, any time they realize someone sent you new mail, they can create a new node, a new rectangle in memory, and you, the human, see a new div or a new tr again and again and again.
使用 JavaScript，每当他们意识到有人给你发了新邮件时，
他们就会创建一个新的节点，一个新的内存中的矩形，而你，作为用户，会看到一个新的 div 或者一个新的 tr，一次又一次。
So with JavaScript, you just have the ability to control the user's experience instead of, like I've been doing, constantly hitting reload in the page to see some new content.
所以使用 JavaScript，你就可以控制用户的体验，而不是像我一直做的那样，不断地刷新页面才能看到新的内容。
To see some new content, JavaScript can be running 24-7 so that you can actually see all of these changes live.
为了看到新的内容，JavaScript 可以 24 小时不间断地运行，这样你就可以实时地看到所有这些变化。
All right, let's go about writing some JavaScript code now.
我们来写一些 JavaScript 代码。
Instead of writing it on the server and executing it on the server, we're going to actually use a very common paradigm, whereas JavaScript is actually executed in the browser client side.
我们不用在服务器上编写和执行代码，而是采用一种非常常见的模式，即在浏览器客户端执行 JavaScript。
That is to say, we can actually start writing some JavaScript code inside of our own .html file so that when a user visits that web page with their browser, not only is the HTML and any CSS downloaded to the user's browser, so is that JavaScript code so that it's executed, indeed,
也就是说，我们可以在自己的 .html 文件中编写一些 JavaScript 代码，
这样当用户使用浏览器访问网页时，不仅 HTML 和 CSS 会下载到用户的浏览器，JavaScript 代码也会被下载并执行。
Client-side on the browser rather than server-side, as has been the case with Python in previous weeks.
它是在浏览器端（客户端）执行，而不是像前几周的 Python 那样在服务器端执行。
Well, where do we go about writing some JavaScript code?
那么，我们在哪里编写 JavaScript 代码呢？
Let's go ahead and revisit hello.html, which previously was a completely static example that literally just said, hello, title, hello, body.
我们再来看看 hello.html，它之前是一个完全静态的例子，字面上只是写着 "hello, title" 和 "hello, body"。
Indeed, if I open this up using HTTP server and view it now in a separate tab, all it said was exactly that, hello, title in the tab, and hello, body in the main part of the viewport, so to speak.
实际上，如果我使用 http server 打开它，并在另一个标签页中查看，
它显示的内容就是 "hello"，标签页标题是 "title"，视口的主要部分是 "hello, body"。
Well, let's make this example a little more dynamic so it doesn't just say, hello, body, but maybe says hello to an actual person.
我们来让这个例子更动态一些，不要只是显示 "hello, body"，而是向一个真实的人问候。
So let's go ahead and do this.
我们来实现它。
Let's go ahead and remove the hard-coded hello, body.
我们把写死的 "hello, body" 删除。
And let's actually go ahead here and use a form tag.
我们在这里使用一个 `<form>` 标签。
But we're not going to use this form in the usual way, whereby the data gets sent all the way back to the server.
但我们不会以通常的方式使用这个表单，数据不会被发送回服务器。
We're going to leverage control over this form client-side instead.
我们将改为在客户端控制这个表单。
So I'm going to go ahead and create this open form tag, close form tag.
我先创建 `<form>` 的开始标签和结束标签。
Inside of that, let me give myself a text input that's going to have autocomplete equals, quote unquote, off, just to ensure that what I previously typed in my examples doesn't reappear accidentally.
在标签内部，我创建一个文本输入框，并将 `autocomplete` 属性设置为 `"off"`，以确保我之前在例子中输入的内容不会意外地重新出现。
We're going to autofocus it so that the cursor is blinking right there in that text box.
我们将 `autofocus` 设置为 `true`，这样光标就会在这个文本框中闪烁。
And this time, I'm going to go ahead and give it, how about a placeholder of quote, unquote, name, to make clear that I'm prompting the user for their name.
这次，我将给它一个占位符，内容是 `"name"`，以便清楚地提示用户输入他们的名字。
And then the type of this text box will be the default, or more explicitly here, text.
这个文本框的 `type` 属性将使用默认值，或者更明确地说，是 `"text"`。
And then I'm going to have, as we've seen before, a button, the type of which is submit, also our typical default.
像我们之前看到的那样，我将添加一个按钮，它的 `type` 属性是 `"submit"`，这也是默认值。
And then inside of this button is going to be the label.
在这个按钮里面是标签。
How about something like, how about we'll call this greet.
不如这样，我们把这个按钮命名为 greet。
So that's what the button will actually say.
这就是按钮上实际显示的内容。
Well, let me actually go back into my browser tab.
让我回到浏览器选项卡。
Let me reload this page.
刷新一下页面。
And we should now see a relatively simple form, whereby I have the cursor blinking on a text input, prompting the user for their name, and then a greet button that I can click.
现在应该能看到一个相对简单的表单，光标在文本输入框中闪烁，提示用户输入姓名，还有一个可以点击的 greet 按钮。
But if I click this button now, it's not going to do anything useful, because I haven't written any code to tell the browser what to do when I click that button.
但如果现在点击这个按钮，它不会有任何作用，因为还没有编写任何代码来告诉浏览器点击按钮后该做什么。
But it turns out there's all sorts of events in the world of JavaScript that you can listen for, so to speak.
事实证明，在 JavaScript 的世界里，你可以监听各种各样的事件。
In fact, here's just a list of some of them.
实际上，这里列出了一些事件。
Anytime something changes in a form field, anytime the user clicks or drags on something, anytime the user presses a key and maybe lifts their finger up, anytime the mouse goes down or over or up on top of something, or anytime a form is submitted, those are events.
表单字段发生变化、用户点击或拖动、用户按下或抬起按键、鼠标在某个元素上按下、悬停或抬起，以及表单提交，这些都是事件。
In the same way that we talked about events back in week 0 in Scratch,
就像我们在第 0 周讨论 Scratch 中的事件一样。
And in JavaScript, just like in Scratch, where you can do something when green flag clicked, in JavaScript, you can write code that actually listens for any of these events or more.
在 JavaScript 中，就像在 Scratch 中点击绿旗时可以执行操作一样，你可以编写代码来监听这些事件或更多事件。
So with that said, let's go back to VS Code here, and let's make a couple of changes instead.
接下来，回到 VS Code，做一些修改。
Let's go ahead and add to this form a new attribute.
给这个表单添加一个新属性。
That's not the best way to do it, but it's perhaps the simplest for version 1 here.
这不是最好的方法，但对第一个版本来说可能是最简单的。
And let's say onSubmit do the following.
添加 onsubmit 属性，并在提交时执行以下操作。
So onSubmit is an HTML attribute.
onsubmit 是一个 HTML 属性。
And curiously, its value inside of the quotes there can actually be some JavaScript code.
有趣的是，它在引号内的值实际上可以是一些 JavaScript 代码。
And let's go ahead now, and let's assume there exists a function in the world called greet.
假设存在一个名为 greet 的函数。
And what I want to do is call that function right then and there.
现在就想调用这个函数。
Well, now in JavaScript, how do I go about making that function exist?
那么在 JavaScript 中，如何创建这个函数呢？
It doesn't come out of the box just like print might or say might in Python or Scratch, respectively.
它不像 Python 或 Scratch 中的 print 或 say 那样开箱即用。
But I can do this.
但我可以这样做。
Let me go up into the head of this page.
让我进入这个页面的头部。
Inside of a script tag here, both open and close, let me actually write some JavaScript code.
在这个 script 标签内部，包括开始和结束标签，让我来写一些 JavaScript 代码。
And just so it stands out, I'm going to give myself a couple of blank lines, though not strictly necessary.
为了让它更醒目，我要给自己加几行空行，虽然这不是严格必要的。
And let me define a new function in JavaScript called greet.
然后我将在 JavaScript 中定义一个名为 greet 的新函数。
And this is the syntax in JavaScript for creating your own function.
这就是 JavaScript 中创建自定义函数的语法。
Similar in Python, instead of saying def in JavaScript, you just say function, then the name of the function and any arguments within the parentheses thereafter.
与 Python 类似，在 JavaScript 中不需要使用 def，只需使用 function，然后是函数的名称，以及后面括号中的任何参数。
But I'm not going to pass in any here.
但我这里不打算传入任何参数。
Then inside of curly braces, what I'm going to do is use a built-in JavaScript function that comes with any browser called alert.
然后在大括号内，我要做的是使用一个名为 alert 的内置 JavaScript 函数，它包含在所有浏览器中。
It's not the best or prettiest user interface.
它不是最好或最漂亮的界面。
But for now, it's going to get the job done.
但就目前而言，它可以完成这项工作。
What do I want to say to the user?
我想对用户说什么？
Well, let's first just say something simple like, hello, comma, world, close quote, semicolon, thereby alerting the user with precisely that message.
首先，让我们只说一些简单的话，比如 hello，逗号，world，引号，分号，从而用这条消息提醒用户。
Now, what I'm going to do down here is make one other change.
现在，我要在这里做另一个改变。
I don't want this form to actually get submitted to the server, just like we've seen in the past.
我不希望这个表单像我们过去看到的那样真正提交到服务器。
When you submit a form, it often goes to something like google.com slash search.
当你提交表单时，它通常会发送到 google.com/search 之类的地方。
I actually want my JavaScript code to take control over the entire thing.
实际上，我希望我的 JavaScript 代码能够完全控制整个过程。
The entire user experience of this form so that I'm just using the form as a user input mechanism, not to actually send via GET or POST this data to some other server, including my own.
我希望完全控制这个表单的用户体验，这样我就只是把表单当作一个用户输入机制，
而不是通过 GET 或 POST 把这些数据发送到其他服务器，包括我自己的服务器。
So this is going to look a little ugly.
所以这看起来会有点丑陋。
But after calling greet, I'm actually going to do this, which I've read the documentation about.
调用 greet 函数之后，我要做的是这个，我已经阅读过相关文档了。
And I know that if you actually hard code return false here, that just tells the browser, please don't actually submit the form.
我知道如果在这里硬编码 `return false`，就会告诉浏览器不要实际提交表单。
Only call the greet function.
只调用 greet 函数。
All right, well, let me go back to my browser here.
让我回到浏览器这边。
Let me reload this, because I need to download the latest version of the JavaScript code.
我要重新加载一下页面，因为我需要下载最新版本的 JavaScript 代码。
And I'm just going to go ahead, without even typing my name, I'm going to click on the Greet button.
我要直接点击“Greet”按钮，甚至不用输入我的名字。
And you'll see that, albeit a little cryptically at the top, we see an alert that says, hello world.
你会看到，虽然在顶部有点隐蔽，但我们确实看到了一个显示“hello, world”的弹窗。
There's my ugly URL of my code space there at the moment, but we do indeed see that string.
虽然显示了我的代码空间的丑陋 URL，但我们确实看到了那串字符。
But what I haven't, of course, done is taken any actual name from the user.
但我还没有做的是从用户那里获取任何实际的名字。
So how can we go about doing that?
那么我们该如何做到这一点呢？
Well, ideally, I want to alert.
理想情况下，我想要弹窗显示：
The user with hello, David, or hello, Carter, whatever name I type into that box.
“hello，David”，或者“hello，Carter”，以及任何我输入到那个框的名字。
So how can I go about doing that?
那么我该怎么做呢？
Well, let me create a variable called name.
让我创建一个名为 name 的变量。
And let me set it equal to this function call, document.querySelector.
并将它设置为这个函数调用的结果：`document.querySelector`。
That comes with JavaScript itself.
这是 JavaScript 自带的函数。
Let me then, in parentheses, pass in an argument that is going to be, huh, the ID.
我在括号中传入一个参数，这个参数将是，id。
I need a unique identifier for the thing I want to select.
我需要一个唯一标识符来选择我想要的东西。
So let me actually go back to my HTML code here.
让我回到 HTML 代码这边。
And instead of giving this form field a name, like Q for query, let me actually use another HTML attribute called ID, where now I can call this anything I want.
与其给这个表单字段一个像 Q 这样的名字，不如让我使用另一个叫做 id 的 HTML 属性，现在我可以把它叫做任何我想要的。
And for clarity, I'm just going to call this input element uniquely name. Now, up here in Query.
为了更清晰，我将这个输入元素命名为 `name`。现在，在 `Query` 中，
query selector, just like in CSS, where you can use hashes and dots and other symbology in order to select certain nodes in your DOM, that is, rectangles in that memory tree.
`query selector` 就像在 CSS 中一样，可以使用井号、点和其他符号来选择 DOM 中的特定节点，也就是内存树中的矩形。
Well, I can go ahead and select hash name, which, again, is just the syntax for uniquely selecting the element whose ID is, in this case,
我可以选择 `#name`，这是一种语法，用于唯一选择 id 为 `name` 的元素，在本例中，
So you have the hash up here.
这里有一个井号。
You don't need the hash as the value of the attribute down here on line 20.
在第 20 行的属性值中不需要井号。
And now if I want to actually get the value of that text box, I literally just say dot value.
如果要获取该文本框的值，只需使用 `.value`。
So document refers to the whole web page itself.
`document` 指的是整个网页本身。
Query selector is a function that's built into that object, so to speak.
`query selector` 是内置于该对象中的函数。
And the value, accessible via dot value just like a C struct or even a Python class, allows me to go inside of that text field and get whatever the value the user has typed in.
`.value` 可以像 C 语言结构体或 Python 类一样访问，它允许我进入文本字段并获取用户输入的任何值。
Now, as I've been able to do in languages like Python fairly readily, I can concatenate this name onto the string hello comma space so as to form a complete phrase.
就像在 Python 等语言中可以轻松做到的一样，我可以将此名称连接到字符串 `hello` 后面，以形成完整的短语。
And you'll notice here that I'm actually using single quotes in my JavaScript, double quotes in my HTML.
你会注意到，我在 JavaScript 中使用单引号，在 HTML 中使用双引号。
This is perhaps a common convention.
这可能是一种常见的约定。
In JavaScript, the language does not care if you use double quotes or single quotes.
在 JavaScript 中，语言并不关心使用双引号还是单引号。
But I dare say single quotes are just more common. And so that's what I've done here.
但我敢说单引号更常见。所以这就是我在这里所做的。
All right, now, as always, I'm going to cross my fingers, go back to this page.
和往常一样，我要祈祷一下，回到这个页面。
I'm going to reload, because I've changed the JavaScript, and I need my browser to download it.
我要重新加载，因为我更改了 JavaScript，并且需要浏览器下载它。
And now I'm going to type in my name, for instance, D-A-V-I-D, click Greets with fingers crossed, and voila, now I see hello, David.
现在我要输入我的名字，比如 D-A-V-I-D，点击 `Greets`，祈祷一切顺利，瞧，现在我看到了 `hello, David`。
All right, so it turns out that while functional, this isn't the best design.
事实证明，虽然功能正常，但这并不是最佳设计。
And commingling your HTML with your JavaScript code, as with this onSubmit attribute, isn't particularly clean.
将 HTML 与 JavaScript 代码混合在一起，就像使用 `onsubmit` 属性一样，并不是特别简洁。
It's better, as with CSS, to keep your HTML over here, your CSS over here, and your JavaScript now over here, so to speak.
就像 CSS 一样，最好将 HTML 放在这里，CSS 放在这里，而 JavaScript 放在这里。
And better still, perhaps even in some separate files.
最好是放在单独的文件里。
So how can I go about changing this a little bit?
那么我要怎么修改呢？
Well, let me go ahead and actually.
让我来实际操作一下。
Let's go ahead and delete all of this code for just a moment.
让我们先把这段代码全部删除。
And let me go and get rid of this onSubmit handler down here and really just distill my HTML only into the HTML and the attributes therefore.
删除 onsubmit 处理程序，只保留 HTML 代码和属性。
And what I'm instead going to do now is do this.
我要做的是这个。
I can use JavaScript to achieve the listening for that submit event or that onSubmit event.
我可以用 JavaScript 来监听 submit 事件。
I don't need to actually use HTML for that.
不需要用 HTML 来实现。
I can use JavaScript entirely.
完全可以用 JavaScript。
So it turns out I can access some other member of this document by doing document.querySelector again.
事实证明，我可以通过 document.querySelector 访问文档中的其他成员。
But this time, let's select the actual form tag. And it doesn't have an ID, because it has no ID in its HTML. But it does have a tag name. So just like in CSS, when you can target Elements by way of their name.
这次选择 form 标签，它没有 id，但在 HTML 中有标签名。就像在 CSS 中一样，可以通过元素名称来定位元素。
I'm just going to select the one and only form on this page by using that same query selector function. And now I'm going to use another function that just comes with JavaScript in the context of browsers, whereby once you select an element like that form, I can call addEventElement.
使用相同的 querySelector 函数选择页面上唯一的 form。
然后使用浏览器 JavaScript 中自带的另一个函数，选择元素后，可以调用 addEventListener。
Listener, which is similar in spirit to Scratch's when green flag clicked or any block like that.
它类似于 Scratch 中的“当绿旗被点击”或类似的积木块。
You can then tell the browser what event you want to listen for.
可以告诉浏览器要监听的事件。
I want to listen for the submit event.
我要监听 submit 事件。
So you don't say on submit here.
这里不用说 onsubmit。
Now that we're in pure JavaScript, you just say submit.
在纯 JavaScript 中，只用说 submit。
And now I can do something like this.
然后可以这样做。
I can go ahead and say, call the following function.
调用以下函数。
And I'm not even going to bother giving this function a name.
我甚至不打算给这个函数命名。
And that is allowed to in JavaScript, as we saw briefly in Python.
在 JavaScript 中这是允许的，就像我们之前在 Python 中简单看到的。
And what I'm going to do now inside of curly braces after that keyword function is the same kind of code as before.
我接下来要在这个关键字 function 后面的大括号里做的事情，和之前的代码是一样的。
I'm going to do let name equals document.querySelector.
我要写 `let name = document.querySelector`。
I'm going to select that same name ID as before and get its value.
我要像之前一样选择那个 `name` id，并获取它的值。
And then I'm going to do alert and then pass in hello, a single quote.
然后我要写 `alert` 并传入 `hello`，一个单引号。
Again, after that, concatenate with that the name, and then Semicolon.
同样，在那之后，用 `name` 和分号将它们连接起来。
But I need to do one other thing.
但我还需要做一件事。
It turns out that this function, and if you read the documentation for this technique, actually takes automatically a special argument called by convention event.
事实证明，如果你阅读了这个技术的文档，你会发现这个函数实际上会自动接收一个特殊的参数，按照惯例它被称为 `event`。
And this is just a variable, if you will, that refers to whatever event just happened.
这只是一个变量，如果你愿意这么称呼它的话，它指的是刚刚发生的任何事件。
In this case, it's, of course, going to be submit.
在本例中，它当然会是 `submit`。
But in other contexts, it might be a click event, a mouse down event, or something else entirely.
但在其他情况下，它可能是一个点击事件、一个鼠标按下事件，或者完全是其他的东西。
So this allows me now to do this, which is a little cryptic, but you get used to these conventions.
所以这允许我现在这样做，虽然有点 cryptic，但你会习惯这些约定的。
I can use that event, whatever it is,
我可以使用这个 `event`，不管它是什么，
And then prevent whatever the default behavior is by calling a special function called preventDefault with a capital D. This is the alternative to that messier return false semicolon that I had inside of my HTML before.
然后通过调用一个名为 `preventDefault`（注意是大写 D）的特殊函数来阻止默认行为。
这是我之前在 HTML 中写的比较混乱的 `return false;` 的替代方案。
So all I've done here now is I've left all of my HTML as pure HTML down here, and I've put all of my JavaScript code as
所以我现在所做的就是把我所有的 HTML 代码都保留在下面作为纯 HTML，并把我所有的 JavaScript 代码都放在了
Pure JavaScript up here, this sort of separation of concerns similar to what we started doing with CSS just a bit ago in order to keep those two languages separate too.
上面作为纯 JavaScript，这种关注点分离的方式类似于我们刚才为了保持 CSS 的独立性而做的事情。
Well, let me go back to my browser here, reload the page.
让我回到浏览器这里，刷新页面。
And unfortunately, there's a subtle mistake I've made here.
不幸的是，我在这里犯了一个小错误。
Let me go ahead and type in D-A-V-I-D and click Greet.
让我继续输入 D-A-V-I-D 并点击 Greet。
And unfortunately, nothing actually seems to happen.
不幸的是，似乎什么都没有发生。
Well, maybe it's just my name, Carter, greet, and nothing seems to happen.
可能只是我的名字，Carter，greet，然后似乎什么也没发生。
That alert does not come up.
那个警告没有出现。
Well, why is that?
这是为什么呢？
Well, let me go back to VS Code here and point out that order of operations in JavaScript matters, similar in spirit to C. Because on line 7, I'm selecting the form and trying to add an event listener for submitting that form,
回到 VS Code 这里，我要指出 JavaScript 中的运算顺序很重要，
这和 C 语言的精神类似。因为在第 7 行，我选择表单并尝试为提交该表单添加一个事件监听器，
Unfortunately, the form had better exist at that moment in time, but it doesn't.
不幸的是，表单最好在那个时刻存在，但它不存在。
Because just like in C, and in some cases Python, where the compiler or the interpreter reads the code top to bottom, notice that the form doesn't actually exist and therefore get loaded into the computer's memory until line 19.
因为就像在 C 语言和某些情况下的 Python 中一样，
编译器或解释器从上到下读取代码，注意表单实际上并不存在，因此直到第 19 行才会加载到计算机内存中。
So we've got to kind of reorder these somehow.
所以我们得想办法重新排序。
Now, maybe the simplest way to do this would just be to perhaps do something like this.
现在，也许最简单的做法就是这样。
Let me scroll back up to my script tag and perhaps a little more explicitly move it into the order in which I want it to be executed.
让我向上滚动到我的 script 标签，或许可以更明确地将它移动到我希望它执行的顺序中。
So I'm going to go below my form and inside of my body, which is actually OK for JavaScript here, and just use that same code.
所以我要到表单下方、body 内部，这对于这里的 JavaScript 来说是可以的，然后使用相同的代码。
And assuming I didn't make any typos, let's go back to the browser, click Reload again to get the latest.
假设我没有输入错误，让我们回到浏览器，再次单击重新加载以获取最新版本。
Type in my name again using that purely JavaScript solution.
使用纯粹的 JavaScript 解决方案再次输入我的名字。
And the only change I made was I moved the code from up here to down here, clicking Greet Now.
我做的唯一改动是将代码从这里移到了这里，单击 Greet Now。
And wow, it's now back.
哇，它现在回来了。
We get the alert with hello, David.
我们收到了带有 hello, David 的警告。
So those kinds of things, those kinds of principles matter, at least when we're back in this world.
所以这类事情，这类原则很重要，至少当我们回到这个世界的时候。
But there's other solutions too.
但还有其他解决方案。
And just so that you've seen it, because it's a common convention in libraries as well, let me undo that change.
为了让你看到它，因为它在库中也是一种常见的约定，让我撤销更改。
And put that script tag back in the head or really anywhere else in the page where it might be.
并将该 script 标签放回 head 中，或者放在页面中任何其他可能存在的位置。
And let me propose that there's one other way to solve this problem to postpone that code on line 7 through 11 getting executed until really the whole DOM, the tree, is ready to go.
我建议还有另一种方法可以解决这个问题，那就是将第 7 行到第 11 行的代码推迟到整个 DOM 树准备好之后再执行。
And the syntax for this might be as follows. I can do document.
这种语法可能是这样的，我可以这样做 `document`。
And I can add to the document an event listener that's going to listen for something a little special.
我可以给文档添加一个事件监听器，它会监听一些特殊的东西。
And I always have to look this up myself to remember the spelling and the capitalization.
我总是需要自己查阅这个来记住拼写和大小写。
But it turns out that the browser itself, once it's done loading all of your HTML top to bottom, left to right, it will raise an event called DOMContentList.
但事实证明，浏览器本身一旦完成了所有 HTML 从上到下、从左到右的加载，它就会触发一个名为 `DOMContentLoaded` 的事件。
Loaded, capitalized exactly as such.
`Loaded`，大小写完全相同。
And if you want to call some function, and I don't even need an event argument in this case, you can open curly braces just as before and put inside of those curly braces the code that you want to execute only once the DOM's content has been loaded top to bottom.
如果你想调用某个函数，在这种情况下我甚至不需要事件参数，
你可以像之前一样打开花括号，并将你想执行的代码放在花括号内，这些代码只会在 DOM 的内容从上到下加载完成后执行。
And now let me just finish my thought with a close curly brace, close parenthesis, and semicolon.
现在让我用一个闭合的花括号、闭合的圆括号和分号来结束我的思路。
It gets a little annoying to visually line all of this up, but I think I'm still good.
在视觉上将所有这些代码对齐有点烦人，但我想我还行。
And now, even though this code is at the top of my file, or really above the form tag itself, I think we're OK.
现在，即使这段代码位于我的文件的顶部，或者实际上在 `form` 标签本身之上，我认为我们也没问题。
So let's go back to the browser here, reload the page, type in D-A-V-I-D, and click Read.
让我们回到浏览器这里，刷新页面，输入 D-A-V-I-D，然后点击“读取”。
And we still get the same correct behavior.
我们仍然得到了相同的正确行为。
And so this is just a very common paradigm to use these kinds of events to listen and listen and listen for something to happen, and then only do something once that thing has transpired.
这只是一个非常常见的模式，使用这些类型的事件来监听、监听、监听某件事的发生，然后只在该事件发生后才执行某些操作。
All right, well, let's take one more step with JavaScript code before we take a look at what's really fun about this language and what you can do with browsers in particular by just cleaning things up a little bit further.
在我们看看这种语言真正有趣的地方以及通过进一步清理代码，你可以在浏览器中做些什么之前，让我们用 JavaScript 代码再做一步。
I'm going to go back into the code here.
我要回到代码这里。
And I'm actually going to remove or cut all of this code out of the hello.html file itself.
我实际上要从 `hello.html` 文件本身中删除或剪切所有这些代码。
And I'm going to change my script tag to have nothing in between the open and close tag.
我要把我的 `script` 标签改成在开始标签和结束标签之间没有任何内容。
But I am going to give it a source attribute.
但我打算给它一个 `source` 属性。
And let's go ahead and call this, for instance, hello.js.
让我们继续，把它叫做，比如，`hello.js`。
So .js would be the convention for the file extension for a JavaScript file.
所以 `.js` 将是 JavaScript 文件的文件扩展名的惯例。
And even though this is a little weird that we have the script tag and a source attribute, then nothing in between the open and close tag, this is indeed the convention when you want to put all of your code in a separate file.
尽管这有点奇怪，我们有 `script` 标签和一个 `source` 属性，
然后在开始标签和结束标签之间没有任何内容，但这确实是当你想要把所有代码放在一个单独的文件中的惯例。
And let me go ahead and do that. Let me go ahead and open my terminal window, create a new file called hello.js.
我来演示一下。我先打开终端窗口，创建一个名为 hello.js 的新文件。
And then in that file, I'm just going to paste the very code that I just cut from the previous file.
然后在这个文件中，我将粘贴刚才从上一个文件中剪切的代码。
So no changes to the code.
代码没有任何变化。
All I'm doing is factoring it out.
我只是把它提取出来了。
And now I'm doing something just like our CSS factorization before, which confusingly used the link tag.
现在我正在做类似于之前 CSS 分解的操作，之前是使用 link 标签，可能会让人混淆。
This uses the script tag.
这里使用的是 script 标签。
This just now allows me to collaborate with someone like Carter or someone else so that they can do the JavaScript code.
这样我就可以和 Carter 或其他人协作，他们可以编写 JavaScript 代码。
I can do the HTML.
我可以编写 HTML。
Maybe a third person can do the CSS.
也许第三个人可以编写 CSS。
And indeed, maybe we can build even grander things by designing things in this way.
事实上，通过这种方式设计，我们甚至可以构建更宏大的东西。
All right, well, let me go back to my browser again, reload the page.
让我回到浏览器，重新加载页面。
I shouldn't see any visual changes.
我应该看不到任何视觉上的变化。
But if I type in my name again, David, and click Greet, this still now works.
但如果我再次输入我的名字 David，然后点击 Greet，它仍然有效。
And what my browser has just done underneath the hood is not only download the hello.html file, as always, because there's now this script tag that's referencing the source of another file, just like an image tag might reference the source of an image.
我的浏览器在后台所做的不仅仅是像往常一样下载 hello.html 文件，
因为现在有了这个 script 标签，它引用了另一个文件的源，就像 image 标签可能引用图像的源一样。
The browser is automatically helping me out by loading that into its memory as well.
浏览器会自动帮我把那个文件也加载到内存中。
And now, how about one final example?
现在，最后一个例子怎么样？
And for this one, I'm going to go ahead and not write it live, but open it up as prepared in advance, just to show you what you can do by listening for some of these other events as well, like the key up, the finger going down, the finger going up, and listening for exactly that.
对于这一个例子，我不打算现场编写，而是打开一个提前准备好的文件，
只是为了向你展示通过监听其他一些事件，比如按键按下、手指按下、手指抬起，以及监听这些事件，你可以做什么。
So as the user is typing something, you can do something interesting as well.
所以当用户输入内容时，你也可以做一些有趣的事情。
I'm going to go back into my directory listing here, and I click on this source a directory, which has all of the examples that I wrote here in advance.
我要回到我的目录列表，点击这个 source 目录，它包含了我提前写的所有例子。
And I'm going to scroll down to one called hello5.html.
我将向下滚动到一个名为 hello5.html 的文件。
And in hello5 now, we've gotten rid of the button, and we just have this text box.
在 hello5 中，我们去掉了按钮，只留下了这个文本框。
But notice now what happens if I start typing my name as D-A-V-I-L.
但现在请注意，如果我开始输入我的名字 D-A-V-I-L 会发生什么。
D, I'm not typing Enter at all.
输入 D 的时候，我根本没有按回车键。
And in fact, if I start deleting and I change my mind and start typing Carter's name, notice now that the web page, the DOM inside of the computer's memory, is now automatically updating itself.
事实上，如果我开始删除并改变主意，开始输入 Carter 的名字，你会注意到网页，也就是计算机内存中的 DOM，现在正在自动更新。
So it's not even listening, it would seem, for a submit event anymore, but maybe for a key up event instead.
所以它似乎不再监听提交事件了，而是可能监听按键弹起事件。
So let me go back to VS Code here, open my terminal window, and in my source A directory, let me open up hello5.html.
让我回到 VS Code，打开终端窗口，在我的 src8 目录中打开 hello5.html。
Inside of the script tag, you'll see some code that's similar in spirit to before, whereby I'm adding an event listener to the document, waiting for the whole DOM's content to be loaded.
在 script 标签内，你会看到一些代码在精神上与之前相似，我正在向文档添加一个事件监听器，等待整个 DOM 内容加载完毕。
But then inside of that function, I'm now doing this.
但在该函数内部，我现在正在做这个。
I'm creating a variable called input and selecting from the document the one and only input tag that we saw just a moment ago.
我正在创建一个名为 input 的变量，并从文档中选择我们刚才看到的唯一一个 input 标签。
I'm then adding on line 11 an event listener for key up, which is exactly that gesture, so that I can execute some additional code any time the human lifts their finger from the keyboard after typing a key.
然后我在第 11 行添加了一个 key up 事件监听器，这正是那个操作，这样我就可以在每次用户在键盘上敲击按键后抬起手指时执行一些额外的代码。
What do I then do?
然后我要做什么呢？
Well, I'm going to go ahead, it seems, and declare another variable called name.
看起来我要继续声明另一个名为 name 的变量。
And I'm just going to select some p tag on the page.
我要选择页面上的某个 p 标签。
And now, we didn't really see a p tag, so I think it's time to look at the HTML.
我们并没有真正看到 p 标签，所以我认为是时候看看 HTML 了。
If I scroll down to the bottom of the page where my actual HTML is, you'll see that there's just a form tag and no on-submit handler anymore as before.
如果我向下滚动到页面底部，也就是我的实际 HTML 代码所在的位置，你会看到只有一个 form 标签，不再像以前那样有 on-submit 处理程序了。
There's just an input tag and no button at all.
只有一个 input 标签，根本没有按钮。
But there is on line 29 here an open and close p tag, just so I have an empty placeholder in which to put something like, hello, David.
但是在第 29 行这里有一个开放和关闭的 p 标签，这样我就有了一个空的占位符，可以在其中放置类似“hello，David”的内容。
Or hello, Carter.
或者“hello，Carter”。
So that's why now on line 12, I can define a variable called name.
所以这就是为什么在第 12 行，我可以定义一个名为 name 的变量。
And I can select that p tag so that what do I want to do?
我可以选择那个 p 标签，然后我想做什么呢？
Well, if inside of the input, there's a value.
如果输入框里有值。
So this is essentially checking for null or the absence of a string.
这实际上是在检查是否为空或缺少字符串。
So if input.value does not equal nothing, that is, there is a value in that text box, well, this syntax here on line 14 is a very clever way of doing the following.
所以如果 `input.value` 不等于空，也就是说，文本框中有值，那么第 14 行的语法是一种非常聪明的做法。
Go into that name tag, that is to say the empty paragraph.
进入 `name` 标签，也就是那个空的段落。
Change the inner HTML of it, the HTML inside of it, to be literally this, hello, comma.
将其内部的 HTML，也就是 `innerHTML`，更改为“hello,”。
And then just so you've seen an additional piece of syntax, this is similar to Python's f strings.
另外，为了让你看到更多的语法，这类似于 Python 中的 f 字符串。
The syntax is a little weird in JavaScript.
JavaScript 中的语法有点奇怪。
You actually use not single quotes, not double quotes, but backticks, which on a US English keyboard are typically the top left-hand key of your keyboard or thereabouts.
实际上，它使用的不是单引号，也不是双引号，而是反引号，在美式英语键盘上，它通常位于键盘的左上角附近。
And using dollar sign curly braces, just like the curly braces alone in Python, allows us to plug in whatever the value is of that input.
使用美元符号和大括号，就像 Python 中单独使用大括号一样，可以将 `input` 的值插入其中。
However, if there's no value there, it looks like I'm just going to say, hello, whoever you are.
但是，如果没有值，看起来只会显示“hello,”。
And in fact, we can see that behavior now as I delete, delete, delete, delete, delete, delete, and nothing's there.
事实上，当我们删除、删除、删除、删除、删除、删除，直到什么都没有的时候，就可以看到这种行为。
Now that if condition is no longer true, and so we see this default value instead.
现在 `if` 条件不再成立，所以我们看到了默认值。
So this is only to say that by harnessing these various events that are constantly happening on most any web page, we can now register code, just like we did way back in Scratch, to actually listen for those events and do something with them.
这只是说，通过利用大多数网页上不断发生的各种事件，
我们现在可以注册代码，就像我们在 Scratch 中做的那样，来监听这些事件并对其进行处理。
Now, it turns out we can do some interesting things even using third-party code.
事实证明，即使使用第三方代码，我们也可以做一些有趣的事情。
And just as we used Bootstrap a bit ago to make our table prettier, allow me to propose that we also take a look at this version of favorites as well.
就像我们之前使用 Bootstrap 来美化表格一样，让我们也来看看这个版本的 `favorites`。
Let me go back into my source8 directory and open up favorites2, which I made in advance, which looks almost the same, though I've zoomed in here a bit.
让我们回到 `source8` 目录，打开我提前创建的 `favorites2`，它看起来几乎一样，不过我在这里放大了。
But you'll notice, somewhat subtly, over the leftmost
但是你会注意到，在最左边，有一些细微的变化。
So I'm going to start with a column in this table.
我先从表格中的一个列开始。
You'll see now this arrow in gray pointing up and pointing down.
你会看到现在有一个灰色的箭头指向上方和下方。
Previously, those were not there.
之前，这些箭头是不存在的。
All I had was a static HTML table with all of this data sorted in whatever order it was inputted the other day in that form.
我之前只有一个静态 HTML 表格，里面所有的数据都是按照前几天输入表单时的顺序排列的。
But now, notice what I can do if I want to sort in data.
但是现在，注意如果我想对数据进行排序，我可以做什么。
One order, I can click this arrow, or the other order, I can sort in this arrow.
我可以点击这个箭头按一种顺序排序，或者点击另一个箭头按另一种顺序排序。
So essentially doing it chronologically forward or backward.
本质上是按时间顺序向前或向后排序。
Now, how is that sorting happening?
那么，排序是如何进行的呢？
It's presumably based on all of the timestamps that were registered when we submitted that Google Form just a bit ago.
它大概是根据我们刚才提交 Google 表单时记录的所有时间戳进行排序的。
when it was live.
当它处于活动状态时。
But now, using JavaScript, it turns out that we can use some logic somehow and sort this data by the same.
但是现在，使用 JavaScript，我们就可以使用一些逻辑，并根据相同的数据对这些数据进行排序。
And you don't get that automatically just by using HTML alone.
而且仅仅使用 HTML 是无法自动实现这一点的。
Now, how did I achieve that?
那么，我是如何实现的呢？
Well, it turns out, if I go ahead and close these hello files, and in VS Code, let's open up favorites2.html, you'll see that all of the HTML is actually the same if I scroll down and down through this file.
实际上，如果我关闭这些 hello 文件，并在 VS Code 中打开 favorites2.html，
你会发现如果我向下滚动浏览这个文件，所有的 HTML 实际上都是一样的。
But I added a little something interesting at top.
但是我在顶部添加了一些有趣的东西。
I copied and pasted the appropriate URLs and HTML tags from Bootstrap's documentation.
我从 Bootstrap 的文档中复制并粘贴了相应的 URL 和 HTML 标签。
And you'll see here that I have a file called not only bootstrap-min.css, but also bootstrap.bundle.min.js, as well as a couple of other things, as well, that allows me, ultimately, using third-party libraries to add some special APIs.
你会在这里看到，我不仅有一个名为 bootstrap-min.css 的文件，
还有一个名为 bootstrap.bundle.min.js 的文件，以及其他一些文件，这些文件最终允许我使用第三方库来添加一些特殊的 API。
HTML attributes that those libraries told me to add.
这些库告诉我要添加的 HTML 属性。
And then as soon as those libraries detect the presence of these attributes now on my own raw data, they do their thing and JavaScriptify, not a technical term, the entire table and now make it interactive and not static.
一旦这些库检测到我的原始数据中存在这些属性，它们就会执行它们的操作，
并将整个表格 JavaScript 化（这不是一个技术术语），使其变成交互式的，而不是静态的。
So you'll see here that the aesthetics of the table are as before, table and table striped.
所以你会看到这里的表格美观程度和之前一样，使用了 table 和 table-striped。
But I'm adding now another HTML attribute called data toggle, whose value is table.
但是我现在添加了另一个名为 data-toggle 的 HTML 属性，它的值是 table。
And I know that only from the documentation of these libraries indicating that that's how I can now enable this table to be interactive, as I can too by adding data sortable equals quote unquote true on specifically the timestamp column.
我知道这一点只是从这些库的文档中了解到的，文档中指出，
这就是我现在如何使这个表格能够交互，我也可以通过在时间戳列上添加 data-sortable 等于“true”来实现这一点。
And the only thing unfamiliar here perhaps is I'm using th for table heading as opposed to td as I do elsewhere.
也许这里唯一不熟悉的是，我使用 th 表示表头，而不是像其他地方那样使用 td。
But that's all that it takes to now focus on the raw data you want to present and let someone else do the heavy lifting of actually implementing the logic.
但这足以让你专注于要展现的原始数据，而让其他人完成实际实现逻辑的繁重工作。
Well, let's end with just a look at what more you can do with JavaScript and just how powerful it is when you combine a language like this with the data and the user interface you want to convey.
我们最后来看看用 JavaScript 还能做什么，以及当你将这种语言与数据和想要传达的用户界面结合起来时，它有多强大。
Let's go ahead and open up within source8 directory something called background.html.
我们继续打开 source8 目录下的 background.html。
Now, this interface here is quite simple.
这个界面非常简单。
It just has three buttons, R, G, and B. And the background, of course, notice by default, is just white.
它只有三个按钮：R、G 和 B。默认情况下，背景是白色的。
But when I click on the R, the background turns red.
当我点击 R 时，背景变成红色。
When I click on the G, it turns green.
当我点击 G 时，它变成绿色。
And the blue, it turns blue.
点击蓝色，它变成蓝色。
And again and again.
一次又一次。
So how is this working?
这是如何实现的？
Well, if you think back again to the available events, perhaps I'm just listening for a click.
回想一下可用的事件，也许我只是在监听点击事件。
Click on those buttons, and then doing something with maybe the CSS of the page to allow me to see those different colors.
点击这些按钮，然后对页面的 CSS 做一些操作，让我看到不同的颜色。
So in fact, let's go back to VS Code here, and let's open up background.html.
实际上，让我们回到 VS Code，打开 background.html。
And in here, you'll see some simple HTML at the top, just three buttons.
在这里，你会看到顶部有一些简单的 HTML 代码，只有三个按钮。
But I've given each a unique ID so that I can reference it in code.
但我给每个按钮都设置了唯一的 id，以便在代码中引用它们。
And then inside of a script tag here below, because I didn't bother with the DOM content loaded event here, notice that I'm doing the following.
然后在下面这个 script 标签中，因为我没有理会 DOMContentLoaded 事件，注意我做了以下操作。
I'm creating a variable called body that lets me select the body tag.
我创建了一个名为 body 的变量，它可以让我选择 body 标签。
I then have in these three lines some code that handles red.
在这三行代码中，有一些代码处理红色。
What am I doing?
我在做什么？
Well, I'm selecting from the document whatever HTML tag has a unique ID of red.
我从文档中选择 id 为 red 的 HTML 标签。
And then I'm adding an event listener for any click on that button.
然后我添加了一个事件监听器，用于监听按钮上的任何点击。
And any time someone clicks on that red button, I call this function anonymously.
每当有人点击红色按钮时，我就会匿名调用这个函数。
It doesn't even have or need a name.
它甚至没有名字，也不需要名字。
And this syntax here is powerful, because now in JavaScript, I can alter the CSS of my page by doing body, which is the tag that I selected two lines ago, accessing its style, accessing its background color property, and setting it equal to quote, unquote, red.
这种语法很强大，因为现在在 JavaScript 中，我可以通过 `body`（就是两行前选择到的标签）
来修改页面 CSS，访问它的 `style`，访问它的 `background-color` 属性，并将其设置为“red”。
And I do the same down below for green.
我在下面为绿色做了同样的事情。
I do the same down below for blue.
我在下面为蓝色做了同样的事情。
And the only thing worth noting here is that in CSS, it turns out it's the case.
唯一值得注意的是，在 CSS 中，事实证明是这样的。
that the CSS property for the background color of a page is actually background-color, in all lowercase with a hyphen in between.
页面背景颜色的 CSS 属性实际上是 `background-color`，全部小写，中间用连字符连接。
Unfortunately, in the world of JavaScript, a hyphen would be mistaken for subtraction, like background minus color, which would be wrong.
不幸的是，在 JavaScript 的世界里，连字符会被误认为是减法运算符，比如 `background` 减去 `color`，这是错误的。
So the convention in JavaScript is when you're trying to manipulate CSS, you take whatever the property name is
所以在 JavaScript 中，当你试图操作 CSS 时，你需要把属性名
Font size, background color, and you change it into so-called camel case here.
比如 `font-size`、`background-color`，改成所谓的驼峰式命名法。
You get rid of the hyphen, and you capitalize the subsequent words, like color, in this case here.
去掉连字符，后面的单词首字母大写，比如这里的 `color`。
All right, how about another?
再来看一个例子。
Well, it turns out back in the day, back in my day, there was a HTML tag that would actually allow you to do this, create blinking text on a screen.
在过去，在我那个年代，有一个 HTML 标签可以让你做到这一点，在屏幕上创建闪烁的文本。
It's rather unpleasant at this rate, certainly, but how might this work?
当然，现在看来这相当烦人，但这可能是怎么实现的呢？
Well, it turns out in JavaScript, if we take a look at the blink.html file here,
事实证明，在 JavaScript 中，如果我们看一下这里的 `blink.html` 文件，
We'll see that you can, in your HTML, do something literally as simple as hello world in the body.
我们会看到，你可以在 HTML 中简单地在 `body` 里写上“hello world”。
But then you can call this function here.
然后你可以调用这个函数。
Turns out, just like document, there's another global special variable you can use in JavaScript and browsers called window, which refers to all things related to the window itself.
事实证明，就像 `document` 一样，在 JavaScript 和浏览器中，
你还可以使用另一个全局特殊变量 `window`，它引用了与窗口本身相关的所有内容。
The window comes with a setInterval function, which lets you do exactly that.
`window` 对象带有一个 `setInterval` 函数，它可以让你做到这一点。
Set an interval in milliseconds.
以毫秒为单位设置一个时间间隔。
And after every expiration of that interval, some function will be called for you.
每次时间间隔结束后，会自动调用某个函数。
So in this case, it's saying every 50 milliseconds, but let's actually slow that down now to 500 milliseconds or 1 half a second, call a function called blink.
这里呢，每 50 毫秒调用一次，不过现在我们把它调慢到 500 毫秒，也就是半秒，调用一个叫做 blink 的函数。
Notice I do not have parentheses after the blink name because I don't want to call blink now.
注意，blink 后面没有括号，因为我现在还不想调用它。
I want to tell JavaScript to call the function called blink every 500 milliseconds.
我想告诉 JavaScript 每 500 毫秒调用一次名为 blink 的函数。
Now, we'll see in a moment what that code looks like.
稍后我们会看到代码是什么样的。
But let's go back to the page and reload. And you'll see now that it's a more pleasant blinking, if that's even the case, every half second, because I'm now firing that event.
让我们回到页面重新加载。你会发现现在的闪烁更令人舒适了，如果可以这么说的话，每半秒一次，因为我现在触发了那个事件。
That is, I'm calling that function now every 500 milliseconds instead. How am I doing that?
也就是说，我现在每 500 毫秒调用一次函数。我是怎么做到的呢？
Well, in this same script tag, I've invented my own blink function.
在这个 script 标签中，我创建了自己的 blink 函数。
This has the distinction back in the day of actually being an HTML tag and among the few tags that the world removed and got rid of so that it's no longer used because it's not all that user-friendly.
这曾经是一个 HTML 标签，并且是少数被移除和废弃的标签之一，因为它不再使用，因为它对用户不太友好。
But down here, what am I doing?
但是在这里，我做了什么？
I'm getting the body of the document. itself with this variable.
我用这个变量获取文档的主体部分。
And then I'm checking two CSS properties that we didn't talk about before.
然后我检查了两个我们之前没有讨论过的 CSS 属性。
But it turns out that you can check and set the visibility of an element in JavaScript by going into that tag, checking its style, and getting its visibility property.
事实证明，你可以通过 JavaScript 中的标签，检查其样式，并获取其 visibility 属性来检查和设置元素的可见性。
And if it happens to equal hidden, the next line of code here, 13, sets it equal to visible instead.
如果它恰好等于 hidden，那么下一行代码，也就是第 13 行，将其设置为 visible。
Else, if it's not hidden, it must already be visible.
否则，如果它不是 hidden，那么它一定已经是 visible 的。
And so line 17 flips it the other way and changes it to hidden.
所以第 17 行将其反转，将其更改为 hidden。
Here, left hand, right hand, clearly not talking.
这里，左手，右手，显然没有说话。
No idea why the opposite of visible is not invisible.
不知道为什么 visible 的反义词不是 invisible。
It's indeed visible and hidden.
它确实是可见的和隐藏的。
But this just allows you, every time this function is called, to change the property from one value to another, achieving that blinking effect.
每次调用这个函数时，它都能让你改变属性的值，从而实现闪烁的效果。
You can do even more powerful things that you and I take for granted every day.
你甚至可以做更多我们每天都认为理所当然的事情。
Let's go into source 8 and go to autocomplete.html, which I wrote in advance.
让我们进入 src 8 并打开 autocomplete.html，这是我提前写好的。
And this is a page that also loads into memory a really big dictionary that you might recall from problem set 5.
这个页面还会将一个很大的字典加载到内存中，你可能还记得在习题集 5 中见过它。
And if I go ahead and type in something like C,
如果我继续输入像 C 这样的内容，A，T，
A, T, you'll notice dynamically an unordered bulleted list appearing below the text box that shows you all of the words in that dictionary from PSET 5 that start with C, and then CA, and then T, just like the autocomplete you see every day on your phone, and Google, or websites like it.
你会注意到文本框下方动态出现了一个无序的项目符号列表，它显示了 PSET 5 中所有以 C 开头的单词，
然后是 CA，然后是 T，就像你每天在手机、Google 或类似网站上看到的自动完成功能一样。
How is that working?
这是如何工作的？
Well, probably I'm listening for the key press going up.
可能是监听按键弹起事件。
As soon as that key is pressed, I'm probably searching through a big array
一旦按下该键，我可能就会在一个很大的数组中搜索
Really, of all of those words, maybe using linear search, maybe binary search, if faster than that.
实际上，是在所有这些单词中搜索，可能使用线性搜索，也可能使用二分搜索，如果比这更快的话。
And then looking for any string in that array that starts with C or CA or CAT.
然后在数组中查找以 C 或 CA 或 CAT 开头的任何字符串。
And then I'm generating automatically the HTML, therefore.
然后我会自动生成 HTML 代码。
But perhaps most familiar nowadays is just how much your phone and your laptop know about you.
但也许现在最熟悉的是你的手机和笔记本电脑对你有多了解。
And let me go into A final example here in source 8 called geolocation.html, which is a term of art that just refers to figuring out your geography, for instance, your GPS coordinates.
让我进入 src 8 中的最后一个例子，叫做 geolocation.html，这是一个专业术语，指的是确定你的地理位置，例如你的 GPS 坐标。
Now, here we have a third and final global variable that your browser provides you with called navigator.
现在，这里有第三个也是最后一个浏览器提供的全局变量，叫做 navigator。
And in navigator, there's a special object called geolocation that comes with a function called getCurrentPosition.
在 navigator 中，有一个名为 geolocation 的特殊对象，它带有一个名为 getCurrentPosition 的函数。
So if you call navigator.geolocation.getCurrentPosition and then pass in a function of your own that doesn't need a name but does take an argument,
如果你调用 navigator.geolocation.getCurrentPosition 并传入一个你自己的函数，这个函数不需要名字，但需要一个参数，
in this case, I called it position, as soon as the browser or as soon as the phone has figured out where in the world that user is with that browser at some latitude and longitude, the browser will automatically call that function for you.
在这个例子中，我把它叫做 position，一旦浏览器或手机确定了该用户在世界上的哪个位置，浏览器就会自动调用这个函数。
And you can do anything you want with the position that comes back, the latitude and longitude respectively.
你可以对返回的位置信息，即经度和纬度，做任何你想做的事情。
So I'm going to use a function that's not often that helpful.
我要使用一个不太常用的函数。
But for our purposes today, it's just going to write to the document itself, to my big rectangular region, whatever the latitude is, then a comma, and then the longitude as well.
但在今天，它只是将纬度、逗号和经度写入文档本身，也就是我的大矩形区域中。
So if we go back with this final flourish into source 8, Open up geolocation.html.
如果我们带着最后的装饰回到 src8， 打开 geolocation.html。
You'll see that my browser first wants my permission to let this website, my own, know my location.
你会看到我的浏览器首先需要我的许可，才能让这个网站（我自己的网站）知道我的位置。
I'm going to go ahead and click Allow, crossing my fingers, because it might take a moment for the phone or the laptop to figure it out.
我得点击“允许”，同时祈祷它不会花太长时间，因为手机或笔记本电脑可能需要一些时间来确定位置。
And it looks like OK.
看起来没问题。
According to Google, I am right this moment with my Mac at latitude longitude 42.375 comma negative 71.11.
根据 Google 的说法，我现在的位置，也就是我的 Mac 的位置，是北纬 42.375 度，西经 71.11 度。
Let's go ahead and highlight and copy that.
我们把它选中并复制。
Let's go to a website like googlemaps.com, crossing our fingers.
我们打开 googlemaps.com 网站试试看。
If you've never done this, you can search for GPS coordinates, too.
如果你以前没用过，你也可以搜索 GPS 坐标。
Let's hit Enter and.
按下回车键。
Amazing.
太棒了。
We are indeed in Sanders Theater, roughly there, standing on this stage on Halloween.
我们确实在桑德斯剧院，大概就在那里，万圣节站在这个舞台上。
And that, then, is week eight.
这就是第八周的内容。
We will see you next time.
我们下次再见。
Happy Halloween.
万圣节快乐。